characterized by massiveness and rigidity and total uniformity; a monolithic society; a monolithic worldwide movement;
acting together as a single undiversified whole; a solid voting bloc;
(of investments) not distributed among a variety of securities;
capable of being or liable to be divided or separated; even numbers are divisible by two; the Americans fought a bloody war to prove that their nation is not divisible;
capable of being cleaved;
capable of being divided or dissociated; often drugs and crime are not dissociable; the siamese twins were not considered separable; a song...never conceived of as severable from the melody;
tending to produce dissociation;
can be divided usually without leaving a remainder; 15 is dividable by 3;
(of e.g. property) capable of being parted or divided; a partible estate;
impossible of undergoing division; an indivisible union of states; one nation indivisible;
not divided or divisible into parts; layers that were fused into an indiscrete mass;
cannot be divided without leaving a remainder;
not capable of being separated; inseparable pieces of rock;
furnished with or supported by documents; the first documented case of shark attack in those waters;
supported with written references or citations; a carefully referenced biography;
(of a boat or vessel) furnished with necessary official documents specifying ownership etc;
lacking necessary documents (as for e.g. permission to live or work in a country); undocumented aliens; undocumented tax deductions;
(a boat or vessel) not furnished with official documents;
tending to domineer;
expecting unquestioning obedience; the timid child of authoritarian parents; insufferably overbearing behavior toward the waiter;
offensively self-assured or given to exercising usually unwarranted power; an autocratic person; autocratic behavior; a bossy way of ordering others around; a rather aggressive and dominating character; managed the employees in an aloof magisterial way; a swaggering peremptory manner;
noisily domineering; tending to browbeat others;
given to haughty disregard of others;
unjustly domineering; incensed at the government's heavy-handed economic policies; a manager who rode roughshod over all opposition;
marked by unjust severity or arbitrary behavior; the oppressive government; oppressive laws; a tyrannical parent; tyrannous disregard of human rights;
inclined or willing to submit to orders or wishes of others or showing such inclination; submissive servants; a submissive reply; replacing troublemakers with more submissive people;
showing humiliation or submissiveness; an abject apology;
showing an excessively deferential manner;
evidencing little spirit or courage; overly submissive or compliant; compliant and anxious to suit his opinions of those of others; a fine fiery blast against meek conformity- Orville Prescott; she looked meek but had the heart of a lion; was submissive and subservient;
totally submissive;
harassed by persistent nagging;
submissive or fawning in attitude or behavior; spoke in a servile tone; the incurably servile housekeeper; servile tasks such as floor scrubbing and barn work;
attempting to win favor by flattery;
attentive in an ingratiating or servile manner; obsequious shop assistants;
abjectly submissive; characteristic of a slave or servant; slavish devotion to her job ruled her life; a slavish yes-man to the party bosses- S.H.Adams; she has become submissive and subservient;
suitable for a slave or servant;
not servile or submissive;
exercising influence or control; television plays a dominant role in molding public opinion; the dominant partner in the marriage;
most powerful or important or influential; the economically ascendant class; D-day is considered the dominating event of the war in Europe;
able to control or determine policy; a controlling interest in the firm;
responsible for making and enforcing rules and laws; governing bodies;
having superior power and influence; the predominant mood among policy-makers is optimism;
having or showing a desire to control or dominate; a possessive parent;
greatest in status or authority or power; a supreme tribunal;
(sometimes followed by to) not subject to or influenced by; overcome by a superior opponent; trust magnates who felt themselves superior to law;
lower in rank or importance;
of or relating to a person who is subordinate to another;
having partial rights and privileges or subordinate status; an associate member; an associate professor;
belonging to a lower class or rank;
lower in rank, power, or authority; an under secretary;
(of genes) producing the same phenotype whether its allele is identical or dissimilar;
(of genes) producing its characteristic phenotype only when its allele is identical;
having one barrel; most guns are single-barreled;
having two barrels mounted side by side; a double-barreled shotgun;
(of clothing) fastened by lapping one edge of the front well over the other usually with a double row of buttons; double-breasted jacket; double-breasted suit;
(of clothing) closing with a narrow overlap and fastened with a single row of buttons; a single-breasted jacket;
suitable to or characteristic of drama; a dramatic entrance in a swirling cape; a dramatic rescue at sea;
having the excitement and emotional appeal of melodrama; a melodramatic account of two perilous days at sea;
characteristic of spectacles or drama; spectacular dives from the cliff;
affectedly dramatic; overacted;
lacking dramatic force and quality; moved with quiet force and undramatic bearing;
not spectacular; an unspectacular but necessary task;
capable of being acted; suitable for the stage; an actable scene;
not actable; an unactable play;
suited to or characteristic of the stage or theater; a theatrical pose; one of the most theatrical figures in public life;
characteristic of acting or a stage performance; often affected; histrionic gestures; an attitude of melodramatic despair; a theatrical pose;
displaying brilliance and virtuosity;
having characteristics of the stage especially an artificial and mannered quality; stagy heroics;
not suited to or characteristic of the stage or theater; a well-written but untheatrical play; an untheatrical personality;
suitable for drinking;
unsuitable for drinking;
stupefied or excited by a chemical substance (especially alcohol); a noisy crowd of intoxicated sailors; helplessly inebriated;
used of riotously drunken merrymaking; a night of bacchanalian revelry; carousing bands of drunken soldiers; orgiastic festivity;
smelling of beer;
very drunk;
slightly intoxicated;
given to or marked by the consumption of alcohol; a bibulous fellow; a bibulous evening; his boozy drinking companions; thick boozy singing; a drunken binge; two drunken gentlemen holding each other up; sottish behavior;
under the influence of narcotics; knocked out by doped wine; a drugged sleep; were under the effect of the drugged sweets; in a stuperous narcotized state;
British informal for intoxicated;
slightly and pleasantly intoxicated from alcohol or a drug (especially marijuana);
under the influence of narcotics;
not affected by a chemical substance (especially alcohol);
totally sober;
characteristic of a person not taking illegal drugs or of a place where no illegal drugs are used;
practicing complete abstinence from alcoholic beverages; he's been dry for ten years; no thank you; I happen to be teetotal;
not inebriated;
not having a sharp edge or point; the knife was too dull to be of any use;
used of a knife or other blade; not sharp; a blunt instrument;
made dull or blunt;
lacking a cutting edge;
not sharpened;
having or made by a thin edge or sharp point; suitable for cutting or piercing; a sharp knife; a pencil with a sharp point;
(of a tooth) adapted for shearing flesh; the carnassial teeth of carnivores;
resembling a chisel;
resembling a dagger;
resembling a drill;
having a cutting edge or especially an edge or edges as specified; often used in combination; an edged knife; a two-edged sword;
resembling a fang;
resembling a file;
suitable for cutting or piercing; incisive teeth;
