capable of being transformed into a diagonal matrix;
relating to or exhibiting diamagnetism; slightly repelled by a magnet;
consisting of diamonds or resembling diamonds;
related to or along a diameter; the diametral plane;
inducing perspiration;
of or relating to a diastole or happening during a diastole;
containing two carboxyls per molecule;
of or like the novels of Charles Dickens (especially with regard to poor social and economic conditions);
of or characteristic of a dictator; dictatorial powers;
possessing a differential coefficient or derivative;
relating to or showing a difference; differential treatment;
relating to or performed with the fingers; digital examination;
displaying numbers rather than scale positions; digital clock; digital readout;
occurring or existing in two different forms; dimorphic crystals; dimorphous organisms;
of or relating to or worshipping Dionysus;
relating to or characteristic of diplomacy; diplomatic immunity;
of or relating to or belonging to the Diptera;
relating to or indicating directions in space; a directional microphone;
not directional; omnidirectional antenna;
relating to direction toward a (nonspatial) goal; he tried to explain the directional trends of modern science;
relating to or characteristic of fungi of the subclass Discomycetes;
of or relating to spatial distribution; distributional requirements;
of or in the manner of a dithyramb;
pertaining to or characteristic of drama; dramatic arts;
of or related to a drupe;
resembling a garbage dump;
of or relating to the dura mater;
of or relating to or characteristic of a dynasty;
pertaining to or causing degeneration in the offspring produced;
relating to or evidencing dysplasia;
of or relating to ancient Ephesus or its people or language or culture;
of or relating to the sacrament of the Eucharist; the Eucharistic cup;
pertaining to or causing improvement in the offspring produced;
focussed on Europe and the Europeans;
(ecology) of a lake or other body of water rich in nutrients and subject to eutrophication;
of or relating to the Ebionites or their religion;
without bracts;
of or relating to the science of economics; economic theory;
of or relating to an economy, the system of production and management of material wealth; economic growth; aspects of social, political, and economical life;
involving social as well as economic factors; socioeconomic status;
exhibiting ectopia;
of or relating to an article stating opinions or giving perspectives; editorial column;
relating to or characteristic of an editor; editorial duties;
of or relating to elections; electoral process;
of or relating to an electrocardiograph;
of or involving electrochemistry;
of or relating to an electroencephalograph;
of or relating to or containing an electrolyte;
of or concerned with or produced by electrolysis;
of or relating to or involving an electrically operated mechanical device;
concerned with or producing electric current;
of or relating to electronics; concerned with or using devices that operate on principles governing the behavior of electrons; electronic devices;
of or concerned with electrons; electronic energy;
of or relating to electrophoresis;
concerned with or producing or caused by static electricity; an electrostatic generator produces high-voltage static electricity;
resembling or characteristic of or appropriate to an elegy; an elegiac poem on a friend's death;
relating to or being an element; elemental sulphur;
relating to severe atmospheric conditions; a race against hail or cold rains or some other elemental catastrophe- J.K.Howard;
of or pertaining to or characteristic of elementary school or elementary education; the elementary grades; elementary teachers;
relating to or made or done by or as if by an elf; elfin bells; all the little creatures joined in the elfin dance;
of or relating to the sky or heavens; the empyrean sphere;
characterized by or arising from emulation or imitation;
of or relating to a geological eon (longer than an era);
of or pertaining to epenthesis;
on or outside the dura mater;
lying on or over the stomach;
of or relating to the anterior walls of the abdomen; epigastric artery;
growing on stone; epilithic mosses;
denoting or governed by or relating to a bishop or bishops;
of or relating to or featuring horseback riding;
of or relating to or composed of knights;
of or belonging to the family Equidae;
resembling a horse;
relating to an equinox (when the lengths of night and day are equal);
relating to the vicinity of the equator;
of or relating to ergonomics;
relating to or produced by ergot;
of or relating to ergotropism;
producing or characterized by eruptions; an eruptive disease;
relating to or characterized by erythema;
relating to erythrocytes;
of or relating to the formation of red blood cells;
of or relating to or dealing with or regarding the ultimate destiny of mankind and the world;
relating to the esophagus;
said of or relating to the Essenes;
being or relating to or containing the essence of a plant etc; essential oil;
of or pertaining to Estonia or the people or culture of Estonia;
relating to or caused by estrogen;
of or relating to or found in estuaries;
of or relating to the philosophical study of ethics; ethical codes; ethical theories;
pertaining to or constituting evidence; evidentiary technique; an evidentiary fact;
forming an outgrowth (usually an excessive outgrowth);
of or relating to the process of excretion;
relating to exegesis;
of or relating to a period of exile (especially the exile of the Jews known as the Babylonian Captivity);
relating to or dealing with existence (especially with human existence);
of or as conceived by existentialism; an existential moment of choice;
relating to or involving existentialism; existentialist movement; existentialist philosophy; the existentialist character of his ideas;
of or relating to extropy;
of or pertaining to the outside surface of an object;
