of or relating to or denoting the second period of the Mesozoic era;
of or relating to or denoting the time before the Jurassic period;
of or relating to the law or jurisprudence; juridical days;
relating to the science or philosophy of law or a system of laws;
made of lead; a leaden weight;
of or relating to jurisprudence; legal loophole;
relating to or characteristic of the profession of law; the legal profession;
relating to or near the female labium;
of or relating to the lips of the mouth; labial stops;
inducing lactation;
of stocks of companies with a market capitalization of five billion dollars or more;
resembling lather or covered with lather;
of or relating to the countries of Latin America or their people; Latin-American countries; Latin-American music;
relating to or consisting of legumes;
of or characteristic of or resembling a lion;
of or relating to the book of Leviticus in the Bible;
expressed by a word;
of or pertaining to equipment or methods used to sustain life;
of or pertaining to or characteristic of plants of the family Liliaceae;
of or resembling a slug;
of or relating to limnology;
pertaining to living persons; within living memory;
belonging to the family Lobeliaceae;
of or belonging to or characteristic of a particular locality or neighborhood; local customs; local schools; the local citizens; a local point of view; local outbreaks of flu; a local bus line;
relating to or appropriate for a locker room; locker-room humor;
of or relating to logograms or logographs;
of or relating to or being a long-distance telephone call; a long-distance call; a long-distance transmission line; a long-distance operator;
consisting of or covered with or having loops;
light-avoiding ;
of or relating to or associated with the moon; lunar surface; lunar module;
situated between the earth and the moon;
situated beyond the moon or its orbit around the earth; who can imagine a translunary visitor in Times Square?;
performing functions similar to those performed by lungs;
relating to or attributed to the moon and the sun or their mutual relations;
of or relating to or characteristic of wolves;
of or relating to the corpus luteum;
of or containing a mixture of Latin words and vernacular words jumbled together; macaronic verse;
of or relating to macroeconomics;
of or relating to the Malayo-Polynesian branch of the Austronesian languages;
of or relating to the Mandaean people or their language or culture;
having mandibles;
of or relating to Manichaeism;
of or relating to the hands; manual dexterity;
of or relating to Maoism;
relating to or derived from one's mother; maternal genes;
pertaining to or occurring in the morning; took his matutinal walk;
belonging to or inherited from one's father; spent his childhood on the paternal farm; paternal traits;
relating to or characteristic of a man who is older or higher in rank;
containing meal or made of meal;
of or relating to mecopterans;
relating to the study or practice of medicine; the medical profession; a medical student; medical school;
relating to the activities and applications of science to clinical medicine; biomedical research laboratory;
preparing for the study of medicine; premedical students;
pertaining to legal aspects of the practice of medicine (as malpractice or patient consent for operations or patient information);
of or relating to the medulla of any body part;
of or relating to the medulla oblongata;
containing or consisting of or resembling bone marrow;
relating to or resembling a medusa;
relating to the meninges;
of or relating to the menopause;
of or relating to the Merovingian dynasty or its members;
of or relating to Prakrit;
of or relating to the mythical giant Procrustes or the mode of torture practiced by him;
of or relating to Provence or its people or their culture;
of or relating to or being the time before the beginning of the Christian era;
tending to favor preconceived ideas; the presence of discriminatory or prejudicial attitudes in the white population;
prior to menopause;
before the time of Socrates;
existing or occurring after Noah's flood;
of or relating to study or research that is done after work for the doctoral degree has been completed;
of or relating to the period in Jewish history after 539 BC (after the Babylonian Captivity);
relating to or occurring during the time following a glacial period;
subsequent to menopause;
(of a modifier) placed after another word;
having a pouch;
of or relating to the study of ferns;
of or relating to meiosis;
of or containing mercury;
like or relating to a prostitute; meretricious relationships;
of or relating to a meridian;
of or relating to metrology;
hydrous silicates of or relating to or resembling mica;
of or relating to microeconomics;
of or relating to the study of the principles of warfare; military law;
of or relating to a group of civilians organized to function like or to assist a military unit;
of or relating to artistic minimalism;
of or relating to a government minister or ministry; ministerial decree;
of or relating to a minister of religion or the minister's office; ministerial duties;
relating to or suggestive of mint;
of or relating to the Mishna (the first part of the Talmud);
characterized by omissions; omissive crimes;
of or relating to or causing constriction of the pupil of the eye; a miotic drug;
relating to or connected to a religious mission;
containing one carboxyl group;
forming or derived from a single clone;
of or relating to Monophysitism;
consisting of only one type;
of or pertaining to or characteristic of plants of the family Moraceae;
of a rash that resembles that of measles;
of or relating to motivation;
