of or relating to or the product of factor analysis;
of or relating to factorials;
of or relating to the mental faculties;
of or relating to a temperature scale proposed by the inventor of the mercury thermometer; water freezes at 32 degrees Fahrenheit under normal conditions;
having fangs;
of or relating to the central government of a federation; a federal district is one set aside as the seat of the national government;
of or relating to or near the femur or thigh;
of or relating to windows;
of or relating to or having a fenestra;
capable of being fermented;
of or relating to or containing iron;
of or relating to or characteristic of feudalism;
of or relating to or characterized by fever; a febrile reaction caused by an allergen;
having no fever;
of or relating to fiber optics;
covered with fibrils more or less evenly disposed;
characterized by the presence of fibrin;
of or relating to fibrocartilage;
of or relating to the craft of pottery; the fictile art; fictile ware;
related to or involving literary fiction; clever fictional devices; a fictional treatment of the train robbery;
not fictional;
of or relating to field crops; field-crop management;
related to or having filaments (especially across a field of view as in the eyepiece of a telescope); a filar eyepiece;
having or using two filaments; a bifilar suspension of a waving part of an instrument;
having or using only one filament;
related to or infested with or transmitting parasitic worms especially filaria;
of or relating to or belonging to the family Filariidae;
of or relating to a fisheye lens;
of or relating to or resembling fish; the soup had a fishy smell;
of or pertaining to or resembling a fistula;
made of or resembling flakes; flaky soap;
of or relating to or resembling flesh;
containing flint;
of or relating to or involving floriculture;
of or relating to or suggestive of flowers; a flowery hat; flowery wine;
of or relating to or happening in a river; fluvial deposits;
ornamented with foliage or foils; foliate tracery; a foliated capital;
of or pertaining to or resembling the leaf of a plant;
shaped like a forceps; deeply forked;
concerned with or characterized by rigorous adherence to recognized forms (especially in religion or art); highly formalized plays like Waiting for Godot;
of or containing or derived from formic acid;
of or relating to or derived from ants;
of or relating to or of the nature of a formula;
characteristic of a fossil;
bearing or containing fossils; fossiliferous strata;
of or relating to vehicles having three wheels; a three-wheel bike;
(of card games) involving or requiring four players;
of or relating to vehicles with four wheels; a four-wheel drive;
of or relating to the Franks;
of or relating to a fraternity or society of usually men; a fraternal order;
having frets;
without frets;
pertaining to or worked or produced by friction; frictional electricity; frictional heat; frictional gearing;
lacking all friction; a perpetual motion machine would have to be frictionless;
of or relating to the people or culture or language of Friesland or Frisia;
of or relating to Galilee or its inhabitants;
of or relating to Galileo or his works;
relating to or characteristic of Gallicanism;
relating to or tasting or smelling of garlic; garlicky sauce;
relating to or involving the stomach; gastric ulcer;
of or relating to the stomach and the duodenum;
of or relating to or involving the stomach and esophagus;
of or relating to or involving the lungs and stomach;
bearing or reproducing by a gemma;
of or relating to a generation;
relating to or common to or descriptive of all members of a genus; the generic name;
of or relating to the science of genetics; genetic research;
pertaining to or referring to origin; genetic history reconstructs the origins of a literary work;
of or relating to or produced by or being a gene; genic combinations; genetic code;
of or relating to the chin or median part of the lower jaw;
of or relating to the chin- or liplike structure in insects and certain mollusks;
belonging to or characteristic of non-Jewish peoples;
of or relating to or determined by geometry;
of or relating to geophytes;
of or relating to geostrategy; Pakistan became a country of paramount geostrategic importance to the United States;
of or relating to the heat in the interior of the earth;
of or relating to the gums;
of or relating to the glabella;
relating to or derived from a glacier; glacial deposit;
of or relating to neuroglia;
of or relating to or near the gluteus muscles;
of or relating to or involving glycogen;
producing or full of granules;
relating to or characterized by granulomas;
resembling the fruit of a grape vine;
relating to or presented by a graph; a graphic presentation of the data;
of or relating to the graphic arts; the etchings, drypoints, lithographs, and engravings which together form his graphic work- British Book News;
of or relating to or caused by gravitation;
infested with grubs;
relating to or articulated in the throat; the glottal stop and uvular rand chin German Bachare guttural sounds;
self-sacrificing or austere;
of or relating to harmony as distinct from melody and rhythm; subtleties of harmonic change and tonality- Ralph Hill;
not harmonic; a nonharmonic note;
of or relating to the branch of acoustics that studies the composition of musical sounds; the sound of the resonating cavity cannot be the only determinant of the harmonic response;
of or relating to harmonics;
of or relating to the Jewish Hasidim or its members or their beliefs and practices;
of or relating to or characteristic of the state or island of Hawaii or to the people or culture or language;
resembling heath;
of or relating to the Hebrides;
pertaining to or near the sun; especially the first rising of a star after and last setting before its invisibility owing to its conjunction with the sun; the heliacal rising of the Dog Star; the heliacal or Sothic year is determined by the heliacal rising of Sothis (the Egyptian name for the Dog Star);
