in a straight-backed manner; the old man still walks erectly;
with erudition; in an erudite manner; he talked eruditely about Indian mythology;
in an ethical manner; from an ethical point of view; according to ethics; he behaved ethically; this is ethically unacceptable;
in an unethical manner; he behaved unethically;
in a euphemistic manner; his violent death was euphemistically referred to as a passing away;
with evasion; in an evasive manner; her husband seemed to know many of the people who were named, but he replied evasively when asked who they were;
in a level and regular way;
in an evolutionary way; from an evolutionary point of view; the mutation has been evolutionarily successful;
in a regular way without variation; try to breathe evenly;
in an uneven and irregular way;
in an irregular manner; the patient is breathing irregularly;
having a regular form; regularly shaped objects;
having an irregular form; irregularly shaped solids;
in equal amounts or shares; in a balanced or impartial way; a class evenly divided between girls and boys; they split their winnings equally; deal equally with rich and poor;
in an unequal or partial manner; profits were distributed unevenly; angry at being dealt with so unequally;
at any future time; in the future; lead a blameless life evermore;
in an exciting manner; at the time of its appearance, the movie must have seemed excitingly new, even revolutionary;
in an unexciting manner; this painting was nothing more but an unexcitingly grey canvas with a few red speckles;
in an excusable manner or to an excusable degree; he was excusably late;
in an unpardonable manner or to an unpardonable degree; he was inexcusably cruel to his wife;
to an exorbitant degree; prices are exorbitantly high in the capital;
in an expedient manner;
in an inexpedient manner;
in an expensive manner; an expensively dressed little man turned a corner and approached her;
in a cheap manner; a cheaply dressed woman approached him in the bar;
suddenly and rapidly; the population in Central America is growing explosively;
in an explosive manner; the political situation in Kashmir and Jammu is explosively unstable;
in an exponential manner; inflation is growing exponentially;
by express; please send the letter express;
with expression; in an expressive manner; she gave the order to the waiter, using her hands very expressively;
without expression; in an inexpressive manner; she looked at him inexpressively;
without prior preparation; he spoke extemporaneously;
in a wasteful manner; the United States, up to the 1920s, used fuel lavishly, mainly because it was so cheap;
in an exuberant manner; the exuberantly baroque decoration of the church;
in a faddish manner;
in a disloyal and faithless manner; he behaved treacherously; his wife played him false;
in an incorrect manner; to credit Lister with the first formulation of the basic principle of stratigraphy would be to bestow credit falsely;
in an insincerely false manner; a seduction on my part would land us with the necessity to rise, bathe and dress, chat falsely about this and that, and emerge into the rest of the evening as though nothing had happened;
in an intimately familiar manner; Sid, as he was familiarly known by his friends, was one of the most respected and devoted members of the socialist minority group;
in a manner or to an extent that is well known; in his famously anecdotal style;
in a passionately fanatic manner; he followed the teachings of his guru fanatically;
in a fanciful manner; the Christmas tree was fancifully decorated;
in a farcical manner; a farcically inept bungler;
in a fashionable manner; his voice had no trace of the drawl that you would expect to find in a fashionably dressed young man;
in an unfashionable manner; she seemed to make a point of being unfashionably dressed;
in a fastidious manner; he writes extremely musical music, of which the sound is fastidiously calculated and yet agreeably spontaneous and imaginative;
in a civil manner; he treats his former wife civilly;
in an uncivil manner; he treats his former wife uncivilly;
in a prophetically fateful manner; the nurse whispered fatefully to call the priest;
in an inaccurate manner; these statements were faultily attributed to me;
without a fault; in a faultless manner; he solved all the problems faultlessly;
in a fearsome manner; a sabre slammed fearsomely through the thicket in all directions;
in a halting and feeble manner; reform, in fact, is, rather feebly, on the win;
in a faint and feeble manner; the lighthouse, flashing feebly against the sleet-blurred , rocky backdrop of the coast of north west Norway;
with great feeling; she spoke feelingly of her early childhood;
without compassionate feelings; unfeelingly, she required her maid to work on Christmas Day;
in a felicitous manner; a not felicitously chosen word;
in an infelicitous manner; he chose his words rather infelicitously;
with passionate fervor; both those for and against are fervently convinced they speak for the great majority of the people; a fierily opinionated book;
in the fifth place; fifthly, we must adhere to the rules set by the local government;
in a figurative sense; figuratively speaking,...;
in a literal sense; literally translated; he said so literally;
by first class conveyance; with first class accommodations; we always travel first class;
from the original source; directly; I heard this story firsthand;
quite well; she doesn't feel first-rate today;
in a fitful manner; he slept fitfully;
in a fixed manner; he stared at me fixedly;
in a flabby manner; the old man's muscles were sagging flabbily;
in a flagrant manner; he is flagrantly disregarding the law;
in a fancy colorful manner; he dresses rather flamboyantly;
with flat sails; sail flat against the wind;
with flexibility; Come whenever you are free,he said flexibly;
in an inflexible manner; You will--because you must!,Madam told her inflexibly;
in a weak and flimsy manner; this car is so flimsily constructed!;
with repeated strokes and noise; something going flip-flap in the night;
in a flippant manner; he answered the reporters' questions flippantly; this cannot be airily explained to your children;
with a flopping sound; he tumbled flop into the mud;
in a fluent manner; she speaks French fluently;
in an unpleasant or menacing manner; it was forbiddingly dark in the corridor;
with full force; we are seeing this film too late to feel its original impact forcefully;
in cold blood; he cold-bloodedly planned the murder of his boss;
in a forcible manner; keep in mind the dangers of imposing our own values and prejudices too forcibly;
in a forgetful manner; she is getting old and acts forgetfully;
with forgiveness; in a forgiving manner; Never mind,she said forgivingly;
without forgiveness; in an unforgiving manner; unforgivingly, he insisted that she pay her debt to the last penny;
in a forlorn manner; a single chicken was scratching forlornly in the yard;
in a formidable manner; the constant risk that attends the exchanges of human beings formidably armed;
in a formless manner; the dress hung formlessly on her body;
used as a direction in music; to be played relatively softly;
used as a direction in music; to be played relatively loudly;
a direction in music; to be played very softly;
a direction in music; to be played very loudly;
in a wicked and shameful manner; two policemen were foully murdered;
in an unfair and insulting manner; this internationally known writer was foully condemned by the Muslim fundamentalists;
by a factor of four; the price of gasoline has increased fourfold over the past two years;
by a factor of a million; it increased a millionfold;
in the fourth place; fourthly, you must pay the rent on the first of the month;
in a fractious manner; the horse was behaving fractiously and refused to jump;
in a brotherly manner;
in a dishonest and fraudulent manner; this money was fraudulently obtained;
