with great caution; warily;
without caution or prudence; one unfortunately sees historic features carelessly lost when estates fall into unsympathetic hands;
in a proud and domineering manner; he treated his staff cavalierly;
with unflagging resolve; dance inspires him ceaselessly to strive higher and higher toward the shining pinnacle of perfection that is the goal of every artiste;
all the time; seemingly without stopping; a theological student with whom I argued interminably; her nagging went on endlessly;
every hundred years; once in a century; the birthday of this city is being celebrated centennially;
in a manner suggestive of chaos; the room was chaotically disorganized;
in a wild and confused manner; the drugged man was talking chaotically;
in a chaste and virtuous manner; she lived chastely;
in a chatty manner; when I was a girl,she said chattily, I used to ride a bicycle;
with little expenditure of money; I bought this car very cheaply;
in a brash cheeky manner; brashly, she asked for a rebate;
in a gallant manner; he gallantly offered to take her home;
in a churlish manner; the store owner treated his customers churlishly;
in a circular manner;
in a clannish manner; these four friends always act clannishly, and don't let us participate in their activities;
in conformity with the rules or laws and without fraud or cheating; they played fairly;
in an unfair manner; they dealt with him unfairly; their accusations hit below the belt;
without difficulty or distortion; she played the piano accompaniment cleanly;
in a manner that minimizes dirt and pollution; the motor burns cleanly;
in an easily perceptible manner; could be seen clearly under the microscope; She cried loud and clear;
completely; read the book clear to the end; slept clear through the night; there were open fields clear to the horizon;
with respect to climate; they were used to a climatically different environment;
by way of, or along the coast; we were travelling coastwise;
in a cajoling manner; Come here,she said coaxingly;
in a coherent manner; she could not talk coherently after the accident;
in an incoherent manner; he talked incoherently when he drank too much;
with the use of colloquial expressions; this building is colloquially referred to as The Barn;
in a self-collected or self-possessed manner; he announced the death of his father collectedly;
in a colloidal manner; particles were colloidally dispersed in the medium;
in a bellicose contentious manner; Don't trespass onto my property,the neighbor shouted combatively;
in a comforting or consoling manner; one part of a strange world should be given a comfortingly familiar form;
taking up no more space than necessary; liquid food compactly stored in a pressurized tank;
with compatibility;
without compatibility;
in a self-satisfied manner; he complacently lived out his life as a village school teacher;
without complaining; an equally gallant little wife and mother uncomplainingly keeping up the production of tasty and nourishing meals;
with complaints; she did her work, but she did so complainingly;
in an all-inclusive manner;
in a limited way;
in a manner that cannot be evaded; the ministry considers that contributions to such a fund should be met from voluntary donations rather than from rates compulsorily levied.;
with regard to computation; computationally, this is a tricky problem;
(archaic as adverb) in a brotherly manner;
in favor of a proposition, opinion, etc.;
in opposition to a proposition, opinion, etc.; much was written pro and con;
with conceit; in a conceited manner; he always acts so conceitedly!;
in a conceptual manner; he can no longer think conceptually; conceptually, the idea is quite simple;
in a manner showing concern; Are you all right,he asked concernedly;
in a concise manner; in a few words; the history is summed up concisely in this book; she replied briefly; briefly, we have a problem; to put it shortly;
summed up briefly; gave the facts in a nutshell; just tell me the story in a nutshell; explained the situation in a nutshell;
with concise and precise brevity; to the point; Please state your case as succinctly as possible; he wrote compactly but clearly;
in a conical manner; conically shaped;
with cynicism; in a cynical manner; Larsen's frost-blackened lips curved cynically;
by cytophotometric means;
by means of cytoplasm;
without taking pains; he looked cursorily through the magazine;
in a cumulative manner; mind has become self-reproducing through man's capacity to transmit experience and its products cumulatively;
with honor; he graduated cum laude;
with high honor; he graduated magna cum laude;
with highest honor; he graduated summa cum laude;
in violation of the law; in a criminal manner; the alterations in the document were ruled to be criminally fraudulent;
in a shameful manner; the garden was criminally neglected;
in a coy manner; she pouted and looked at him coyly;
with the legs crossed; he sat on the floor cross-legged and meditated;
with condescension; in a patronizing manner; he treats his secretary condescendingly;
in a consecutive manner; we numbered the papers consecutively;
in a conservative manner; we estimated the number of demonstrators conservatively at 200,000.;
subject to a condition; he accepted the offer conditionally;
not subject to a condition; he accepted the offer unconditionally;
to a crucial degree; crucially important; crucially, he must meet us at the airport;
not in the intended manner; things are going crosswise;
crossing one another in opposite directions;
in the opposite direction; run counter;
in a counteractive manner;
across the countryside; the river runs cross-country; the road runs cross-country;
not following tracks or roads; they liked to race cross-country;
in an ill-natured manner; she looked at her husband crossly;
across a town or city; he traveled crosstown;
in an artful manner; he craftily arranged to be there when the decision was announced; had ever circumstances conspired so cunningly?;
in a confused manner; Queen Augusta wrote him an hysterical letter in which she confusedly sympathised with him;
as a consequence; he had good reason to be grateful for the opportunities which they had made available to him and which consequently led to the good position he now held;
having consequence;
lacking consequence; You're so beautifully dressed,she said and added quite inconsequentially, Can you stay the night?;
in a constructive manner; it is my task to look critically and constructively at the flaws and the failures;
during the same period of time; contemporaneously, or possibly a little later, there developed a great Sumerian civilisation;
in a contrasting manner; contrastingly, both the rooms leading off it gave an immediate impression of being disgraced;
in a composed and unconcerned manner; without more ado Barker borrowed a knife from his brigade Major and honed it on a carborundum stone as coolly as a butcher;
not easy to believe; behind you the coastal hills plunge to the incredibly blue sea backed by the Turkish mountains;
easy to believe on the basis of available evidence; he talked plausibly before the committee; he will probably win the election;
in an incredulous manner; the woman looked up at her incredulously;
in a credulous manner; the children followed the teacher credulously;
in a cryptic manner; we will meet again,he said cryptically;
in a cryptographic manner;
in an attractive manner; how cunningly the olive-green dress with its underskirt of rose-brocade fitted her perfect figure;
in a curt, abrupt and discourteous manner; he told me curtly to get on with it; he talked short with everyone; he said shortly that he didn't like it;
in a damnable manner; kindly Arthur--so damnably , politely , endlessly persistent!;
in a damp manner; a scarf was tied round her head but the rebellious curl had escaped and hung damply over her left eye;
to a degree or in a manner that daunts; dauntingly difficult;
in a daze; in a dazed manner; he wondered dazedly whether the term after next at his new school wouldn't matter so much;
in an indisputable degree; the Fisher Act of 1918 decisively raised their status and pay;
