a photograph taken at close range;
a photographic lens with a short focal length used to take pictures at short ranges;
a flat woolen cap with a stiff peak;
a covering made of cloth;
a brush used for cleaning clothing;
a closet where clothes are stored;
a dryer that dries clothes wet from washing;
a hamper that holds dirty clothes to be washed or wet clothes to be dried;
a framework on which to hang clothes (as for drying);
a cord on which clothes are hung to dry;
wood or plastic fastener; for holding clothes on a clothesline;
an upright pole with pegs or hooks on which to hang clothing;
a covering designed to be worn on a person's body;
a store where men's clothes are sold;
apparatus that detects the path of high-energy particles passing through a supersaturated vapor; each particle ionizes molecules along its path and small droplets condense on them to produce a visible track;
a short nail with a flat head; used to attach sheet metal to wood;
a knot used to fasten a line temporarily to a post or spar;
an interchange that does not require left-hand turns;
an antipsychotic drug (trade name Clozaril) used as a sedative and for treatment-resistant schizophrenia; know to have few side effects;
stout stick that is larger at one end; he carried a club in self defense; he felt as if he had been hit with a club;
a playing card in the minor suit that has one or more black trefoils on it; he led a small club; clubs were trumps;
railroad car having a bar and tables and lounge chairs;
a controlled substance that is usually taken by young people at dance clubs and raves;
a building that is occupied by a social club; the clubhouse needed a new roof;
a room used for the activities of a club;
bomb consisting of a canister that is dropped from a plane and that opens to release a cluster of bomblets (usually fragmentation bombs) over a wide area; cluster bombs cannot be targeted precisely;
a coupling that connects or disconnects driving and driven parts of a driving mechanism; this year's model has an improved clutch;
a pedal or lever that engages or disengages a rotating shaft and a driving mechanism; he smoothely released the clutch with one foot and stepped on the gas with the other;
a woman's strapless purse that is carried in the hand;
a tower in Toronto; 1815 feet tall for broadcasting widely;
a carriage pulled by four horses with one driver;
a small building for housing coaches and carriages and other vehicles;
a bin for holding coal;
freight car with fixed sides and no roof; for transporting coal;
a chute for coal;
a shed for storing coal;
a mine where coal is dug from the ground;
a hand shovel for shoveling coal;
a raised framework around a hatchway on a ship to keep water out;
a covering (plate or mat) that protects the surface of a table (i.e., from the condensation on a cold glass or bottle);
a brake on a bicycle that engages with reverse pressure on the pedals;
an outer garment that has sleeves and covers the body from shoulder down; worn outdoors;
a button on a coat;
a closet for storing outerwear;
a dress that is tailored like a coat and buttons up the front;
a short close-fitting coat;
a hanger that is shaped like a person's shoulders and used to hang garments on;
a thin layer covering something; a second coat of paint;
a heavy fabric suitable for coats;
the official symbols of a family, state, etc.;
a layer of paint covering something else;
a rack with hooks for temporarily holding coats and hats;
the loose back flap of a coat that hangs below the waist;
a transmission line for high-frequency signals;
rectangular paving stone with curved top; once used to make roads;
a dense elaborate spider web that is more efficient than the orb web;
filaments from a web that was spun by a spider;
a fabric so delicate and transparent as to resemble a web of a spider;
dried leaves of the coca plant (and related plants that also contain cocaine); chewed by Andean people for their stimulating effect;
a narcotic (alkaloid) extracted from coca leaves; used as a surface anesthetic or taken for pleasure; can become powerfully addictive;
an ornament (such as a knot of ribbon or a rosette) usually worn on the hat;
a high-voltage machine in which rectifiers charge capacitors that discharge and drive charged particles through an accelerating tube;
hat with opposing brims turned up and caught together to form points;
anything used as a toy horse (such as a rocking horse or one knee of an adult);
a small light flimsy boat;
a small loft or garret;
compartment where the pilot sits while flying the aircraft;
seat where the driver sits while driving a racing car;
a pit for cockfights;
a cap worn by court jesters; adorned with a strip of red;
a dress suitable for formal occasions;
a barroom in a hotel or restaurant where cocktails are served;
a shaker for mixing cocktails;
a small casserole in which individual portions can be cooked and served;
derivative of opium; used as an antitussive (to relieve coughing) and an analgesic (to relieve pain);
(15th-16th century) a flap for the crotch of men's tight-fitting breeches;
optical device used to follow the path of a celestial body and reflect its light into a telescope; has a movable and a fixed mirror;
a can for storing ground coffee;
a cup from which coffee is drunk;
filter (usually of paper) that passes the coffee and retains the coffee grounds;
a kitchen appliance for brewing coffee automatically;
a mill that grinds roasted coffee beans;
a mug intended for serving coffee;
tall pot in which coffee is brewed;
a stand (usually movable) selling hot coffee and food (especially at night);
low table where magazines can be placed and coffee or cocktails are served;
an elaborate oversize book suitable for displaying on a coffee table;
an urn in which coffee is made and kept hot;
a chest especially for storing valuables;
an ornamental sunken panel in a ceiling or dome;
a still consisting of an apparatus for the fractional distillation of ethanol from fermentation on an industrial scale;
box in which a corpse is buried or cremated;
tooth on the rim of gear wheel;
railway for steep mountains; a cogwheel on the locomotive engages cogs on a center rail to provide traction;
a skullcap worn by nuns under a veil or by soldiers under a hood of mail or formerly by British sergeants-at-law;
a structure consisting of something wound in a continuous series of loops; a coil of rope;
reactor consisting of a spiral of insulated wire that introduces inductance into a circuit;
tubing that is wound in a spiral;
a contraceptive device placed inside a woman's womb;
a transformer that supplies high voltage to spark plugs in a gasoline engine;
