an orderly arrangement; an array of troops in battle order;
a group of people or things arranged by class or category;
being twofold; a classification into two opposed parts or subclasses; the dichotomy between eastern and western culture;
being threefold; a classification into three parts or subclasses;
a group of genetically identical cells or organisms derived from a single cell or individual by some kind of asexual reproduction;
a basic group of natural objects;
the highest taxonomic group into which organisms are grouped; one of five biological categories: Monera or Protoctista or Plantae or Fungi or Animalia;
(biology) a taxonomic group comprising a major division of a kingdom;
all inorganic objects; contrasts with animal and plant kingdoms;
a group of plants or animals;
a group of organisms sharing a specific genetic constitution;
organisms sharing a specified genotype or the genotype (or peculiarities) so shared;
(ecology) a group of interdependent organisms inhabiting the same region and interacting with each other;
a major biotic community characterized by the dominant forms of plant life and the prevailing climate;
(plural) any group of human beings (men or women or children) collectively; old people; there were at least 200 people in the audience;
the human beings of a particular nation or community or ethnic group; the indigenous peoples of Australia;
a group of people having approximately the same age;
people who lived in times long past (especially during the historical period before the fall of the Roman Empire in western Europe);
people who are old collectively; special arrangements were available for the aged;
young people collectively; rock music appeals to the young; youth everywhere rises in revolt;
people who are frustrated and perplexed; the children's faces clearly expressed the frustration of the baffled;
people who have severe visual impairments, considered as a group; he spent hours reading to the blind;
people viewed as members of a group; we need more young blood in this organization;
people who are brave; the home of the free and the brave;
people who are fearful and cautious; whitewater rafting is not for the timid;
people who transact business (especially business executives);
people raised in or living in a rural environment; rustics;
people living in the same country; compatriots;
people who are condemned to eternal punishment; he felt he had visited the realm of the damned;
people who are no longer living; they buried the dead;
people who are still living; save your pity for the living;
people who have severe hearing impairments; many of the deaf use sign language;
people who are defeated; the Romans had no pity for the defeated;
people collectively who are crippled or otherwise physically handicapped; technology to help the elderly and the disabled;
(archaic) lame persons collectively; the poor, and the maimed, and the halt, and the blind--Luke 14:21;
people who are destined to die soon; the agony of the doomed was in his voice;
any hostile group of people; he viewed lawyers as the real enemy;
the collective body of bishops;
(botany) the arrangement of sepals and petals in a flower bud before it opens;
people in general (often used in the plural); they're just country folk; folks around here drink moonshine; the common people determine the group character and preserve its customs from one generation to the next;
people of good family and breeding and high social status;
the common people at a local level (as distinguished from the centers of political activity);
people who are free; the home of the free and the brave;
folks from your own home town;
people who are confined to their homes;
poor people who unfortunately do not have a home to live in; the homeless became a problem in the large cities;
people who have been introduced to the mysteries of some field or activity; it is very familiar to the initiate;
people who have not been introduced to the mysteries of some field or activity; it diverts the attention of the uninitiate;
people collectively who are mentally retarded; he started a school for the retarded;
a group of like-minded people united by the internet; a new kind of social or political of business group that may exert broad influence on a shared concern; a network army of software programmers contribute free software to those who want it;
people having common origins or traditions and often comprising a nation; immigrants of the same nationality often seek each other out; such images define their sense of nationality;
(figurative) people whose criticisms are regarded as irrelevant or insignificant (resembling uneducated people who throw peanuts on the stage to express displeasure with a performance); he ignored complaints from the peanut gallery;
a small isolated group of people; they were concentrated in pockets inside the city; the battle was won except for cleaning up pockets of resistance;
people who have retreated; he had only contempt for the retreated;
people who are sick; they devote their lives to caring for the sick;
people who have been slain (as in battle);
people engaged in trade;
people who are wounded; they had to leave the wounded where they fell;
people sharing some social relation;
several things grouped together or considered as a whole;
the collection of equipment and methods used in the practice of medicine;
a collection of art works;
an accumulation of jobs not done or materials not processed that are yet to be dealt with (especially unfilled customer orders for products or services);
a collection of related things intended for use together; took a battery of achievement tests;
a number or quantity of related things dealt with as a unit; he reserved a large block of seats; he held a large block of the company's stock;
a collection of rules or prescribed standards on the basis of which decisions are made; they run things by the book around here;
a collection of playing cards satisfying the rules of a card game;
a collection of bottles; her bottle collection is arranged on glass shelves in the window;
any collection in its entirety; she bought the whole caboodle;
a collection of coins;
any collection of diverse things; a collage of memories;
everything that is included in a collection and that is held or included in something; he emptied the contents of his pockets; the two groups were similar in content;
an assemblage of parts or details (as in a work of art) considered as forming a whole;
a collection of writings; he edited the Hemingway corpus;
a collection of people or things appearing together; the annual crop of students brings a new crop of ideas;
tenants of an estate considered as a group;
a number of pictures loaned by their owners for exhibition;
a collection of tools and other articles used by an artisan to make jewelry or clothing or shoes;
flagstones collectively; there was a pile of flagging waiting to be laid in place;
bits and splinters and fragments; it would have shattered in flinders long before it did that damage;
a complete collection of similar things;
(computer science) a portable pack of magnetic disks used in a disk storage device;
a pack of 52 playing cards;
the cards held in a card game by a given player at any given time; I didn't hold a good hand all evening; he kept trying to see my hand;
in a hand, the suit having the most cards;
the cards held in a game of bridge;
a bridge hand that is void of trumps;
a long suit including high cards;
the 5 cards held in a game of poker;
a poker hand with the ace, king, queen, jack, and 10 all in the same suit;
a poker hand with consecutive cards in the same suit;
a poker hand with 3 of a kind and a pair;
a poker hand with all 5 cards in the same suit;
a poker hand with 5 consecutive cards (regardless of suit);
a poker hand with 2 cards of the same value;
a collection of dried plants that are mounted and systematically classified for study;
a collection of stamps;
statues collectively;
a collection of classical Greek marble sculptures and fragments of architecture created by Phidias; chiefly from the Parthenon in Athens;
the final aggregate; the sum of all our troubles did not equal the misery they suffered;
