a jumbled collection or mass;
all of the identical copies of something offered to the public at the same time; the first edition appeared in 1920; it was too late for the morning edition; they issued a limited edition of Bach recordings;
a grouping of electrons surrounding the nucleus of an atom; the chemical properties of an atom are determined by the outermost electron shell;
a collection of gimmicks;
a grouping of a number of similar things; a bunch of trees; a cluster of admirers;
a tight cluster of people or things; a small knot of women listened to his sermon; the bird had a knot of feathers forming a crest;
the nations possessing nuclear weapons;
a bunch; a thick swad of plants;
a bunch of hair or feathers or growing grass;
a small tuft or lock; wisps of hair;
a compact mass; a ball of mud caught him on the shoulder;
a lump of slimy stuff; a gob of phlegm;
a ball of yarn or cord or thread;
a collection of objects laid on top of each other;
a heap of manure and vegetation and other organic residues that are decaying to become compost;
an ill-structured collection of similar things (objects or people);
a heap of dung or refuse;
an immovable mass of logs blocking a river;
a bushy thick mass (especially hair); he had an unruly shock of black hair;
pile of discarded metal;
a pile of sheaves of grain set on end in a field to dry; stalks of Indian corn set up in a field; corn is bound in small sheaves and several sheaves are set up together in shocks; whole fields of wheat in shock;
pile of waste matter from coal mining etc;
an orderly pile;
a stack of hay;
a small cone-shaped pile of hay that has been left in the field until it is dry enough to carry to the hayrick;
wood heaped for burning a dead body as a funeral rite;
a pile or stack of wood to be used for fuel;
a collection of things that have been combined; an assemblage of separate parts or qualities;
a combination or blend of diverse things; his theory is an amalgam of earlier ideas;
a planned combination of colors; the color scheme for this room was determined by an interior decorator;
a combination that results from coupling or interlinking; diphthongs are complexions of vowels;
an alliance of people or corporations or countries for a special purpose (formerly to achieve some antisocial end but now for general political or economic purposes);
(law) any monopoly or contract or combination or conspiracy intended to restrain commerce (which are illegal according to antitrust laws of the United States);
a group of persons associated by some common tie or occupation and regarded as an entity; the whole body filed out of the auditorium; the student body; administrative body;
a body of people sharing some common interest; the reading public;
people in general; especially a distinctive group of people with some shared interest; the Western world;
an extended social group having a distinctive cultural and economic organization;
a group of people migrating together (especially in some given time period);
a group of people who differ racially or politically from a larger group of which it is a part;
a social group that forms part of the society or the economy; the public sector;
business concerns collectively; Government and business could not agree;
commercial enterprises organized and financed on a scale large enough to influence social and political policies; big business is growing so powerful it is difficult to regulate it effectively;
people of the same race or nationality who share a distinctive culture;
a group that has different national or cultural traditions from the majority of the population;
people who are believed to belong to the same genetic stock; some biologists doubt that there are important genetic differences between races of human beings;
a race with skin pigmentation different from the white race (especially Blacks);
a race that considers itself superior to all others and fitted to rule the others;
(usually plural) a social group whose members control some field of activity and who have common aims; the iron interests stepped up production;
an individual or group who are concerned with some particular part of the economy and who try to influence legislators or bureaucrats to act in their favor;
groups that seek to control a social system or activity from which they derive private benefit;
a country's military establishment and the industries that produce arms and other military equipment; we must guard against the acquisition of unwarranted influence, whether sought or unsought, by the military-industrial complex--Dwight David Eisenhower;
group of people related by blood or marriage;
(Yiddish) the entire family network of relatives by blood or marriage (and sometimes close friends); she invited the whole mishpocha;
your friends and acquaintances; all his kith and kin;
primary social group; parents and children; he wanted to have a good job before starting a family;
people descended from a common ancestor; his family has lived in Massachusetts since the Mayflower;
your parents; he wrote to his folks every day;
members of a family line; his people have been farmers for generations; are your people still alive?;
the people of your home locality (especially your own family); he wrote his homefolk every day;
aristocratic family line; the House of York;
a sequence of powerful leaders in the same family;
family based on male descent; he had no sons and there was no one to carry on his name;
the social system that developed in Europe in the 8th century; vassals were protected by lords who they had to serve in war;
a form of social organization in which a male is the family head and title is traced through the male line;
a form of social organization in which a female is the family head and title is traced through the female line;
a form of social system in which power goes to those with superior intellects;
the occupants of a building; the entire building complained about the noise;
a family in which the parents have separated or divorced;
a family consisting of parents and their children and grandparents of a marital partner;
a family consisting of the nuclear family and their blood relatives;
the family of a fosterling;
a household in which an orphaned or delinquent child is placed (usually by a social-service agency);
people having the same social, economic, or educational status; the working class; an emerging professional class;
people in the same age range;
a social group holding marginal or extreme views; members of the fringe believe we should be armed with guns at all times;
a group of persons together in one place;
a social gathering to carry out some communal task or to hold competitions;
a gathering of passengers sufficient to fill an automobile;
an assemblage of people or animals or things collected together; a congregation of children pleaded for his autograph; a great congregation of birds flew over;
a gathering of persons representative of some larger group; each nation sent a contingent of athletes to the Olympics;
the occupants of a floor; the whole floor complained about the lack of heat;
a social gathering intended to create goodwill among the participants;
a gathering to make quilts;
two people considered as a unit;
a collection of the best or most popular people or items of a given kind;
historical and literary materials relating to Judaism;
a badly assembled collection of parts hastily assembled to serve some particular purpose(oftenusedtorefertocomputingsystemsorsoftwarethathasbeenbadlyputtogether);
(computing) a collection of standard programs and subroutines that are stored and available for immediate use;
a collection of literary documents or records kept for reference or borrowing;
a collection of books;
a nonprofit library maintained for public use;
a collection of books that can be rented by readers in return for a small daily fee;
myths collectively; the body of stories associated with a culture or institution or person;
the system of mythology of the Greeks and Romans together; much of Roman mythology (especially the gods) was borrowed from the Greeks;
the mythology of the ancient Greeks;
the mythology of the ancient Romans;
the mythology of Scandinavia (shared in part by Britain and Germany) until the establishment of Christianity;
a collection of 13 ancient papyrus codices translated from Greek into Coptic that were discovered by farmers near the town of Nag Hammadi in 1945; the codices contain 45 distinct works including the chief sources of firsthand knowledge of Gnosticism;
a set containing a single member;
a set of two similar things considered as a unit;
