an erect to spreading hairy shrub of the Pacific coast of the United States having racemes of red to indigo flowers;
dense shrub of moist riverbanks and flood plains of the eastern United States having attractive fragrant foliage and dense racemes of dark purple flowers;
very small genus of twining vines of North America and Asia: hog peanut;
vine widely distributed in eastern North America producing racemes of purple to maroon flowers and abundant (usually subterranean) edible one-seeded pods resembling peanuts;
very small genus of shrubs of southern Europe having backward curving seed pods;
shrub with trifoliate leaves and yellow flowers followed by backward curving seed pods; leaves foetid when crushed;
small genus of evergreen trees of tropical America and western Africa;
any of several tropical American trees of the genus Andira;
tree with shaggy unpleasant-smelling toxic bark and yielding strong durable wood; bark and seeds used as a purgative and vermifuge and narcotic;
genus of Mediterranean herbs and shrubs;
silvery hairy European shrub with evergreen foliage and pale yellow flowers;
perennial Eurasian herb having heads of red or yellow flowers and common in meadows and pastures; formerly used medicinally for kidney disorders;
twining perennial North American plants;
a North American vine with fragrant blossoms and edible tubers; important food crop of Native Americans;
genus of South African heathlike shrubs;
South African shrub having flat acuminate leaves and yellow flowers; leaves are aromatic when dried and used to make an herbal tea;
large genus of annual or perennial herbs or shrubs of north temperate regions; largest genus in the family Leguminosae;
any of various plants of the genus Astragalus;
European perennial;
perennial of mountainous areas of Eurasia and North America;
perennial of southern and western Europe having dense racemes of purple or violet flowers;
small genus of shrubs and lianas and trees of Africa and Madagascar;
small shrubby African tree with hard wood used as a dyewood yielding a red dye;
genus of North American plants with showy flowers and an inflated pod;
any of several plants of the genus Baptisia;
wild indigo of the eastern United States having racemes of blue flowers;
erect or spreading herb having racemes of creamy white flowers; the eastern United States;
much-branched erect herb with bright yellow flowers; distributed from Massachusetts to Florida;
genus of East Indian trees or shrubs: dhak;
East Indian tree bearing a profusion of intense vermilion velvet-textured blooms and yielding a yellow dye;
erect densely branched shrubby perennials of Old World tropics; naturalized in other warm regions;
tropical woody herb with showy yellow flowers and flat pods; much cultivated in the tropics;
herbs or woody vines of mainly American tropics and subtropics;
annual semi-erect bushy plant of tropical South America bearing long pods with white seeds grown especially for forage;
twining tropical Old World plant bearing long pods usually with red or brown beans; long cultivated in Orient for food;
large genus of Asiatic deciduous shrubs or small trees;
any plant of the genus Caragana having even-pinnate leaves and mostly yellow flowers followed by seeds in a linear pod;
large spiny shrub of eastern Asia having clusters of yellow flowers; often cultivated in shelterbelts and hedges;
shrub with dark-green glossy foliage and solitary pale yellow flowers; northern China;
a rosid dicot genus of the subfamily Papilionoideae having one species: Moreton Bay chestnut;
Australian tree having pinnate leaves and orange-yellow flowers followed by large woody pods containing 3 or 4 seeds that resemble chestnuts; yields dark strong wood;
a genus of chiefly tropical American vines of the family Leguminosae having trifoliate leaves and large flowers;
large-flowered weakly twining or prostrate vine of New Jersey to tropical eastern North America, sometimes cultivated for its purple and white flowers;
deciduous shrubs and trees of eastern Asia, southern Europe and the United States;
small tree of the eastern Mediterranean having abundant purplish-red flowers growing on old wood directly from stems and appearing before the leaves: widely cultivated in mild regions; wood valuable for veneers;
small shrubby tree of eastern North America similar to the Judas tree having usually pink flowers; found in damp sheltered underwood;
shrub of western United States having pink or crimson flowers; often forms thickets;
small late-flowering trees or subshrubs having yellow to red flowers and leathery or woody pods; often especially formerly included in genus Cytisus;
shrub of Canary Islands having bristle-tipped oblanceolate leaves; used as cattle fodder;
2 species of small New Zealand trees: weeping tree broom; endangered;
small shrubby tree of New Zealand having weeping branches and racemes of white to violet flowers followed by woolly indehiscent two-seeded pods;
genus of Australian twining vines and small shrubs: flame peas;
any of several small shrubs or twining vines having entire or lobed leaves and racemes of yellow to orange-red flowers; Australia;
chickpea plant; Asiatic herbs;
Asiatic herb cultivated for its short pods with one or two edible seeds;
the seed of the chickpea plant;
yellowwoods;
small handsome roundheaded deciduous tree having showy white flowers in terminal clusters and heavy hardwood yielding yellow dye;
genus of semi-prostrate Australasian shrubs or vines;
any of various shrubs or vines of the genus Clianthus having compound leaves and pea-like red flowers in drooping racemes;
sprawling shrubby perennial noted for its scarlet black-marked flowers; widely distributed in dry parts of Australia;
evergreen shrub with scarlet to white clawlike or beaklike flowers; New Zealand;
genus of tropical shrubs or vines having pinnate leaves and large axillary flowers;
large-flowered wild twining vine of southeastern and central United States having pale blue flowers;
vine of tropical Asia having pinnate leaves and bright blue flowers with yellow centers;
used in some classifications for plants usually included in genus Desmodium;
erect tropical Asian shrub whose small lateral leaflets rotate on their axes and jerk up and down under the influence of sunshine;
small genus of Eurasian shrubs with yellow flowers and bladdery pods;
yellow-flowered European shrub cultivated for its succession of yellow flowers and very inflated bladdery pods and as a source of wildlife food;
genus of Old World shrubs and herbs;
any of various plants of the genus Coronilla having purple or pink or yellow flowers in long axillary heads or umbels;
European herb resembling vetch; naturalized in the eastern United States; having umbels of pink-and-white flowers and sharp-angled pods;
large genus of herbs with simple leaves and racemes of yellow flowers; mainly of tropical Africa;
any of various plants of the genus Crotalaria having inflated pods within which the seeds rattle; used for pasture and green-manure crops;
tropical American annual herb having an inflated pod in which the ripe seeds rattle;
erect subshrub having purple-tinted flowers and an inflated pod in which the ripe seeds rattle; India;
small genus of annual usually hairy herbs of tropical Africa and Arabia;
drought-tolerant herb grown for forage and for its seed which yield a gum used as a thickening agent or sizing material;
large genus of stiff or spiny evergreen or deciduous Old World shrubs: broom;
any of various shrubs of the genera Cytisus or Genista or Spartium having long slender branches and racemes of yellow flowers;
low European broom having trifoliate leaves and yellowish-white flowers;
deciduous erect spreading broom native to western Europe; widely cultivated for its rich yellow flowers;
an abnormal tufted growth of small branches on a tree or shrub caused by fungi or insects or other physiological disturbance;
large genus of tropical trees having pinnate leaves and paniculate flowers and cultivated commercially for their dramatically grained and colored timbers;
any of those hardwood trees of the genus Dalbergia that yield rosewood--valuable cabinet woods of a dark red or purplish color streaked and variegated with black;
hard dark reddish wood of a rosewood tree having a strongly marked grain; used in cabinetwork;
East Indian tree having a useful dark purple wood;
East Indian tree whose leaves are used for fodder; yields a compact dark brown durable timber used in shipbuilding and making railroad ties;
Brazilian tree yielding a handsome cabinet wood;
handsome violet-streaked wood of the kingwood tree; used especially in cabinetwork;
an important Brazilian timber tree yielding a heavy hard dark-colored wood streaked with black;
Central American tree yielding a valuable dark streaked rosewood;
a valuable timber tree of tropical South America;
dark red hardwood derived from the cocobolo and used in making musical instruments e.g. clarinets;
any of several hardwood trees yielding very dark-colored wood;
very dark wood of any of several blackwood trees;
indigo bush;
greyish-green shrub of desert regions of southwestern United States and Mexico having sparse foliage and terminal spikes of bluish violet flowers; locally important as source of a light-colored honey of excellent flavor;
genus of Australasian shrubs and subshrubs having small yellow or purple flowers followed by short triangular pods;
any of several spiny shrubs of the genus Daviesia having yellow flowers and triangular seeds; Australia;
