large African forest tree yielding a strong hard yellow to golden brown lumber; sometimes placed in genus Sarcocephalus;
small genus of shrubs or small trees of southeastern United States and northern South America;
ornamental shrub or small tree of swampy areas in southwestern United States having large pink or white sepals and yielding Georgia bark for treating fever;
tropical chiefly South American shrubs and trees;
South African evergreen having hard tough wood;
hard tough elastic wood of the lemonwood tree; used for making bows and fishing rods;
genus of tropical African trees and shrubs;
a stout spreading or semi-climbing tropical shrub with round brownish-red warty fruit; Africa;
tropical African and Asiatic trees and shrubs having one-seeded fruit;
small deciduous tree of southern Africa having edible fruit;
shrubby tree of Madagascar occasionally cultivated for its edible apple-shaped fruit;
shrubs and small trees and woody vines;
chiefly east Asian shrubs;
any of various deciduous or evergreen ornamental shrubs of the genus Abelia having opposite simple leaves and cymes of small white or pink or purplish flowers; Asia and Mexico;
small genus of low deciduous shrubs: bush honeysuckles;
spreading bush of northeastern United States having small clusters of fragrant green and yellow flowers;
bush honeysuckle of southeastern United States having large crowded clusters of sulfur-yellow flowers;
(Chinese genus of 1 species) beauty bush;
Chinese deciduous shrub with yellow-throated pinkish flowers and bristly fruit; often cultivated as an ornamental;
small species of shrubs of western Himalayas to China;
shrub honeysuckle with drooping spikes of purplish flowers;
one species: twinflower;
creeping evergreen subshrub of the northern parts of Europe and Asia with delicate fragrant tubular bell-shaped usually pink flowers borne in pairs;
similar to the twinflower of northern Europe and Asia;
woodbine;
shrub or vine of the genus Lonicera;
bushy honeysuckle with twining branches and white or yellow-white flowers; southern United States;
erect deciduous North American shrub with yellow-white flowers;
deciduous climbing shrub with fragrant yellow-white flowers in axillary whorls;
twining deciduous shrub with clusters of purple-tinged yellow-green flowers; northeastern America;
climbing deciduous shrub with fragrant yellow (later orange) flowers in terminal whorls; southeastern United States;
twining deciduous shrub with hairy leaves and spikes of yellow-orange flowers; northeastern America;
shrubby honeysuckle with purple flowers; western North America;
an Asiatic trailing evergreen honeysuckle with half-evergreen leaves and fragrant white flowers turning yellow with age; has become a weed in some areas;
a variety of Japanese honeysuckle that grows like a vine; established as an aggressive escape in southeastern United States;
a grey deciduous honeysuckle shrub paired white flowers turning yellow; Japan;
European twining honeysuckle with fragrant red and yellow-white flowers;
evergreen North American honeysuckle vine having coral-red or orange flowers;
a honeysuckle shrub of southern Russia to central Asia;
cultivated Eurasian shrub with twin yellowish-white flowers and scarlet fruit;
a variety of fly honeysuckle;
deciduous shrubs of North America and Central America and China;
deciduous shrub of western North America having spikes of pink flowers followed by round white berries;
North American deciduous shrub cultivated for it abundant clusters of coral-red berrylike fruits;
elder; elderberry;
any of numerous shrubs or small trees of temperate and subtropical northern hemisphere having white flowers and berrylike fruit;
common elder of central and eastern North America bearing purple-black berries; fruit used in wines and jellies;
shrub or small tree of western United States having white flowers and blue berries; fruit used in wines and jellies;
dwarf herbaceous elder of Europe having pink flowers and a nauseous odor;
a common shrub with black fruit or a small tree of Europe and Asia; fruit used for wines and jellies;
common North American shrub or small tree;
Eurasian shrub;
genus of Asiatic and North American herbs: feverroot;
coarse weedy American perennial herb with large usually perfoliate leaves and purple or dull red flowers;
deciduous or evergreen shrubs or small trees: arrow-wood ; wayfaring tree;
deciduous North American shrub or small tree having three-lobed leaves and red berries;
vigorous deciduous European treelike shrub common along waysides; red berries turn black;
deciduous thicket-forming Old World shrub with clusters of white flowers and small bright red berries;
deciduous shrub of eastern North America having blue-black berries and tough pliant wood formerly used to make arrows;
closely related to southern arrow wood; grows in the eastern United States from Maine to Ohio and Georgia;
upright deciduous shrub having frosted dark-blue fruit; east and east central North America;
east Asian flowering shrubs;
deciduous shrub widely cultivated for its white or pink or red flowers;
chiefly southern European herbs with flowers usually in dense cymose heads;
type genus of the Dipsacaceae: teasel;
any of several herbs of the genus Dipsacus native to the Old World having flower heads surrounded by spiny bracts;
teasel with lilac flowers native to Old World but naturalized in North America; dried flower heads used to raise a nap on woolen cloth;
similar to the common teasel and similarly used; widespread in Europe and North Africa and western Asia; naturalized in United States;
European teasel with white to pink flowers; naturalized in United States;
annual or perennial herbs or subshrubs; mainly Mediterranean;
any of various plants of the genus Scabiosa;
Old World annual having fragrant purple to deep crimson flower heads; naturalized in United States;
perennial having bluish-lilac flowers; introduced in the eastern United States;
distinguished from the family Geraniaceae by the irregular flowers;
annual or perennial herbs with stems more or less succulent; cosmopolitan except for South America, Australia, and New Zealand;
North American annual plant with usually yellow or orange flowers; grows chiefly on wet rather acid soil;
an order of plants of subclass Rosidae including geraniums and many other plants; see Euphorbiaceae; Geraniaceae; Rutaceae; Malpighiaceae; Simaroubaceae; Meliaceae; Zygophyllaceae; Tropaeolaceae;
chiefly herbaceous plants;
any of numerous plants of the family Geraniaceae;
genus of mostly North American geraniums: cranesbills;
any of numerous geraniums of the genus Geranium;
common wild geranium of eastern North America with deeply parted leaves and rose-purple flowers;
tall perennial cranesbill with paired violet-blue axillary flowers; native to northern parts of Old World and naturalized in North America;
geranium of western North America having branched clusters of white or pale pink flowers;
a sticky low herb with small reddish-purple flowers; widespread in the northern hemisphere;
geranium of western North America having pinkish-purple flowers in open clusters;
western geranium with small pink flowers; a common weed on lawns and in vacant lots;
geraniums native chiefly to South Africa; widely cultivated;
any of several southern African geraniums having fragrant three-lobed to five-lobed leaves and pink flowers;
an upright geranium having scalloped leaves with a broad color zone inside the margin and white or pink or red flowers;
a commonly cultivated trailing South American plant with peltate leaves and rosy flowers;
geranium with round fragrant leaves and small white flowers;
a common garden geranium with lemon-scented foliage;
geraniums of Europe and South America and Australia especially mountainous regions;
any of various plants of the genus Erodium;
European weed naturalized in southwestern United States and Mexico having reddish decumbent stems with small fernlike leaves and small deep reddish-lavender flowers followed by slender fruits that stick straight up; often grown for forage;
low annual European herb naturalized in America; similar to alfilaria;
of prairies and desert areas of southwestern United States and Mexico;
a family of plants of order Geraniales; have drupaceous fruit;
a large genus of South American shrubs and small trees of the family Erythroxylaceae;
