in an inaudible manner; she spoke inaudibly low;
in a beastly manner; she behaved beastly toward her mother-in-law;
genuinely; with authority; it is authentically British;
without bloodshed; in a bloodless manner; without shedding blood; the coup disposed of the dictator bloodlessly;
involving a great bloodshed;
in a grandiose manner; the building was bombastically spacious;
in a turgid manner; he lectured bombastically about his theories;
like a boy; he smiled boyishly at his fiancee;
with the bottom lodged on the ground; he ran the ship aground;
with hands on hips and elbows extending outward; she stood there akimbo;
on or toward the lee; put the helm alee;
in mentally perceptive and responsive way; she got through the day alertly, despite being on drugs;
as known or named at another time or place; Mr. Smith, alias Mr. Lafayette;
in a moderately quick tempo; play this more allegretto;
in a quick and lively tempo; play this section allegro;
in an alliterative manner; the early Norse poets wrote alliteratively;
in an altruistic manner; he acted selflessly when he helped the old lady in distress;
in an anomalous manner; this man behaves anomalously;
with appreciation; in a grateful manner; he accepted my offer appreciatively;
in an ungrateful manner;
with respect to arithmetic; this problem is arithmetically easy;
with a side or oblique glance; did not quite turn all the way back but looked askance at me with her dark eyes;
with suspicion or disapproval; he looked askance at the offer;
away from the correct or expected course; something has gone awry in our plans; something went badly amiss in the preparations;
turned or twisted to one side; rugs lying askew; with his necktie twisted awry;
with care and persistence; she worked assiduously on the senior thesis;
with perseverance;
with persistence;
in a shrewd manner; he invested his fortune astutely; he was acutely insightful;
transversely; the marble slabs were cut across;
to the opposite side; the football field was 300 feet across;
with all your strength; he pulled the ropes amain;
at full speed; with great haste; the children ran down the hill amain;
at or near or toward the middle;
in a murderous frenzy; rioters running amuck and throwing sticks and bottles and stones;
wildly; without self-control; when the restaurant caught fire the patrons ran amuck, blocking the exit;
with antithesis; in an antithetical manner;
at an opportune time; your letter arrived apropos;
in accordance with the season; it was seasonably cold;
not in accordance with the season; it was unseasonably cold;
in an arch manner; with playful slyness or roguishness;
in an arduous manner; they worked arduously;
in an ingenuous manner; she answered the judge's questions artlessly;
in a crude and unskilled manner; an inexpertly constructed lean-to;
at an oblique angle; the sun shone aslant into his face;
in a blissful manner; he was blissfully unaware of the danger;
over or across in a slanting direction;
into a sleeping state; he fell asleep;
in the sleep of death;
(of a ship or an airplane) behind; we dropped her astern on the end of a seven-inch manilla, and she laid comfortably on the ebb tide;
at or near or toward the stern of a ship or tail of an airplane; stow the luggage aft; ships with square sails sail fairly efficiently with the wind abaft; the captain looked astern to see what the fuss was about;
near or toward the bow of a ship or cockpit of a plane; the captain went fore (or forward) to check the instruments;
stern foremost or backward; the steamer went astern at half speed;
with one leg on each side; she sat astride the chair;
with the legs stretched far apart;
at right angles to the center line of a ship;
on, to, or at the top;
in an austere fashion; the church was austerely simple;
in a greedy manner;
by open declaration; their policy has been avowedly Marxist; Susan Smith was professedly guilty of the murders;
in or to a backstage area of a theater; costumes were changed backstage;
out of view of the public; behind the scenes; Working backstage to gain political support for his proposal; many private deals were made backstage at the convention;
confidentially or in secret; told her friend privily that she was planning to be married;
in a bald manner; this book is, to put it baldly, an uneven work.;
in a baleful manner; she looked at him balefully;
in a noxiously baneful way; this banefully poisoned climate;
directly; he ran bang into the pole; ran slap into her;
in a bantering fashion; he spoke to her banteringly;
in a barbarous manner; they were barbarously murdered;
without a saddle; she prefers to ride her horse bareback;
without shoes on; he chased her barefoot across the meadow;
in a bawdy manner;
in a becoming manner; she was becomingly dressed;
in a beneficial manner; this medicine will act beneficially on you;
in a benign manner; this drug is benignly soporific;
in a beseeching manner; You must help me,she said imploringly;
in a bewitching manner; she was bewitchingly beautiful;
every two years; this festival takes places biennially;
twice a year; we hold our big sale biannually;
without expression; in a blank manner; she stared at him blankly;
in a blasphemous manner; the sailors were cursing blasphemously;
in a blunt direct manner; he spoke bluntly; he stated his opinion flat-out ; he was criticized roundly;
like a boor, he behaved boorishly at the party;
in a bountiful manner;
in the direction of the breadth; cut the cloth breadthwise;
in a breezy manner; he swings breezily into the title song;
in a brisk manner; she walked briskly in the cold air; after lunch,she said briskly;
in an inhumane manner; she treated her husband bestially;
in a bumptious manner; he behaved rather bumptiously and offended the hostess;
in a cheerfully buoyant manner; we accepted the opportunity buoyantly;
very happily; we were floating on air at the news;
with respect to bureaucracy; it's bureaucratically complicated;
in a bureaucratic manner; his bureaucratically petty behavior annoyed her;
in a cagey manner; I don't know yet,he answered cagily;
in a bad mood; he answered her cantankerously;
in a capricious manner; there were Turk's head lilies and patches of iris , islands of brilliant blue set capriciously in the green sea;
unpredictably; the weather has been freakishly variable;
in a captious, carping manner; he was captiously pedantic;
in a caustic vitriolic manner; he addressed her caustically;
as if with kid gloves; with caution or prudence or tact; she ventured cautiously downstairs; they handled the incident with kid gloves;
