yews;
any of numerous evergreen trees or shrubs having red cup-shaped berries and flattened needlelike leaves;
wood of a yew; especially the durable fine-grained light brown or red wood of the English yew valued for cabinetwork and archery bows;
predominant yew in Europe; extraordinarily long-lived and slow growing; one of the oldest species in the world;
small or medium irregularly branched tree of the Pacific coast of North America; yields fine hard close-grained wood;
shrubby hardy evergreen of China and Japan having lustrous dark green foliage; cultivated in the eastern United States;
small bushy yew of northern Florida having spreading branches and very narrow leaves;
a gymnosperm genus having one species: New Caledonian yew;
large yew native to New Caledonia; cultivated in eastern Australia and New Zealand and Hawaii;
one species;
yew of southeastern China, differing from the Old World yew in having white berries;
ginkgos: in some systems classified as a class and in others as a subdivision; used in some classifications for one of five subdivisions of Gymnospermophyta;
coextensive with the family Ginkgoaceae: plants that first appeared in the Permian and now represented by a single surviving species; often included in Coniferales;
constituting the order Ginkgoales; includes the genus Ginkgo and extinct forms;
sole surviving genus of the Ginkgoaceae;
deciduous dioecious Chinese tree having fan-shaped leaves and fleshy yellow seeds; exists almost exclusively in cultivation especially as an ornamental street tree;
used in former classifications to include all ferns and flowering plants and divided into the three classes Filicinae and Gymnospermae and Angiospermae;
comprising flowering plants that produce seeds enclosed in an ovary; in some systems considered a class (Angiospermae) and in others a division (Magnoliophyta or Anthophyta);
plants having seeds in a closed ovary;
tree bearing fruit enclosed in a shell or involucre or husk;
comprising seed plants that produce an embryo with paired cotyledons and net-veined leaves; divided into six (not always well distinguished) subclasses (or superorders): Magnoliidae and Hamamelidae (considered primitive); Caryophyllidae (an early and distinctive offshoot); and three more or less advanced groups: Dilleniidae; Rosidae; Asteridae;
flowering plant with two cotyledons; the stem grows by deposit on its outside;
a group of families of trees and shrubs and herbs having well-developed perianths and apocarpous ovaries and generally regarded as the most primitive extant flowering plants; contains 36 families including Magnoliaceae and Ranunculaceae; sometimes classified as a superorder;
comprising seed plants that produce an embryo with a single cotyledon and parallel-veined leaves: includes grasses and lilies and palms and orchids; divided into four subclasses or superorders: Alismatidae; Arecidae; Commelinidae; and Liliidae;
a monocotyledonous flowering plant; the stem grows by deposits on its inside;
one of four subclasses or superorders of Monocotyledones; comprises about 500 species in 14 families of aquatic and semiaquatic herbs;
one of four subclasses or superorder of Monocotyledones; comprises about 6400 species in 5 families of trees and shrubs and terrestrial herbs and a few free-floating aquatics including: Palmae; Araceae; Pandanaceae and Lemnaceae;
one of four subclasses or superorders of Monocotyledones; comprises about 19,000 species in 25 families of mostly terrestrial herbs especially of moist places including: Cyperaceae; Gramineae; Bromeliaceae; and Zingiberaceae;
reproductive organ of angiosperm plants especially one having showy or colorful parts;
a diminutive flower (especially one that is part of a composite flower);
a plant cultivated for its blooms or blossoms;
a flower that blooms in a particular way; a night bloomer;
wild or uncultivated flowering plant;
flower having no petals;
a shortened compact cluster of flowers so arranged that the whole gives the effect of a single flower as in clover or members of the family Compositae;
the flowering part of a plant or arrangement of flowers on a stalk;
small flower with a flat strap-shaped corolla usually occupying the peripheral rings of a composite flower;
a cylindrical spikelike inflorescence;
a partially opened flower;
the bud of a rose;
the male reproductive organ of a flower;
the part of the stamen that contains pollen; usually borne on a stalk;
the crown of the stamen in plants of the genus Asclepias;
the fine spores that contain male gametes and that are borne by an anther in a flowering plant;
a coherent mass of pollen grains (as in orchids);
the parts of a plant involved in its reproduction;
the female ovule-bearing part of a flower composed of ovary and style and stigma;
the enlarged receptacle in which the pistil is borne;
the stalk of a pistil that raises it above the receptacle;
consists of one carpel;
consists of two or more fused carpels;
a sterile vestigial pistil remaining in a staminate flower;
(botany) the narrow elongated part of the pistil between the ovary and the stigma;
an enlargement at the base of the style in some Umbelliferae;
the apical end of the style where deposited pollen enters the pistil;
a simple pistil or one element of a compound pistil;
a slender stalk that furnishes an axis for a carpel;
the stalk of a corn plant;
the stalk of a stamen;
the stalk of a plant ovule or seed;
the stalk of a leaflet;
a carpel with one seed; one of a pair split apart at maturity;
the scar on certain seeds marking its point of attachment to the funicle;
the organ that bears the ovules of a flower;
a small body that contains the female germ cell of a plant; develops into a seed after fertilization;
basal part of a plant ovule opposite the micropyle; where integument and nucellus are joined;
central part of a plant ovule; contains the embryo sac;
minute opening in the wall of an ovule through which the pollen tube enters;
a partly inverted ovule turned back 90 degrees on its stalk;
a completely inverted ovule turned back 180 degrees on its stalk;
a curved ovule with the micropyle almost touching the funiculus;
a completely straight ovule with the micropyle at the apex;
a minute epidermal pore in a leaf or stem through which gases and water vapor can pass;
a pore in the outer wall of a spore or pollen grain through which the germ tube or pollen tube makes its exit on germination;
(botany) a slender tubular outgrowth from a spore in germination;
(botany) a slender tubular outgrowth from a pollen grain when deposited on the stigma for a flower; it penetrates the style and conveys the male gametes to the ovule;
that part of the ovary of a flowering plant where the ovules form;
arrangement of the ovules in the placenta and of the placentas in the ovary;
where one or few ovules develop at the top of a simple or compound ovary;
ovules are borne at or around the center of a compound ovary on an axis formed from joined septa;
where one or few ovules develop at the base of a simple or compound ovary;
where ovules develop on a central column in a compound ovary lacking septa or with septa at base only;
with ovules on thin extensions of the placentae into a compound ovary;
with ovules borne on the wall along the ventral suture of a simple ovary;
where ovules develop on the wall or slight outgrowths of the wall forming broken partitions within a compound ovary;
protective outer layer of seeds of flowering plants;
nutritive tissue surrounding the embryo within seeds of flowering plants;
small asexual reproductive structure in e.g. liverworts and mosses that detaches from the parent and develops into a new individual;
cone-shaped mass of ovule- or spore-bearing scales or bracts;
the seed-producing cone of a fir tree;
the seed-producing cone of a cypress tree;
the seed-producing cone of a pine tree;
a partition or wall especially in an ovary;
the hard usually fibrous outer layer of some fruits especially nuts;
the shell around the kernel of a nut;
a gland (often a protuberance or depression) that secretes nectar;
a mature fertilized plant ovule consisting of an embryo and its food source and having a protective coat or testa;
the ripened and variously modified walls of a plant ovary;
outermost layer of the pericarp of fruits as the skin of a peach or grape;
the middle layer of a pericarp;
