North American perennial herb with alternately compound leaves and racemes of small white flowers followed by bright red oval poisonous berries;
North American herb with white poisonous berries;
annual or perennial herbs;
Eurasian herb cultivated for its deep red flowers with dark centers;
perennial herbs with tuberous roots and beautiful flowers; of north and south temperate regions;
any woodland plant of the genus Anemone grown for its beautiful flowers and whorls of dissected leaves;
silky-foliaged herb of the Rocky Mountains with bluish-white flowers;
common summer-flowering woodland herb of Labrador to Colorado;
a common North American anemone with cylindrical fruit clusters resembling thimbles;
European anemone with solitary white flowers common in deciduous woodlands;
common anemone of eastern North America with solitary pink-tinged white flowers;
thimbleweed of northern North America;
Eurasian herb with solitary nodding fragrant white flowers;
thimbleweed of central and eastern North America;
one species: rue anemone;
woodland flower native to eastern North America having cup-shaped flowers reminiscent of anemone but more delicate;
columbine;
a plant of the genus Aquilegia having irregular showy spurred flowers; north temperate regions especially mountains;
columbine of eastern North America having long-spurred red flowers;
columbine of the Rocky Mountains having long-spurred blue flowers;
common European columbine having variously colored (white or blue to purple or red) short-spurred flowers; naturalized in United States;
a genus of Caltha;
swamp plant of Europe and North America having bright yellow flowers resembling buttercups;
small genus of perennial herbs of north temperate regions: bugbane;
a plant of the genus Cimicifuga having flowers in long racemes or panicles reported to be distasteful to insects;
bugbane of the eastern United States having erect racemes of white flowers;
North American bugbane found from Maine and Ontario to Wisconsin and south to Georgia;
bugbane of Siberia and eastern Asia having ill-smelling green-white flowers;
large genus of deciduous or evergreen woody vines or erect herbs;
any of various ornamental climbing plants of the genus Clematis usually having showy flowers;
erect clematis of Florida having pink to purple flowers;
climber of southern United States having bluish-purple flowers;
clematis of California;
shrubby clematis of the eastern United States having curly foliage;
Chinese clematis with serrate leaves and large yellow flowers;
woody vine of Texas having showy solitary nodding scarlet flowers;
woody vine of the southern United States having purple or blue flowers with leathery recurved sepals;
scandent subshrub of southeastern United States having large red-purple bell-shaped flowers with leathery recurved sepals;
common climber of eastern North America that sprawls over other plants and bears numerous panicles of small creamy white flowers;
vigorous deciduous climber of Europe to Afghanistan and Lebanon having panicles of fragrant green-white flowers in summer and autumn;
climber of northeastern North America having waxy purplish-blue flowers;
small genus of low perennial herbs having yellow rhizomes and white or yellow flowers;
low-growing perennial of North America woodlands having trifoliate leaves and yellow rootstock and white flowers;
plants having flowers resembling the larkspur's but differing from larkspur's in the arrangement of petals; sometimes included in genus Delphinium;
commonly cultivated larkspur of southern Europe having unbranched spikelike racemes of blue or sometimes purplish or pinkish flowers; sometime placed in genus Delphinium;
large genus of chiefly perennial erect branching herbs of north temperate regions some poisonous;
any plant of the genus Delphinium having palmately divided leaves and showy spikes of variously colored spurred flowers; some contain extremely poisonous substances;
any of numerous cultivated plants of the genus Delphinium;
winter aconite;
small Old World perennial herb grown for its bright yellow flowers which appear in early spring often before snow is gone;
a genus of Helleborus;
any plant of the Eurasian genus Helleborus;
digitate-leaved hellebore with an offensive odor and irritant qualities when taken internally;
European evergreen plant with white or purplish rose-like winter-blooming flowers;
slightly hairy perennial having deep green leathery leaves and flowers that are ultimately purplish-green;
deciduous plant with large deep green pedate leaves and nodding saucer-shaped green flowers;
small genus of perennial herbs of north temperate regions; allied to genus Anemone;
any of several plants of the genus Hepatica having three-lobed leaves and white or pinkish flowers in early spring; of moist and mossy subalpine woodland areas of north temperate regions;
small genus of perennial herbs having rhizomes and palmate leaves and small solitary flowers; of northeastern United States and Japan;
perennial herb of northeastern United States having a thick knotted yellow rootstock and large rounded leaves;
tufted perennial herbs of northern hemisphere;
slender erect perennial of eastern North America having tuberous roots and pink-tinged white flowers; resembles meadow rue;
one species: giant buttercup;
spectacular perennial native of wet montane grasslands of Peru; formerly included in genus Ranunculus;
erect annual Eurasian herbs;
any plant of the genus Nigella;
European garden plant having finely cut leaves and white or pale blue flowers;
nigella of Spain and southern France;
herb of the Mediterranean region having pungent seeds used like those of caraway;
includes a group of plants that in some classifications are included in the genus Anemone: pasqueflowers;
any plant of the genus Pulsatilla; sometimes included in genus Anemone;
short hairy perennial with early spring blue-violet or lilac flowers; North America and Siberia;
of western North America;
European perennial having usually violet or white spring flowers;
widely distributed genus of perennial herbs: meadow rue;
any of various herbs of the genus Thalictrum; sometimes rhizomatous or tuberous perennials found in damp shady places and meadows or stream banks; have lacy foliage and clouds of small purple or yellow flowers;
small genus of perennial herbs: false bugbane;
tall perennial of the eastern United States having large basal leaves and white summer flowers;
perennial herbs of north temperate regions: globeflowers;
any of several plants of the genus Trollius having globose yellow flowers;
small family of chiefly tropical shrubs and trees of genera Drimys and Pseudowintera; sometimes included in Magnoliaceae;
shrubs and trees of southern hemisphere having aromatic foliage;
South American evergreen tree yielding winter's bark and a light soft wood similar to basswood;
evergreen shrubs or small trees of Australia and New Zealand;
evergreen shrub or small tree whose foliage is conspicuously blotched with red and yellow and having small black fruits;
coextensive with the family Myricaceae;
constituting the order Myricales;
deciduous aromatic shrubs or small trees;
bog shrub of north temperate zone having bitter-tasting fragrant leaves;
any shrub or small tree of the genus Myrica with aromatic foliage and small wax-coated berries;
evergreen aromatic shrubby tree of southeastern United States having small hard berries thickly coated with white wax used for candles;
deciduous aromatic shrub of eastern North America with grey-green wax-coated berries;
a fragrant green wax obtained from the wax myrtle and used in making candles;
one species: sweet fern;
deciduous shrub of eastern North America with sweet scented fernlike leaves and tiny white flowers;
coextensive with the genus Leitneria; commonly isolated in a distinct order;
one species: corkwood;
very small deciduous dioecious tree or shrub of damp habitats in southeastern United States having extremely light wood;
tufted herbs resembling grasses: rushes;
grasslike plants growing in wet places and having cylindrical often hollow stems;
