type genus of the Juncaceae; perennial tufted glabrous marsh plants of temperate regions: rushes;
tall rush with soft erect or arching stems found in Eurasia, Australia, New Zealand, and common in North America;
rush of Australia;
low-growing annual rush of damp low-lying ground; nearly cosmopolitan;
tall rush of temperate regions;
rush of the Pacific coast of North America;
tufted wiry rush of wide distribution;
a family of plants;
a genus of plants;
any of various trees or shrubs having mottled or striped wood;
handsomely striped or mottled wood of the zebrawood tree; used especially for cabinetwork;
mostly tropical climbing shrubs or small trees; closely related to Leguminosae;
large genus of tropical trees and shrubs; type genus of the Connaraceae;
tropical American and east African tree with strikingly marked hardwood used in cabinetwork;
a large family of trees, shrubs, vines, and herbs bearing bean pods; divided for convenience into the subfamilies Caesalpiniaceae; Mimosaceae; Papilionaceae;
an erect or climbing bean or pea plant of the family Leguminosae;
the fruit or seed of any of various bean or pea plants consisting of a case that splits along both sides when ripe and having the seeds attach to one side of the case;
a genus of plants with pods that ripen underground (see peanut);
widely cultivated American plant cultivated in tropical and warm regions; showy yellow flowers on stalks that bend over to the soil so that seed pods ripen underground;
underground pod of the peanut vine;
genus of prickly shrubs and small trees of the Caribbean region; source of a durable hardwood;
West Indian tree yielding a fine grade of green ebony;
wood of the granadilla tree used for making musical instruments especially clarinets;
a genus of Centrolobium;
Brazilian tree with handsomely marked wood;
tropical American trees: tonka beans;
tall tropical South American tree having pulpy egg-shaped pods of fragrant black almond-shaped seeds used for flavoring;
fragrant black nutlike seeds of the tonka bean tree; used in perfumes and medicines and as a substitute for vanilla;
genus of tropical American timber trees;
West Indian locust tree having pinnate leaves and panicles of large white or purplish flowers; yields very hard tough wood;
resin from the courbaril tree;
(Old World herbs) the sweet clovers;
erect annual or biennial plant grown extensively especially for hay and soil improvement;
biennial plant; valuable honey plant;
biennial yellow-flowered Eurasian plant having aromatic leaves used as carminative or flavoring agent; widely cultivated especially as green manure or cover crop;
a genus of Australian herbs and subshrubs: darling peas;
either of two Australian plants of the genus Swainsona that are poisonous to sheep;
erect or trailing perennial of eastern Australia having axillary racemes of blue to purple or red flowers;
shrubby perennial of southern Australia having downy or woolly stems and undersides of leaves and racemes of red to pink flowers;
any leguminous plant having leaves divided into three leaflets;
a plant of the genus Trifolium;
European mountain clover with fragrant usually pink flowers;
clover native to Ireland with yellowish flowers; often considered the true or original shamrock;
southern European annual with spiky heads of crimson flower; extensively cultivated in United States for forage;
erect to decumbent short-lived perennial having red-purple to pink flowers; the most commonly grown forage clover;
clover of western United States;
creeping European clover having white to pink flowers and bright green leaves; naturalized in United States; widely grown for forage;
family of spiny woody plants (usually shrubs or small trees) whose leaves mimic animals in sensitivity to touch; commonly included in the family Leguminosae;
alternative name used in some classification systems for the family Mimosaceae;
genus of spiny woody shrubs or trees; named for their apparent imitation of animal sensitivity to light and heat and movement;
any of various tropical shrubs or trees of the genus Mimosa having usually yellow flowers and compound leaves;
semi-climbing prickly evergreen shrub of tropical America having compound leaves sensitive to light and touch;
prostrate or semi-erect subshrub of tropical America, and Australia; heavily armed with recurved thorns and having sensitive soft grey-green leaflets that fold and droop at night or when touched or cooled;
large genus of shrubs and trees and some woody vines of Central and South America, Africa, Australia and Polynesia: wattle; mimosa;
any of various spiny trees or shrubs of the genus Acacia;
source of a wood mentioned frequently in the Bible; probably a species of genus Acacia;
wood of the shittah tree used to make the ark of the Hebrew Tabernacle;
any of various Australasian trees yielding slender poles suitable for wattle;
Australian tree that yields tanning materials;
scrubby Australian acacia having extremely foul-smelling blossoms;
East Indian spiny tree having twice-pinnate leaves and yellow flowers followed by flat pods; source of black catechu;
extract of the heartwood of Acacia catechu used for dyeing and tanning and preserving fishnets and sails; formerly used medicinally;
evergreen Australasian tree having white or silvery bark and young leaves and yellow flowers;
tropical American thorny shrub or small tree; fragrant yellow flowers used in making perfumery;
tall Australian acacia yielding highly valued black timber;
shrubby Australian tree having clusters of fragrant golden yellow flowers; widely cultivated as an ornamental;
African tree supposed to mark healthful regions;
small genus of trees of tropical Asia and Pacific areas;
East Indian tree with racemes of yellow-white flowers; cultivated as an ornamental;
large genus of unarmed trees and shrubs of Old World tropics;
any of numerous trees of the genus Albizia;
attractive domed or flat-topped Asiatic tree having bipinnate leaves and flowers with long silky stamens;
large spreading Old World tree having large leaves and globose clusters of greenish-yellow flowers and long seed pods that clatter in the wind;
large ornamental tropical American tree with bipinnate leaves and globose clusters of flowers with crimson stamens and seed pods that are eaten by cattle;
2 species of tropical American shrubs or trees;
Brazilian shrub having twice-pinnate leaves and small spicate flowers followed by flat or irregularly torulose pods; sometimes placed in genus Piptadenia;
genus of pinnate-leaved shrubs and small trees of tropical and subtropical North and South America and India and West Africa;
any of various shrubs and small trees valued for their fine foliage and attractive spreading habit and clustered white to deep pink or red flowers;
small genus of tropical American timber trees closely allied to genus Albizia;
tropical South American tree having a wide-spreading crown of bipinnate leaves and coiled ear-shaped fruits; grown for shade and ornament as well as valuable timber;
genus of tropical trees or shrubs;
any tree or shrub of the genus Inga having pinnate leaves and showy usually white flowers; cultivated as ornamentals;
ornamental evergreen tree with masses of white flowers; tropical and subtropical America;
tropical tree of Central America and West Indies and Puerto Rico having spikes of white flowers; used as shade for coffee plantations;
small genus of tropical evergreen trees or shrubs having pods like those of the acacia;
low scrubby tree of tropical and subtropical North America having white flowers tinged with yellow resembling mimosa and long flattened pods;
small genus of tropical American trees and shrubs with pinnate leaves and flat straight pods;
a tree of the West Indies and Florida and Mexico; resembles tamarind and has long flat pods;
West Indian tree yielding a hard dark brown wood resembling mahogany in texture and value;
the wood of the sabicu which resembles mahogany;
genus of tropical Old World trees: nitta trees;
any of several Old World tropical trees of the genus Parkia having heads of red or yellow flowers followed by pods usually containing edible seeds and pulp;
tall evergreen rain forest tree with wide-spreading crown having yellow-white flowers; grown as an ornamental in parks and large gardens;
tropical American trees and shrubs; often placed in other genera;
thorny shrubs and trees of tropical and subtropical America and Asia;
common thorny tropical American tree having terminal racemes of yellow flowers followed by sickle-shaped or circinate edible pods and yielding good timber and a yellow dye and mucilaginous gum;
erect shrub with small if any spines having racemes of white to yellow flowers followed by curved pointed pods and black shiny seeds; West Indies and Florida;
genus of tropical or subtropical branching shrubs or trees: mesquite;
any of several small spiny trees or shrubs of the genus Prosopis having small flowers in axillary cylindrical spikes followed by large pods rich in sugar;
thorny deep-rooted drought-resistant shrub native to southwestern United States and Mexico bearing pods rich in sugar and important as livestock feed; tends to form extensive thickets;
