a genus of Soleidae;
popular pale brown food flatfish of the Pacific coast of North America;
a genus of Soleidae;
a common flatfish of the Pacific coast of North America;
a genus of Soleidae;
useless as food; in coastal streams from Maine to Texas and Panama;
skin that is very thick (as an elephant or rhinoceros);
part of an insect's body that bears the wings and legs;
the anterior part of an insect's thorax; bears the first pair of legs;
one of a series of similar body segments into which some animals are divided longitudinally;
a fabric woven from goat hair and camel hair;
a loose sleeveless outer garment made from aba cloth; worn by Arabs;
a calculator that performs arithmetic functions by manually sliding counters on rods or in grooves;
a tablet placed horizontally on top of the capital of a column as an aid in supporting the architrave;
a ship abandoned on the high seas;
the battery used to heat the filaments of a vacuum tube;
a line of defense consisting of a barrier of felled or live trees with branches (sharpened or with barbed wire entwined) pointed toward the enemy;
a building where animals are butchered;
(Arabic) a loose black robe from head to toe; traditionally worn by Muslim women;
a condenser having 2 or 3 lenses with wide aperture for use in microscopes;
a monastery ruled by an abbot;
a convent ruled by an abbess;
a church associated with a monastery or convent;
a surveying instrument consisting of a spirit level and a sighting tube; used to measure the angle of inclination of a line from the observer to the target;
a drug (or other chemical agent) that causes abortion;
an abortion-inducing drug (trade name RU 486) developed in France; when taken during the first five weeks of pregnancy it blocks the action of progesterone so that the uterus sloughs off the embryo;
a tool or machine used for wearing down or smoothing or polishing;
a primitive stone artifact (usually made of sandstone) used as an abrader;
a New York school of painting characterized by freely created abstractions; the first important school of American painting to develop independently of European styles;
an abstract painting;
an abstract genre of art; artistic content depends on internal form rather than pictorial representation;
a masonry support that touches and directly receives thrust or pressure of an arch or bridge;
an arch supported by an abutment;
a costume worn on formal occasions by the faculty or students of a university or college;
a gown worn by academics or judges;
a learned establishment for the advancement of knowledge;
a particularly potent variety of marijuana;
a valve that regulates the supply of fuel to the engine;
a scientific instrument that increases the kinetic energy of charged particles;
a pedal that controls the throttle valve; he stepped on the gas;
an instrument for measuring the acceleration of aircraft or rockets;
a way of entering or leaving; he took a wrong turn on the access to the bridge;
(computer science) the operation of reading or writing stored information;
a supplementary component that improves capability;
clothing that is worn or carried, but not part of your main clothing;
a short road giving access to an expressway; in Britain they call an access road a slip road;
a lens implant containing a hinge that allows for both near and far vision (thus mimicking the natural lens of a young person);
living quarters provided for public convenience; overnight accommodations are available;
(nautical) a portable ladder hung over the side of a vessel to give access to small boats alongside;
a portable box-shaped free-reed instrument; the reeds are made to vibrate by air from the bellows controlled by the player;
(computer science) a register that has a built-in adder that adds an input number to the contents of the register;
one of four playing cards in a deck having a single pip on its face;
an oral beta blocker (trade name Sectral) used in treating hypertension;
an antihypertensive drug that blocks the formation of angiotensin II in the kidney, leading to relaxation of the arteries; promotes the excretion of salt and water by inhibiting the activity of the angiotensin converting enzyme; also used to treat congestive heart failure;
the ace in the club suit;
the ace in the diamond suit;
the ace in the heart suit;
the ace in the spade suit; sometimes taken as a portent of death;
an analgesic for mild pain but not for inflammation; also used as an antipyretic;(Datril,Tylenol,Panadol,Phenaphen,Tempra,andAnacinIIIaretrademarksofbrandsofacetaminophentablets);
a white crystalline compound used as an analgesic and also as an antipyretic;
a disk coated with cellulose acetate;
a fabric made from fibers of cellulose acetate;
a white crystalline compound used as an analgesic and also as an antipyretic;
a compound lens system that forms an image free from chromatic aberration;
street name for lysergic acid diethylamide;
a small vacuum tube; used at high frequencies;
a remedy for hearing loss or deafness;
a delay line based on the time of propagation of sound waves;
a device for amplifying or transmitting sound;
sound is not amplified by electrical means;
a modem that converts electrical signals to telephone tones and back again;
a storage device consisting of acoustic delay lines;
the citadel in ancient Greek towns;
a synthetic fabric;
used especially by artists;
trade name for a drug containing an antihistamine and a decongestant; used to treat upper respiratory conditions and minor allergies;
an instrument for measuring the intensity of electromagnetic radiation (usually by the photochemical effect);
any of various red antibiotics isolated from soil bacteria;
the operating part that transmits power to a mechanism; the piano had a very stiff action;
a type of LCD screen used for some portable computers; there is a separate circuit for each pixel;
a placebo used in experimental tests of a drug that has noticeable side effects; an active placebo mimics the side effects of the experimental drug;
a mechanism that puts something into automatic action;
an oral antiviral drug (trade name Zovirax) used to treat genital herpes; does not cure the disease but relieves the symptoms;
street names for methylenedioxymethamphetamine;
device that enables something to be used in a way different from that for which it was intended or makes different pieces of apparatus compatible;
a machine that adds numbers;
a calculator that performs simple arithmetic functions;
a component that is added to something to improve it; the addition of a bathroom was a major improvement; the addition of cinnamon improved the flavor;
something added to enhance food or gasoline or paint or medicine;
a printer that automatically prints addresses on letters for mailing;
bandage consisting of a medical dressing of plain absorbent gauze held in place by a plastic or fabric tape coated with adhesive;
tape coated with adhesive;
a nearly horizontal passage from the surface into a mine;
a hotel room that shares a wall with another hotel room;
can be changed to different settings;
an additive that enhances the effectiveness of medical treatment;
an additional ingredient that is added by mixing with the base; the growing medium should be equal parts of sand and loam with an admixture of peat moss and cow manure; a large intermixture of sand;
sun-dried brick; used in hot dry climates;
a decoration of color or interest that is added to relieve plainness;
drug that has the effects of epinephrine;
