small tadpole-shaped cold-water fishes with pelvic fins forming a sucker; related to lumpfish;
poachers;
small slender fish (to 8 inches) with body covered by bony plates; chiefly of deeper northern Pacific waters;
type genus of the Agonidae;
northern Atlantic sea poacher;
alligatorfishes;
small very elongate sea poachers;
greenlings;
food fish of the northern Pacific;
type genus of the Hexagrammidae;
common food and sport fish of western coast of North America;
a genus of Hexagrammidae;
greenling with whitish body marked with black bands;
scorpaenoid flatheads;
food fish of the Indonesian region of the Pacific; resembles gurnards;
in some classifications restricted to the gurnards and subdivided into the subfamilies Triglinae (true sea robins) and Peristediinae (armored sea robins);
bottom-dwelling coastal fishes with spiny armored heads and fingerlike pectoral fins used for crawling along the sea bottom;
type genus of the Triglidae;
a kind of gurnard;
American gurnard; mostly found in bays and estuaries;
in some classifications considered a subfamily of Triglidae comprising searobins having ordinary scales and no barbels (true searobins);
a genus of Triglidae;
large searobin; found from Nova Scotia to Florida;
in some classifications considered a subfamily of Triglidae comprising the armored searobins;
in some classifications the type genus of the subfamily Peristediinae: armored sea robins;
sea robins having bony scutes on the body and barbels on the chin; found mostly on the continental slope;
flying gurnards;
a genus of Dactylopteridae;
tropical fish with huge fanlike pectoral fins for underwater gliding; unrelated to searobins;
boxfishes; filefishes; globefishes; ocean sunfishes; triggerfishes; puffers;
tropical marine fishes having the teeth fused into a beak and thick skin covered with bony plates or spines;
triggerfishes;
any of numerous compressed deep-bodied tropical fishes with sandpapery skin and erectile spines in the first dorsal fin;
type genus of the Balistidae;
tropical Atlantic fish;
filefishes;
narrow flattened warm-water fishes with leathery skin and a long file-like dorsal spine;
type genus of the Monocanthidae;
any of several brightly colored tropical filefishes;
boxfishes;
any of numerous small tropical fishes having body and head encased in bony plates;
a genus of Ostraciidae;
trunkfish having hornlike spines over the eyes;
puffers;
any of numerous marine fishes whose elongated spiny body can inflate itself with water or air to form a globe; several species contain a potent nerve poison; closely related to spiny puffers;
spiny puffers;
puffers having rigid or erectile spines;
type genus of the Diodontidae;
spines become erect when the body is inflated; worldwide in warm waters;
similar to but smaller than porcupinefish;
burrfishes;
any of several fishes having rigid flattened spines;
ocean sunfishes;
type genus of the Molidae;
among the largest bony fish; pelagic fish having an oval compressed body with high dorsal and anal fins and caudal fin reduced to a rudder-like lobe; worldwide in warm waters;
caudal fin has a central projection;
flatfishes: halibut; sole; flounder; plaice; turbot; tonguefishes;
any of several families of fishes having flattened bodies that swim along the sea floor on one side of the body with both eyes on the upper side;
any of various European and non-European marine flatfish;
righteye flounders;
flounders with both eyes on the right side of the head;
type genus of the Pleuronectidae;
large European food fish;
a genus of Pleuronectidae;
important food fish of Europe;
a genus of Pleuronectidae; righteye flounders having a humped nose and small scales; the underside is often brightly colored;
American flounder having a yellowish tail;
a genus of Pleuronectidae;
important American food fish in the winter;
a genus of Pleuronectidae;
European flatfish highly valued as food;
a genus of Pleuronectidae;
large American food fish;
marine food fish of the northern Atlantic or northern Pacific; the largest flatfish and one of the largest teleost fishes;
halibuts;
largest United States flatfish;
a righteye flounder found in the Pacific;
a family of fish of the order Heterosomata;
flatfishes with both eyes on the left side of the head;
a genus of Bothidae;
flounder of southern United States;
flounder of eastern coast of North America;
a genus of Bothidae;
flounder found from North Carolina to Florida and the eastern Gulf of Mexico;
a genus of Bothidae;
a lefteye flounder found in coastal waters from New England to Brazil;
a whiff found in waters from the Bahamas and northern Gulf of Mexico to Brazil;
small food fishes of the Pacific coast of North America;
a genus of Bothidae;
very thin translucent flounder of the Atlantic coast of North America;
European food fish;
a genus of Bothidae;
a large brownish European flatfish;
tonguefishes;
left-eyed marine flatfish whose tail tapers to a point; of little commercial value;
soles;
right-eyed flatfish; many are valued as food; most common in warm seas especially European;
type genus of the Soleidae;
highly valued as food;
small European sole;
