make angry; The news angered him;
anger or take offense; She bridled at his suggestion to elope;
cause to become violent or angry; Riots combusted Pakistan after the U.S. air attacks on Afghanistan;
cause to be annoyed; His behavior really miffed me;
irritate or vex; It galls me that we lost the suit;
make furious;
become angry; He angers easily;
get very angry; her indifference to his amorous advances really steamed the young man;
get very angry; He will raise the roof when he hears this;
make mad; His behavior is maddening;
drive up the wall; go on someone's nerves;
cause to go crazy; cause to lose one's mind;
cause annoyance in; disturb, especially by minor irritations; Mosquitoes buzzing in my ear really bothers me; It irritates me that she never closes the door after she leaves;
feel extreme irritation or anger; He was chafing at her suggestion that he stay at home while she went on a vacation;
cause to be annoyed, irritated, or resentful;
trouble or vex; ruffle somebody's composure;
cause annoyance in;
cause to feel resentment or indignation; Her tactless remark offended me;
annoy continually or chronically; He is known to harry his staff when he is overworked; This man harasses his female co-workers;
cause to lose one's composure;
cause to be nervous or upset;
discompose; This play is going to ruffle some people; She has a way of ruffling feathers among her colleagues;
cause to feel embarrassment; The constant attention of the young man confused her;
fill with anxiety, dread, dismay, or confusion; After the terrorist attack, people look consternated;
cause to be confused emotionally;
make confused or perplexed or puzzled;
make nervous or agitated; The mere thought of her bothered him and made his heart beat faster;
draw someone's attention away from something; The thief distracted the bystanders; He deflected his competitors;
be flustered; behave in a confused manner;
cause to be embarrassed; cause to feel self-conscious;
cause to be ashamed;
look with disfavor on; The republic soon discountenanced its few friends;
cause emotional anguish or make miserable; It pains me to see my children not being taught well in school;
cause deep emotional pain and grief to somebody; The young man broke the girl's heart when he told her was going to marry her best friend;
hurt the feelings of; She hurt me when she did not include me among her guests; This remark really bruised my ego;
deeply hurt the feelings of; distress; his lacerating remarks;
cause an emotional pain, as if by stinging; His remark stung her;
worry unnecessarily or excessively; don't fuss too much over the grandchildren--they are quite big now;
raise scruples; He lied and did not even scruple about it;
suffer agony or anguish;
cause to agonize;
experience (emotional) pain; Every time her husband gets drunk, she suffers;
suffer great pains or distress;
suffer the loss of a person through death or removal; She lost her husband in the war; The couple that wanted to adopt the child lost her when the biological parents claimed her;
be mad, angry, or furious;
get very angry and fly into a rage; The professor combusted when the student didn't know the answer to a very elementary question; Spam makes me go ballistic;
put into a rage; make violently angry;
feel intense anger; Rage against the dying of the light!;
be in a state of uncontrolled anger;
feel sudden intense sensation or emotion; he was thrilled by the speed and the roar of the engine;
feel remorse for; feel sorry for; be contrite about;
turn away from sin or do penitence;
feel sad about the loss or absence of;
feel sadness; She is mourning her dead child;
observe the customs of mourning after the death of a loved one;
feel grief;
cause to feel sorrow; his behavior grieves his mother;
cause great unhappiness for; distress; she was afflicted by the death of her parents;
oppress or trouble greatly;
cause mental pain to; The news of her child's illness distressed the mother;
cause to feel distressed or worried; She was besieged by so many problems that she got discouraged;
test the limits of; You are trying my patience!;
stretch to the limits; rack one's brains;
give pain or trouble to; I've been sorely tried by these students;
fail to meet the hopes or expectations of; Her boyfriend let her down when he did not propose marriage;
disappoint, prove undependable to; abandon, forsake; His sense of smell failed him this time; His strength finally failed him; His children failed him in the crisis;
fail to meet (expectations or standards) ;
make ineffective or powerless; The teachers were hamstrung by the overly rigid schedules;
cause to feel shame; hurt the pride of; He humiliated his colleague by criticising him in front of the boss;
humiliate or depress completely; She was crushed by his refusal of her invitation; The death of her son smashed her;
reduce in worth or character, usually verbally; She tends to put down younger women colleagues; His critics took him down after the lecture;
make inconspicuous; efface oneself;
lower in grade or rank or force somebody into an undignified situation; She reduced her niece to a servant;
prove to be of unsound mind or demonstrate someone's incompetence; nobody is legally allowed to stultify himself;
deprive of human qualities; Life in poverty has dehumanized them;
make more humane; The mayor tried to humanize life in the big city;
cause to be unpretentious; This experience will humble him;
hold within limits and control; subdue one's appetites; mortify the flesh;
practice self-denial of one's body and appetites;
express grief verbally; we lamented the death of the child;
give verbal or other expression to one's feelings;
torment emotionally or mentally;
treat cruelly; The children tormented the stuttering teacher;
annoy persistently; The children teased the boy because of his stammer;
to arouse hope, desire, or curiosity without satisfying them; The advertisement is intended to tease the customers; She has a way of teasing men with her flirtatious behavior;
control (others or oneself) or influence skillfully, usually to one's advantage; She manipulates her boss; She is a very controlling mother and doesn't let her children grow up; The teacher knew how to keep the class in line; she keeps in line;
show and train; The prize-winning poodle was handled by Mrs. Priscilla Prescott;
gain favor with somebody by deliberate efforts;
ingratiate oneself to; often with insincere behavior; She is playing up to the chairman;
be excited or anxious about;
become excited about; He warmed to the idea of a trip to Antarctica;
be apathetic, gloomy, or dazed;
be in a huff; be silent or sullen;
feel or suffer from the lack of; He misses his mother;
have a desire for something or someone who is not present; She ached for a cigarette; I am pining for my lover;
recognize with gratitude; be grateful for;
prepare (oneself) for something unpleasant or difficult;
get ready for something difficult or unpleasant;
gain courage;
attract; cause to be enamored; She captured all the men's hearts;
