feel envious towards; admire enviously;
envy without restraint;
feel admiration for;
regard with contempt; the new neighbor looks down on us because our house is very modest;
have a strong sexual desire for; he is lusting after his secretary;
desire strongly or persistently;
have a liking, fondness, or taste (for) ;
get pleasure from; I love cooking;
feel proud of; She took great pride in her sons;
lose one's emotional or mental composure; She fell apart when her only child died;
feel strong emotion, especially anger or passion; She was burning with anger; He was burning to try out his new skies;
feel indifferent towards; She died to worldly things and eventually entered a monastery;
be elated; He was flying high during the summer months;
experience a feeling of well-being or happiness, as from good health or an intense emotion; She was beaming with joy; Her face radiated with happiness;
be exuberant or high-spirited; Make the people's hearts glow;
cause to feel enthusiasm;
cause to be enthusiastic; Her playing brought down the house;
make less hostile; win over; Her charm disarmed the prosecution lawyer completely;
put into a bad mood or into bad humour; The employees were disgruntled by their bad working conditions;
excite suddenly and intensely; The news electrified us;
frighten or scare, and often provoke into a violent action; The noise spooked the horse;
be preoccupied with something; She is obsessing over her weight;
be uncertain about; think about without fully understanding or being able to decide; We puzzled over her sudden departure;
move so as to change position, perform a nontranslational motion; He moved his hand slightly to the right;
take position in the rear, as in a military formation or in the line of scrimmage in football; The defender dropped back behind his teammate;
fall or drop suddenly, usually to evade some danger; The soldiers hit the dirt when they heard gunfire;
slip or fall out of place, as of body parts; prolapsed rectum;
dash violently or with great speed or impetuosity; She plunged at it eagerly;
move gently or carefully; He eased himself into the chair;
move with a whishing sound; The car whished past her;
remain in place; hold still; remain fixed or immobile; Traffic stood still when the funeral procession passed by;
stop moving or become immobilized; When he saw the police car he froze;
be unable to move further; The car bogged down in the sand;
cause to get stuck as if in a mire; The mud mired our cart;
move due to the pull of gravitation; The stars gravitate towards each other;
change location; move, travel, or proceed, also metaphorically; How fast does your new car go?; We travelled from Rome to Naples by bus; The policemen went from door to door looking for the suspect; The soldiers moved towards the city in an attempt to take it before night fell; news travelled fast;
move lightly, as if suspended; The dancer floated across the stage;
move data into and out of core rather than performing useful computation; The system is thrashing again!;
move (a piece of a program) into memory, in computer science;
go to or towards; a liquid seeks its own level;
move with a whining sound; The bullets were whining past us;
be dispersed or disseminated; Rumors and accusations are flying;
move like a floating object; The moon rode high in the night sky;
cover a certain distance; She came a long way;
move like a ghost; The masked men ghosted across the moonlit yard;
displace oneself; go from one location to another;
fly over; The plane passed over Damascus;
travel in an airplane; she is flying to Cincinnati tonight; Are we driving or flying?;
travel on an overnight flight; The candidate red-eyed from California to the East Coast the night before the election to give a last stump speech;
travel by means of an aircraft, bus, etc.; She hopped a train to Chicago; He hopped rides all over the country;
ride or float on an inflated tube; We tubed down the river on a hot summer day;
undergo transportation as in a vehicle; We travelled North on Rte. 508;
direct one's course or way; wend your way through the crowds;
cause to sheer; She sheered her car around the obstacle;
steer a vehicle to the side of the road; The car pulled over when the ambulance approached at high speed;
travel or traverse (a distance) ; This car does 150 miles per hour; We did 6 miles on our hike every day;
navigate in space;
move quickly or suddenly; He flew about the place;
leave the house to go somewhere; We never went out when our children were small;
leave behind; the students deserted the campus after the end of exam period;
travel by raft in water; Raft the Colorado River;
travel or go by means of a certain kind of transportation, or a certain route; He takes the bus to work; She takes Route 1 to Newark;
move around; move from place to place; How does she get around without a car?;
make a trip for pleasure;
go on a pleasure trip;
move, travel, or proceed toward some place; He repaired to his cabin in the woods;
go to certain places as for sightseeing; Did you ever visit Paris?;
visit famous or interesting sights;
come to see in an official or professional capacity; The governor visited the prison; The grant administrator visited the laboratory;
visit again; We revisited Rome after 25 years;
be a regular or frequent visitor to a certain place; She haunts the ballet;
sail or travel about for pleasure, relaxation, or sightseeing; We were cruising in the Caribbean;
travel at a moderate speed; Please keep your seat belt fastened while the plane is reaching cruising altitude;
cruise in slow or routine flights;
make a tour of a certain place; We toured the Provence this summer;
travel all over the world for pleasure and sightseeing;
give theatrical performances while traveling from town to town;
undertake a journey or trip;
ride in or travel with a sledge; the antarctic expedition sledged along the coastline; The children sledged all day by the lake;
travel on water propelled by wind or by other means; The QE2 will sail to Southampton tomorrow;
traverse or travel on (a body of water) ; We sailed the Atlantic; He sailed the Pacific all alone;
travel upon or across; travel the oceans;
make a long and difficult journey; They trekked towards the North Pole with sleds and skis;
journey on foot, especially in the mountains; We spent the summer trekking in the foothills of the Himalayas;
travel by ship;
ride over, along, or through; Ride the freeways of California;
travel over (an area of land or sea) in an aircraft; Lindbergh was the first to fly the Atlantic;
cause to fly or float; fly a kite;
fly a kite; Kids were kiting in the park; They kited the Red Dragon model;
be stationary;
move in order to make room for someone for something; The park gave way to a supermarket; Move over,he told the crowd;
move away from a place into another direction; Go away before I start to cry; The train departs at noon;
leave; informal or rude; shove off!; The children shoved along; Blow now!;
move toward, travel toward something or somebody or approach something or somebody; He came singing down the road; Come with me to the Casbah; come down here!; come out of the closet!; come into the room;
come near in time; Winter is approaching; approaching old age;
grow late or (of time) elapse; It is getting on midnight--let's all go to bed!;
approach while driving; The truck entered the driveway and drove up towards the house;
cause to move or shift into a new position or place, both in a concrete and in an abstract sense; Move those boxes into the corner, please; I'm moving my money to another bank; The director moved more responsibilities onto his new assistant;
move in an agitated manner; His fingers worked with tension;
move text to the previous line; in printing;
