the part played by a person in bringing about a result; I am proud of my contribution in advancing the project; they all did their share of the work;
the part you are expected to play; he held up his end;
the attempt to achieve equal rights or status; she worked for women's liberation;
a futile or unprofitable endeavor;
an aggressive attempt to compel acquiescence by the concentration or manipulation of power; she laughed at this sexual power play and walked away;
an attempt to acquire or gain something;
informal words for any attempt or effort; he gave it his best shot; he took a stab at forecasting;
an attempt to score in a game;
an effortful attempt to attain a goal;
an energetic attempt to achieve something; getting through the crowd was a real struggle; he fought a battle for recognition;
any struggle between two skillful opponents (individuals or groups);
an unceremonious and disorganized struggle;
acquisition of a company by purchasing a controlling percentage of its stock;
an acquisition based on analysis of the benefits of consolidation in anticipation of increased earning power;
a change by sale or merger in the controlling interest of a corporation;
resistance to or defense against a hostile takeover;
an attempt to take control of a corporation;
an offer to buy shares in order to take over the company;
a takeover bid where the acquirer offers to pay more for the shares needed to gain control than for the remaining shares;
a takeover bid where the acquirer offers to buy any and all shares outstanding;
a takeover that is resisted by the management of the target company;
a takeover that is welcomed by the management of the target company;
the act of testing something; in the experimental trials the amount of carbon was measured separately; he called each flip of the coin a new trial;
a quantitative or qualitative test of a substance (especially an ore or a drug) to determine its components; frequently used to test for the presence or concentration of infectious agents or antibodies etc.;
an assay that relies on an enzymatic conversion reaction and is used to detect the presence of specific substances (such as enzymes or viruses or antibodies or bacteria);
an assay that shows specific antigens in tissues by the use of markers that are either fluorescent dyes or enzymes (such as horseradish peroxidase);
a rigorously controlled test of a new drug or a new invasive medical device on human subjects; in the United States it is conducted under the direction of the FDA before being made available for general clinical use;
a clinical trial on a few persons to determine the safety of a new drug or invasive medical device; for drugs, dosage or toxicity limits should be obtained;
a clinical trial on more persons than in phase I; intended to evaluate the efficacy of a treatment for the condition it is intended to treat; possible side effects are monitored;
a large clinical trial of a treatment or drug that in phase I and phase II has been shown to be efficacious with tolerable side effects; after successful conclusion of these clinical trials it will receive formal approval from the FDA;
sometimes the FDA approves a drug for general use but requires the manufacturer to continue to monitor its effects; during this phase the drug may be tried on slightly different patient populations than those studied in earlier trials;
a test procedure in which the identity of those receiving the intervention is concealed from both the administrators and the subjects until after the test is completed; designed to reduce or eliminate bias in the results;
a laboratory test of a new drug or a new invasive medical device on animal subjects; conducted to gather evidence justifying a clinical trial;
the act of undergoing testing; he survived the great test of battle; candidates must compete in a trial of skill;
a test of the suitability of a performer;
a filmed audition of an actor or actress;
a test of young hunting dogs to determine their skill in pointing and retrieving;
putting clothes on to see whether they fit;
a compulsory annual test of older motor vehicles for safety and exhaust fumes;
activity planned as a test or trial; they funded a pilot project in six states;
dull or routine preliminary work preparing for an undertaking;
work paid for at a rate per unit of time;
any piece of work that is undertaken or attempted; he prepared for great undertakings;
an assignment to write something;
a wild and exciting undertaking (not necessarily lawful);
an undertaking that you have been assigned to do (as by an instructor);
a project of personal concern to someone; this project is his baby;
a purposeful or industrious undertaking (especially one that requires effort or boldness); he had doubts about the whole enterprise;
productive work performed voluntarily without material reward or compensation;
any long and arduous undertaking;
anything that requires little thought;
a task to be dealt with; securing adequate funding is a time-consuming proposition;
a formidable task or requirement; finishing in time was a tall order but we did it;
any venturesome undertaking especially one with an uncertain outcome;
the pastime of exploring caves;
a series of actions advancing a principle or tending toward a particular end; he supported populist campaigns; they worked in the cause of world peace; the team was ready for a drive toward the pennant; the movement to end slavery; contributed to the war effort;
an organized program of advertisements;
a campaign against entering or continuing a war;
a campaign of flattery and friendliness (by a company, politician, etc.) to become more popular and gain support;
a movement advocating greater protection of the interests of consumers;
the campaign of a candidate to be elected;
a campaign in which the candidate makes speeches but does not travel; William McKinley's dignified front-porch campaign won him the presidency in 1896; her approach was the opposite of a passive front-porch campaign;
the activities involved in political campaigning (especially speech making);
a campaign to raise money for some cause;
the movement aimed at equal rights for women;
the movement aimed at liberating homosexuals from legal or social or economic oppression;
a defeated cause or a cause for which defeat is inevitable;
a campaign aimed to correct abuses or malpractices; the reforms he proposed were too radical for the politicians;
a concerted campaign to end something that is injurious; the war on poverty; the war against crime;
political or religious or social reform movement or agitation consisting chiefly of young people;
the organized dissemination of derogatory rumors designed to discredit a candidate;
campaigning for something by making political speeches (stump speeches);
an advertising campaign intended to promote sales;
an advertising campaign intended to improve public relations;
a venture off the beaten path; a sally into the wide world beyond his home;
the act of helping or improving yourself without relying on anyone else;
a venture undertaken without regard to possible loss or injury; he saw the rewards but not the risks of crime; there was a danger he would do the wrong thing;
a risk involving danger; you take a chance when you let her drive;
a risky and uncertain venture; getting admitted to the college of your choice has become a crapshoot;
a risky act or venture;
a venture that involves great risk but promises great rewards;
increasing the size of a bet (as in poker); I'll see your raise and double it;
raising the stakes in a card game by a factor of 2; I decided his double was a bluff;
the activity of managing or exerting control over something; the control of the mob by the police was admirable;
activity of controlling a crowd;
an effort to minimize or curtail damage or loss;
the act of being put under federal control;
control from ground stations of airplanes in flight by means of messages transmitted to the pilot electronically;
(engineering) the art or technique of trying to control rivers with dams etc in order to minimize the occurrence of floods;
any instance of aggressive extension of authority;
the act of controlling or directing according to rule; fiscal regulations are in the hands of politicians;
the act of freeing from regulation (especially from governmental regulations);
an official lowering of a nation's currency; a decrease in the value of a country's currency relative to that of foreign countries;
efforts to regulate or control sales of guns;
a system of economic regulation: wages and interest are tied to the cost-of-living index in order to reduce the effects of inflation;
an accounting procedure or system designed to promote efficiency or assure the implementation of a policy or safeguard assets or avoid fraud and error etc.;
an internal control performed by one or more managers;
maintenance of standards of quality of manufactured goods;
a statistical procedure for accepting or rejecting a batch of merchandise or documents; involves determining the maximum number of defects discovered in a sample before the entire batch is rejected;
the act of bringing to uniformity; making regular;
