a failure to be active as a consequence of lack of initiative or ambition;
a disposition to feel that anything less than perfect is unacceptable; his perfectionism seemed excessive to his students;
a disposition to allow freedom of choice and behavior;
a disposition to tolerate or accept people or situations; all people should practice toleration and live together in peace;
an acceptance of yourself as you are, warts and all;
a disposition to yield to the wishes of someone; too much indulgence spoils a child;
a disposition to be lenient in judging others; softness is not something permitted of good leaders;
too much permissiveness;
a lack of permissiveness or indulgence and a tendency to confine behavior within certain specified limits;
uncompromising resolution;
strictness and austerity in conduct and religion;
excessive sternness; severity of character; the harshness of his punishment was inhuman; the rigors of boot camp;
a cheerful, obliging disposition;
a disposition to kindness and compassion; the victor's grace in treating the vanquished;
good-natured tolerance of delay or incompetence;
being without worry or concern;
a disposition to laugh;
a temperamental disposition to be agreeable;
a disposition or tendency to yield to the will of others;
a disagreeable, irritable, or malevolent disposition;
a disposition to be ill-tempered;
a fussy and eccentric disposition;
a sullen moody resentful disposition;
a disposition to exhibit uncontrolled anger; his temper was well known to all his employees;
a dislike of anything that causes delay;
impatience with annoyances; his intolerance of interruptions;
a nature given to nagging or scolding;
the quality of being given to complaining;
harshness of manner;
an ill-tempered and offensive disposition;
a rough and bitter manner;
a natural disposition to be hostile;
a natural disposition to fight;
an inclination to be quarrelsome and contentious;
obstreperous and defiant aggressiveness;
a quarrelsome disposition to engage in or carry on lawsuits; charges of litigiousness and widespread perjury;
cheerful compliance; he expressed his willingness to help;
prompt willingness; readiness to continue discussions; they showed no eagerness to spread the gospel; they disliked his zeal in demonstrating his superiority; he tried to explain his forwardness in battle;
willingness or readiness to receive (especially impressions or ideas); he was testing the government's receptiveness to reform; this receptiveness is the key feature in oestral behavior, enabling natural mating to occur; their receptivity to the proposal;
undivided commitment or unreserved enthusiasm;
the trait of being unwilling; his unwillingness to cooperate vetoed every proposal I made; in spite of our warnings he plowed ahead with the involuntariness of an automaton;
a certain degree of unwillingness; a reluctance to commit himself; his hesitancy revealed his basic indisposition; after some hesitation he agreed;
(psychiatry) an unwillingness to bring repressed feelings into conscious awareness;
the trait of being serious; a lack of solemnity is not necessarily a lack of seriousness- Robert Rice;
the trait of sincere and steadfast fixity of purpose; a man of energy and commitment;
the commitment of something other than money (time, energy, or effort) to a project with the expectation of some worthwhile result; this job calls for the investment of some hard thinking; he made an emotional investment in the work;
a manner that is serious and solemn;
a trait of dignified seriousness;
dull and pompous gravity;
the trait of being frivolous; not serious or sensible;
an impulsive scatterbrained manner;
the trait of being lighthearted and frivolous;
a manner lacking seriousness;
inappropriate levity; her mood changed and she was all lightness and joy;
the trait of merry joking;
a disposition to find (or make) causes for amusement; her playfulness surprised me; he was fun to be with;
playful humor;
inappropriate playfulness;
lively high-spirited playfulness;
the trait of behaving like an imp;
the trait of appreciating (and being able to express) the humorous; she didn't appreciate my humor; you can't survive in the army without a sense of humor;
the trait of being communicative;
the trait of being blunt and outspoken;
good-natured frankness;
a friendly open trait of a talkative person;
the quality of being facile in speech and writing;
the quality of being wordy and talkative;
rambling talkativeness (especially in the aged);
the trait of being uncommunicative;
a refusal to speak when expected; his silence about my contribution was surprising;
the trait of keeping things secret;
secrecy; mum's the word;
the trait of being uncommunicative; not volunteering anything more than necessary;
the tendency to associate with others and to form social groups; mammals as a class are not strong on sociality;
the relative tendency or disposition to be sociable or associate with one's fellows;
a jovial nature;
suitability to be a companion;
the quality of affording easy familiarity and sociability;
the quality of being gregarious--having a dislike of being alone;
characterized by an attitude of ready accessibility (especially about one's actions or purposes); without concealment; not secretive;
a friendly disposition;
a disposition to be friendly and approachable (easy to talk to);
having a disposition characterized by warmth and friendliness;
affability to your inferiors and temporary disregard for differences of position or rank; the queen's condescension was intended to make us feel comfortable;
close or warm friendship; the absence of fences created a mysterious intimacy in which no one knew privacy;
the attribute of being easy to meet or deal with;
a congenial disposition;
a cordial disposition;
a disposition to be friendly and helpful to neighbors;
having a disposition that welcomes guests and is fond of entertaining;
geniality, as through the effects of alcohol or marijuana;
a mild reasonableness; when he learned who I was he became all sweetness and light;
an unsociable disposition; avoiding friendship or companionship;
a disposition to be distant and unsympathetic in manner;
a disposition to be unapproachable; unfriendly and inaccessible;
characterized by a lack of openness (especially about one's actions or purposes);
a disposition to be sly and stealthy and to do things surreptitiously;
an unfriendly disposition;
a hostile (very unfriendly) disposition; he could not conceal his hostility;
a disposition to behave aggressively;
