a coffin along with its stand; we followed the bier to the graveyard;
an interior door;
eyeglasses having two focal lengths, one for near vision and the other for far vision;
clock in the clock tower of the Houses of Parliament, London;
a reliable and deadly 15,000-pound fragmentation bomb that explodes just above ground with a large radius; the largest conventional bomb in existence; used in Afghanistan;
the large display board at the New York Stock Exchange that reports on stocks traded on the exchange;
a child's tight-fitting cap; often ties under the chin;
street names for heroin;
the middle part of a slack rope (as distinguished from its ends);
a small and delicately worked piece;
a woman's very brief bathing suit;
small and tight-fitting underpants; worn by women;
where the sides of the vessel curve in to form the bottom;
either of two lengthwise fins attached along the outside of a ship's bilge; reduces rolling;
a pump to remove bilgewater;
in a vessel with two hulls, an enclosed area between the frames at each side;
(nautical) a well where seepage drains to be pumped away;
a brim that projects to the front to shade the eyes; he pulled down the bill of his cap and trudged ahead;
a long-handled saw with a curved blade; he used a bill to prune branches off of the tree;
large outdoor signboard;
lodging for military personnel (especially in a private home);
ball used in playing billiards;
a device for keeping the score in a game of billiards;
a room in which billiards is played;
a strip consisting of two metals that bends with a rise in temperature;
a container; usually has a lid;
something used to tie or bind;
holds loose papers or magazines;
a machine that cuts grain and binds it in sheaves;
a workshop where books are bound;
the protective covering on the front, back, and spine of a book; the book had a leather binding;
strip sewn over or along an edge for reinforcement or decoration;
a plastic bag used to line a trash or garbage bin;
a nonmagnetic housing for a ship's compass (usually in front of the helm);
an optical instrument designed for simultaneous use by both eyes;
a light microscope adapted to the use of both eyes;
a microchip that uses tiny strands of DNA to latch onto and quickly recognize thousands of genes at a time; intended for use in a biological environment;
a loose one-piece garment worn to protect the wearer against dangerous biological or chemical agents;
a laboratory for biological research;
a kind of early movie projector;
a South African movie theater;
any weapon usable in biological warfare; they feared use of the smallpox virus as a bioweapon;
old fashioned airplane; has two wings one above the other;
an optical device for obtaining interference fringes;
a switch consisting of a twig or a bundle of twigs from a birch tree; used to hit people as punishment; my father never spared the birch;
a canoe made with the bark of a birch tree;
an ornamental basin (usually in a garden) for birds to bathe in;
a cage in which a bird can be kept;
a catcher's mask with a strong wire face;
a device for imitating a birdcall;
an outdoor device that supplies food for wild birds;
a shelter for birds;
small lead shot for shotgun shells;
a stiff cap with ridges across the crown; worn by Roman Catholic clergy;
(chess) a piece that can be moved diagonally over unoccupied squares of the same color;
a small informal restaurant; serves wine;
the cutting part of a drill; usually pointed and threaded and is replaceable in a brace or bitstock or drill press; he looked around for the right size bit;
piece of metal held in horse's mouth by reins and used to control the horse while riding; the horse was not accustomed to a bit;
the part of a key that enters a lock and lifts the tumblers;
a removable dental appliance that is worn in the palate for diagnostic or therapeutic purposes;
a dental X-ray film that can be held in place by the teeth during radiography;
an image represented as a two dimensional array of brightness values for pixels;
(nautical) the inboard end of a line or cable especially the end that is wound around a bitt;
the upper end of a bitt;
a pin through the bitthead to keep the mooring lines from slipping off;
a protective coating of asphalt and filter used on structural metals that are exposed to weathering;
black clothing (worn as a sign of mourning); the widow wore black;
(board games) the darker pieces;
a black-and-white photograph or slide;
sheet of slate; for writing with chalk;
an eraser that removes chalk marks from blackboard;
equipment that records information about the performance of an aircraft during flight;
the makeup (usually burnt cork) used by a performer in order to imitate a Negro;
a flag usually bearing a white skull and crossbones on a black background; indicates a pirate ship;
a dungeon (20 feet square) in a fort in Calcutta where as many as 146 English prisoners were held overnight by Siraj-ud-daula; the next morning only 23 were still alive;
a piece of metal covered by leather with a flexible handle; used for hitting people;
a black bow tie worn with a dinner jacket;
a simple hitch used for temporarily attaching a line to a hook;
a wash that colors a surface black;
a mixture of calomel and limewater that is used on syphilitic sores;
a bag that fills with air;
the flat part of a tool or weapon that (usually) has a cutting edge;
flat surface that rotates and pushes against air or water;
the part of the skate that slides on the ice;
a cartridge containing an explosive charge but no bullet;
a piece of material ready to be made into something;
bedding that keeps a person warm in bed; he pulled the covers over his head and went to sleep;
a layer of lead surrounding the highly reactive core of a nuclear reactor;
a strong reinforcing stitch for edges of blanket and other thick material; similar to buttonhole stitch;
a stone in a castle in Ireland that is said to impart skill in flattery to anyone who kisses it;
a furnace for smelting of iron from iron oxide ores; combustion is intensified by a blast of air;
a small tube filled with detonating substances; used to detonate high explosives;
mixture of guncotton with nitroglycerin;
lightweight single-breasted jacket; often striped in the colors of a club or school;
an outdoor grandstand without a roof; patrons are exposed to the sun as linens are when they are bleached;
an electrically powered mixer with whirling blades that mix or chop or liquefy foods;
a small nonrigid airship used for observation or as a barrage balloon;
a protective covering that keeps things out or hinders sight; they had just moved in and had not put up blinds yet;
a hiding place sometimes used by hunters (especially duck hunters); he waited impatiently in the blind;
a street with only one way in or out;
