that which is perceived or known or inferred to have its own distinct existence (living or nonliving);
an entity that has physical existence;
a general concept formed by extracting common features from specific examples;
a separate and self-contained entity;
a tangible and visible entity; an entity that can cast a shadow; it was full of rackets, balls and other objects;
an assemblage of parts that is regarded as a single entity; how big is that part compared to the whole?; the team is a unit;
a whole (a thing or person) of the same kind or category as another; lard was also used, though its congener, butter, was more frequently employed; the American shopkeeper differs from his European congener;
a living (or once living) entity;
a living thing that has (or can develop) the ability to act or function independently;
organisms (plants and animals) that live at or near the bottom of a sea;
a plant or animal that is atypically small;
an organism that depends on complex organic substances for nutrition;
an organism (plant or animal) from which younger ones are obtained;
living things collectively; the oceans are teeming with life;
a discrete unit of living matter;
(biology) the basic structural and functional unit of all organisms; they may exist as independent units of life (as in monads) or may form colonies or tissues as in higher plants and animals;
any entity that produces an effect or is responsible for events or results;
a human being; there was too much for one person to do;
a living organism characterized by voluntary movement;
(botany) a living organism lacking the power of locomotion;
indigenous plants and animals;
an object occurring naturally; not made by man;
the real physical matter of which a person or thing consists; DNA is the substance of our genes;
a particular kind or species of matter with uniform properties; shigella is one of the most toxic substances known to man;
that which has mass and occupies space; physicists study both the nature of matter and the forces which govern it;
any substance that can be metabolized by an animal to give energy and build tissue;
any substance (such as a chemical element or inorganic compound) that can be taken in by a green plant and used in organic synthesis;
a man-made object taken as a whole;
one of a class of artifacts; an article of clothing;
a feature of the mental life of a living organism;
the psychological result of perception and learning and reasoning;
the psychological feature that arouses an organism to action toward a desired goal; the reason for the action; that which gives purpose and direction to behavior; we did not understand his motivation; he acted with the best of motives;
an abstraction belonging to or characteristic of an entity;
the way something is with respect to its main attributes; the current state of knowledge; his state of health; in a weak financial state;
the experiencing of affective and emotional states; she had a feeling of euphoria; he had terrible feelings of guilt; I disliked him and the feeling was mutual;
a point or extent in space;
the spatial arrangement of something as distinct from its substance; geometry is the mathematical science of shape;
the continuum of experience in which events pass from the future through the present to the past;
the unlimited expanse in which everything is located; they tested his ability to locate objects in space; the boundless regions of the infinite;
physical space independent of what occupies it;
(physics) an ideal space in which the coordinate dimensions represent the variables that are required to describe a system or substance; a multidimensional phase space;
something that happens at a given place and time;
a sustained phenomenon or one marked by gradual changes through a series of states; events now in process; the process of calcification begins later for boys than for girls;
something that people do or cause to happen;
any number of entities (members) considered as a unit;
an abstraction belonging to or characteristic of two entities or parts together;
anything owned or possessed;
a relation between living organisms (especially between people);
something that is communicated by or to or between people or groups;
how much there is or how many there are of something that you can quantify;
any state or process known through the senses rather than by intuition or reasoning;
an action; how could you do such a thing?;
a kind act;
cosmetic surgery of the abdomen to remove wrinkles and tighten the skin over the stomach;
the act of terminating a project or procedure before it is completed; I wasted a year of my life working on an abort; he sent a short message requesting an abort due to extreme winds in the area;
the action of accomplishing something;
a festivity in ancient Greece at which competitors contended for prizes;
the action of alienating; the action of causing to become unfriendly; his behavior alienated the other students;
the action of putting something into operation; the application of maximum thrust; massage has far-reaching medical applications; the application of indexes to tables of data;
an initial accomplishment that opens the way for further developments; the town became a beachhead in the campaign to ban smoking outdoors; they are presently attempting to gain a foothold in the Russian market;
an easy accomplishment; winning the tournament was a cakewalk for him; invading Iraq won't be a cakewalk;
a notable achievement; he performed a great feat; the book was her finest effort;
an outstanding achievement;
an achievement demonstrating great skill or mastery;
used in the phrase to your creditin order to indicate an achievement deserving praise; she already had several performances to her credit;
something done (usually as opposed to something said); there were stories of murders and other unnatural actions;
things done;
a mode of action; if you persist in that course you will surely fail; once a nation is embarked on a course of action it becomes extremely difficult for any retraction to take place;
(figurative) a course of action that is unproductive and offers no hope of improvement; all the clues led the police into blind alleys; so far every road that we've been down has turned out to be a blind alley;
a course of action (following a given idea) that will lead to conflict if it continues unabated;
a mutual or reciprocal action; interacting;
reciprocal action and reaction;
close interaction; they kept in daily contact; they claimed that they had been in contact with extraterrestrial beings;
contact with something dangerous or undesirable; I had a brush with danger on my way to work; he tried to avoid any brushes with the police;
contact that occurs when two people look directly at each other; a teacher should make eye contact with the students;
the action of fetching;
contact established between applicants and prospective employees; the agency provided placement services;
mutual interaction; the activity of reciprocating or exchanging (especially information);
mutual exchange of commercial or other privileges;
interchange between different cultures or different ways of thinking that is mutually productive and beneficial; the cross-fertilization of science and the creative arts;
social or verbal interchange(usuallyfollowedbywith);
(usually plural) mutual dealings or connections among persons or groups; international relations;
the action of taking part in a game or sport or other recreation;
the act using a sword (or other weapon) vigorously and skillfully;
work of little or no value done merely to look busy;
the playing of a game of tenpins or duckpins etc;
the act of acquiring something; I envied his talent for acquiring; he's much more interested in the getting than in the giving;
the act of causing something to happen;
the act of delivering a child;
the act of departing;
brave and heroic feats;
the act of discovering something;
the act or means of getting rid of something;
(baseball) a successful stroke in an athletic contest (especially in baseball); he came all the way around on Williams' hit;
the act of implementing (providing a practical means for accomplishing something); carrying into effect;
the act of coming (or going) out; becoming apparent;
the act of making equal or uniform;
the act of digging something out of the ground (especially a corpse) where it has been buried;
(Judaism) a good deed performed out of religious duty;
the act of propelling;
