the act of referring (as forwarding an applicant for employment or referring a matter to an appropriate agency);
(law) the act of remitting (especially the referral of a law case to another court);
the transmission of a letter; the postmark indicates the time of mailing;
propelling something on wheels;
the act of firing a projectile; his shooting was slow but accurate;
the act of shooting at targets; they hold a shoot every weekend during the summer;
a return shot; a retaliatory shot;
the act of discharging a gun;
the discharge of a firearm as signal or as a salute in military ceremonies; two runners started before the gun; a twenty gun salute;
preparation for the delivery of shellfire on a target;
the act of shooting a gun; the gunfire endangered innocent bystanders; they retreated in the face of withering enemy fire;
gunfire directed along the length rather than the breadth of a formation;
a gunshot from a concealed location;
a shot aimed at a person's head;
the sport of shooting at clay pigeons that are hurled upward in such a way as to simulate the flight of a bird;
shooting artillery shells;
a fight involving shooting small arms with the intent to kill or frighten;
a shot taken at an easy or casual target (as by a pothunter);
the act of touching physically; her fingers came in contact with the light switch;
the act of rubbing or wiping; he gave the hood a quick rub;
the act of scuffing (scraping or dragging the feet);
a light touch or stroke;
the act of contacting one thing with another; repeated hitting raised a large bruise; after three misses she finally got a hit;
the action of bruising; the bruise resulted from a contusion;
the act of colliding with something; his crash through the window; the fullback's smash into the defensive line;
a sharp collision produced by striking or dashing against something;
(baseball) the batter's attempt to get on base;
(baseball) handling the ball while playing in the field;
(baseball) playing the position of catcher on a baseball team;
playing golf; he goes south every winter for the golfing;
(baseball) playing the position of pitcher on a baseball team;
(baseball) an advance to first base by a batter who receives four balls; he worked the pitcher for a base on balls;
the supreme effort one can make; they did their best;
the weakest effort or poorest achievement one is capable of; it was the worst he had ever done on a test;
(baseball) a ball struck with the bat so that it stays between the lines (the foul lines) that define the width of the playing field;
(baseball) a ball struck with the bat so that it does not stay between the lines (the foul lines) that define the width of the playing field;
a glancing contact with the ball off the edge of the cricket bat;
(baseball) the act of hitting a baseball lightly without swinging the bat;
(baseball) a hit that flies up in the air;
a very long fly ball;
a short high fly ball;
(baseball) a hit that travels along the ground;
a grounder that bounces high in the air;
a grounder that rolls along the infield;
(baseball) a failure by a batter or runner to reach a base safely in baseball; you only get 3 outs per inning;
a putout of a base runner who is required to run; the putout is accomplished by holding the ball while touching the base to which the runner must advance before the runner reaches that base; the shortstop got the runner at second on a force;
an out resulting from a fielding play (not a strikeout); the first baseman made 15 putouts;
an out resulting from the batter getting three strikes;
a strikeout resulting from the batter swinging at and missing the ball for the third strike;
a play made on a ground ball in which the fielder chooses to put out an advancing runner instead of the batter;
(baseball) an out that advances the base runners;
a sacrifice made by hitting a long fly ball;
(baseball) the successful act of striking a baseball in such a way that the batter reaches base safely;
a batted or served ball that skims along close to the ground;
(soccer) the act of hitting the ball with your head;
(baseball) a hit that flies straight out from the batter; the batter hit a liner to the shortstop;
a very hard hit ball;
a single resulting from a line drive;
a double resulting from a line drive;
a triple resulting from a line drive;
(baseball) hitting a baseball so that it drops suddenly;
a base hit on which the batter scores a run;
a home run with no runners on base;
a base hit on which the batter stops safely at first base;
a base hit on which the batter stops safely at second base; he hit a double to deep centerfield;
a base hit at which the batter stops safely at third base;
a backhanded blow;
a sharp slanting blow; he gave me a clip on the ear;
the act of hitting vigorously; he gave the table a whack;
a hard blow with a flat object;
the act of smacking something; a blow delivered with an open hand;
a very powerful blow with the fist;
a blow that knocks the opponent off his feet;
a blow that renders the opponent unconscious;
a knockout declared by the referee who judges one boxer unable to continue;
a sharp blow;
a slap with the flat of the hand;
a quick blow delivered with a whip or whiplike object; the whip raised a red welt;
(boxing) a blow with the fist; I gave him a clout on his nose;
a blow with the hand (usually on the ear); I gave him a good box on the ear;
the act of touching someone suddenly with your finger or elbow; she gave me a sharp dig in the ribs;
a return punch (especially by a boxer);
a hard punch that renders the opponent unable to continue boxing;
a short swinging punch delivered from the side with the elbow bent;
a quick short straight punch;
a short chopping blow to the back of the neck;
an unexpected punch;
a hook delivered with an exaggerated swing;
the act of delivering a blow with the foot; he gave the ball a powerful kick; the team's kicking was excellent;
(association football) a kick by the defending side after the attacking side sends the ball over the goal-line ;
(rugby) an attempt to kick a goal;
(football) a kick in which the football is dropped from the hands and kicked before it touches the ground; the punt traveled 50 yards; punting is an important part of the game;
(sports) a kick in which the ball is placed on the ground before kicking;
(soccer) a place kick that is allowed for a foul or infringement by the other team;
a free kick from the corner awarded to the other side when a player has sent the ball behind his own goal line;
(football) kicking (as for a field goal) in which the football is dropped and kicked as it touches the ground;
a light glancing touch; there was a brief kiss of their hands in passing;
the act of caressing with the lips (or an instance thereof);
the act of contacting something with your hand; peonies can be blighted by the laying on of a finger;
an enthusiastic kiss;
