an unexpected hit; that movie was the sleeper of the summer;
a conspicuous success; that song was his first hit and marked the beginning of his career; that new Broadway show is a real smasher; the party went with a bang;
something that exactly succeeds in achieving its goal; the new advertising campaign was a bell ringer; scored a bull's eye; hit the mark; the president's speech was a home run;
the act of raising someone to the nobility;
success in mastering something difficult; the conquest of space;
a brilliant and notable success;
complete success; they passed inspection with flying colors;
success in satisfying a test or requirement; his future depended on his passing that test; he got a pass in introductory chemistry;
recognition by a college or university that a course of studies has been successfully completed; typically measured in semester hours;
a unit of academic credit; one hour a week for an academic semester;
an act that does not achieve its intended goal;
an unexpected omission; he resented my failure to return his call; the mechanic's failure to check the brakes;
an act that fails; his failure to pass the test;
failure to reach a minimum required performance; his failing the course led to his disqualification; he got two flunks on his report;
complete failure; all my efforts led to naught;
an unexcused absence from class; he was punished for taking too many cuts in his math class;
loss due to not showing up; he lost the game by default;
the act of losing someone or something; everyone expected him to win so his loss was a shock;
the act of surrendering (usually under agreed conditions); they were protected until the capitulation of the fort;
an act of hindering someone's plans or efforts;
an improbable and unexpected victory; the biggest upset since David beat Goliath;
a failure to maintain a higher state;
habitual relapse into crime;
an act (or failure to act) that disappoints someone;
a failure to perform some promised act or obligation;
a failure to face some difficulty squarely;
a breach of a legal duty; failure to do something that is required in a contract;
a breach of contract committed prior to the time of required performance;
a breach of due care;
a failure of the seller's guarantee of good title;
failure to keep a promise (of marriage);
violation (either through fraud or negligence) by a trustee of a duty that equity requires of him;
larceny after trust rather than after unlawful taking;
a breach that occurs when an item is deficient according to the terms of a warranty;
the act of deviating from a vertical position;
a breach serious enough to destroy the value of the contract and to give a basis for an action for breach of contract;
the act of motivating; providing incentive;
a breach that does not destroy the value of the contract but can give rise to a claim for damages;
a wrong action attributable to bad judgment or ignorance or inattention; he made a bad mistake; she was quick to point out my errors; I could understand his English in spite of his grammatical faults;
(tennis) two successive faults in serving resulting in the loss of the point;
a fault that occurs when the server in tennis fails to keep both feet behind the baseline;
the momentary juggling of a batted or thrown baseball; the second baseman made a bobble but still had time to throw the runner out;
(baseball) a failure of a defensive player to make an out when normal play would have sufficed;
an act that brings discredit to the person who does it; he made a huge blot on his copybook;
a mistake that results from taking one thing to be another; he changed his name in order to avoid confusion with the notorious outlaw;
the mistake of incurring liability or blame;
a mistake in calculating;
a miscalculation that recoils on its maker;
(mathematics) a miscalculation that results from rounding off numbers to a convenient number of decimals; the error in the calculation was attributable to rounding; taxes are rounded off to the nearest dollar but the rounding error is surprisingly small;
(mathematics) a miscalculation that results from cutting off a numerical calculation before it is finished;
the mistake of misrepresenting the facts;
a minor inadvertent mistake usually observed in speech or writing or in small accidents or memory lapses etc.;
a slip-up that (according to Sigmund Freud) results from the operation of unconscious wishes or conflicts and can reveal unconscious processes in normal healthy individuals;
(sport) the mistake of occupying an illegal position on the playing field (in football, soccer, ice hockey, field hockey, etc.);
a mistake resulting from inattention;
a mistake resulting from neglect;
an embarrassing mistake;
an acronym often used by soldiers in World War II: situation normal all fucked up;
a blunder that makes you look ridiculous;usedinthephrasemakeaspectacleofyourself;
something badly botched or muddled;
a serious and ludicrous blunder; he made a bad bull of the assignment;
(sports) dropping the ball;
a blunder (especially an actor's forgetting the lines);
a socially awkward or tactless act;
a glaring blunder;
a conspicuous mistake whose effects seem to reverberate; he dropped a clanger;
an unintentional but embarrassing blunder; he recited the whole poem without a single trip; he arranged his robes to avoid a trip-up later; confusion caused his unfortunate misstep;
a sudden drop from an upright position; he had a nasty spill on the ice;
a fall onto your buttocks;
a spill in some sport (as a fall from a bicycle or while skiing or being capsized on a surfboard);
the act of contracting or assuming or acquiring possession of something; the acquisition of wealth; the acquisition of one company by another;
the act of obtaining;
becoming infected; catching cold is sometimes unavoidable; the contracting of a serious illness can be financially catastrophic;
acquiring or coming into something (usually undesirable); incurring debts is easier than paying them;
the act of making money (and accumulating wealth);
the formal act of acquiring something (especially territory) by conquest or occupation; the French annexation of Madagascar as a colony in 1896; a protectorate has frequently been a first step to annexation;
acquisition of government money for benefits to a specific locale; keeps his hold on his constituents through unashamed pork-barreling;
the acquisition of something for payment; they closed the purchase with a handshake;
the act of purchasing back something previously sold;
buying or selling securities or commodities;
trading in bonds (usually by a broker on the floor of an exchange);
a trading technique involving large blocks of stock with trades triggered by computer programs;
sale of securities or commodity futures not owned by the seller (who hopes to buy them back later at a lower price);
the purchase of securities or commodities by a short seller to close out a short sale;
buying or selling corporate stock by a corporate officer or other insider on the basis of information that has not been made public and is supposed to remain confidential;
a put or call option for which the seller or buyer has no underlying security position;
a put or call option backed by the shares underlying the option;
the option to buy a given stock (or stock index or commodity future) at a given price before a given date;
the option to sell a given stock (or stock index or commodity future) at a given price before a given date;
the option to buy or sell a given stock (or stock index or commodity future) at a given price before a given date; consists of an equal number of put and call options;
an option granted to corporate executives if the company achieves certain financial goals;
the act of buying; buying and selling fill their days; shrewd purchasing requires considerable knowledge;
searching for or buying goods or services; went shopping for a reliable plumber; does her shopping at the mall rather than down town;
shopping at a market; does the weekly marketing at the supermarket;
buying goods to be shipped through the mail;
purchasing insurance policies for cash from terminally ill policy holders;
the act of taking something that is offered; her acceptance of the gift encouraged him; he anticipated their acceptance of his offer;
acquisition of property by descent or by will;
the act of taking possession of or power over something; his assumption of office coincided with the trouble in Cuba; the Nazi assumption of power in 1934; he acquired all the company's assets for ten million dollars and the assumption of the company's debts;
the act of assuming or taking for granted; your assumption that I would agree was unwarranted;
