(of winds) coming from the land; offshore winds;
marked by an orderly, logical, and aesthetically consistent relation of parts; a coherent argument;
perfectly consistent and coherent; the novel's seamless plot;
without logical or meaningful connection; a turgid incoherent presentation;
lacking orderly continuity; a confused set of instructions; a confused dream about the end of the world; disconnected fragments of a story; scattered thoughts;
confused and not coherent; not clearly thought out; a vague and fuzzy idea of the world of finance;
capable of collapsing or being collapsed; a collapsible boat;
capable of being folded up and stored; a foldaway bed;
having parts that slide one within another; a telescopic antenna; a telescopic drinking cup;
constructed so as to tip up or out of the way; the little tip-up seat of the taxi;
not capable of collapsing;
not telescopic;
having small chinks or crannies (especially in or between rocks or stones); a crannied wall;
without chinks or crannies;
forming a whole or aggregate;
clustered together but not coherent; an agglomerated flower head;
formed of separate units gathered into a mass or whole; aggregate expenses include expenses of all divisions combined for the entire year; the aggregated amount of indebtedness;
characterized by the principle of ownership by the state or the people of the means of production;
(furniture) easily assembled and dismantled; I bought a knockdown chest at the do-it-yourself store;
serving to distribute or allot or disperse;
capable of being distributed;
spreading by diffusion;
of qualities that are spread throughout something; ambition is immanent in human nature; we think of God as immanent in nature;
spreading or spread throughout; armed with permeative irony...he punctures affectations; the pervasive odor of garlic; an error is pervasive if it is material to more than one conclusion;
(of a word) referring singly and without exception to the members of a group; whereas each,every,either,neither,and noneare distributive or referring to a single member of a group, whichin which of the menis separative;
spreading through; suffusive purple light;
made known; especially made widely known;
called to public attention; these advertised products;
publicly announced; the royal couple's much heralded world tour;
formally made public; published accounts;
kept from public knowledge by various means;
suppressed quietly or indirectly;
(used of information or news) kept secret by using influence; hushed-up stories sometimes leak out;
subdued or overcome; the quelled rebellion; an uprising quenched almost before it started; a squelched rumor;
not (or not yet) made available for distribution or publication; someone leaked the unreleased announcement; a film that remained unreleased for years;
prepared and printed for distribution and sale; the complete published works Dickens;
not published; unpublished letters and diaries;
suitable for publication;
not suitable for publication;
made known or told about; especially presented in a formal account; his reported opinion; the reported findings;
(followed by to) as reported or stated by; according to historians;
requiring that official notification be given; a notifiable disease;
meriting report; years of research produced no reportable results;
not reported; unreported results;
(of income) required by law to be reported; reportable income;
(of income) not reportable; not required by law to be reported; very little income is unreportable;
marked by or relating to or resulting from combination;
relating to the combination and arrangement of elements in sets;
able to or tending to combine;
not involving combination;
not able to combine;
capable of igniting and burning;
capable of burning;
supporting combustion;
easily ignited;
can emit sparks or burst into flame;
capable of catching fire spontaneously or causing fires or burning readily; an incendiary agent; incendiary bombs;
not capable of igniting and burning;
impervious to damage by fire;
difficult to burn;
resistant to catching fire;
impossible to ignite;
serving to explode or characterized by explosion or sudden outburst; an explosive device; explosive gas; explosive force; explosive violence; an explosive temper;
exploding almost instantaneously;
not explosive; nonexplosive gases; a nonexplosive fuel;
set afire or burning; the lighted candles; a lighted cigarette; a lit firecracker;
lighted up by or as by fire or flame; forests set ablaze (or afire) by lightning; even the car's tires were aflame; a night aflare with fireworks; candles alight on the tables; houses on fire;
set afire; the ignited paper; a kindled fire;
not set afire or burning; the table was bare, the candles unlighted; held an unlit cigarette;
not set afire;
large and roomy (convenientis archaic in this sense); a commodious harbor; a commodious building suitable for conventions;
(of buildings and rooms) having ample space; a roomy but sparsely furnished apartment; a spacious ballroom;
uncomfortably or inconveniently small; incommodious hotel accommodations;
constricted in size; cramped quarters; trying to bring children up in cramped high-rise apartments;
providing or experiencing physical well-being or relief (comfyis informal); comfortable clothes; comfortable suburban houses; made himself comfortable in an armchair; the antihistamine made her feel more comfortable; are you comfortable?; feeling comfy now?;
enjoying or affording comforting warmth and shelter especially in a small space; a cozy nook near the fire; snug in bed; a snug little apartment;
affording comfort; soft light that was easy on the eyes;
having a feeling of home; cozy and comfortable; the homely everyday atmosphere; a homey little inn;
affording physical relief; a soothing ointment for her sunburn;
providing or experiencing physical discomfort; an uncomfortable chair; an uncomfortable day in the hot sun;
feeling physical discomfort or pain (toughis occasionally used colloquially for bad); my throat feels bad; she felt bad all over; he was feeling tough after a restless night;
without comfort; a comfortless room;
causing physical discomfort; bites of black flies are more than irritating; they can be very painful;
characterized by physical misery; a wet miserable weekend; spent a wretched night on the floor;
relating to bodily unease that causes discomfort;
uncomfortable because of possible danger or trouble; made things warm for the bookies;
free from stress or conducive to mental ease; having or affording peace of mind; was settled in a comfortable job, one for which he was well prepared; the comfortable thought that nothing could go wrong; was comfortable in his religious beliefs; she's a comfortable person to be with; she felt comfortable with her fiance's parents;
made comfortable or more comfortable in a time of distress; the news make her feel comforted;
conducive to or feeling mental discomfort; this kind of life can prove disruptive and uncomfortable; the uncomfortable truth; grew uncomfortable beneath his appraising eye; an uncomfortable way of surprising me just when I felt surest; the teacher's presence at the conference made the child very uncomfortable;
socially uncomfortable; unsure and constrained in manner; awkward and reserved at parties; ill at ease among eddies of people he didn't know; was always uneasy with strangers;
causing mental discomfort; the disquieting sounds of nearby gunfire;
not the right size or shape;
excessively and uncomfortably conscious of your appearance or behavior; self-conscious teenagers; wondered if she could ever be untidy without feeling self-conscious about it;
corresponding in size or degree or extent; pay should be commensurate with the time worked;
being of equal extent or scope or duration;
capable of being measured by a common standard; hours and minutes are commensurable;
agreeing in amount, magnitude, or degree;
not corresponding in size or degree or extent; a reward incommensurate with his effort;
not proportionate;
not having a common factor;
