a smile expressing smugness or scorn instead of pleasure;
an angry vicious expression;
a serious facial expression giving no evidence of interest or amusement;
closing one eye quickly as a signal;
the facial expression of sudden pain;
a visual presentation showing how something works; the lecture was accompanied by dramatic demonstrations; the lecturer shot off a pistol as a demonstration of the startle response;
something intended to communicate a particular impression; made a display of strength; a show of impatience; a good show of looking interested;
a meeting of the eyes between two people that expresses meaningful nonverbal communication; it was a mere glance, but the eye contact was enough to tell her that he was desperate to leave;
a display of force or power; speak softly but carry a big stick;
cheap or pretentious or vain display;
expression without words; tears are an expression of grief; the pulse is a reflection of the heart's condition;
showing by example;
a visible symbol representing an abstract idea;
a symbol for love in the form of a cherubic naked boy with wings and a bow and arrow;
the symbol of the Democratic Party; introduced in cartoons by Thomas Nast in 1874;
an emblem of peace;
an emblem representing power; the Roman eagle;
the symbol of the Republican Party; introduced in cartoons by Thomas Nast in 1874;
bundle of rods containing an axe with the blade protruding; in ancient Rome it was a symbol of a magistrate's power; in modern Italy it is a symbol of fascism;
an emblem flown as a symbol of nationality;
the emblem on the flag of the Soviet Union;
the emblem of socialist revolution;
a six-pointed star formed from two equilateral triangles; an emblem symbolizing Judaism;
an emblem (a small piece of plastic or cloth or metal) that signifies your status (rank or membership or affiliation etc.); they checked everyone's badge before letting them in;
a badge award to Boy Scouts in recognition of special projects;
a badge worn to show official position;
figure of a lamb; emblematic of Christ;
the emblem of Canada;
an emblem indicating that a taxicab is registered;
an emblem (an eagle with wings and legs spread) on the obverse of the Great Seal of the United States;
the official emblem of the Nazi Party and the Third Reich; a cross with the arms bent at right angles in a clockwise direction;
the cloak as a symbol of authority; place the mantle of authority on younger shoulders;
the Crown (or the reigning monarch) as the symbol of the power and authority of a monarchy; the colonies revolted against the Crown;
the symbol of the power of the British monarchy; members of the British Commonwealth owe allegiance to the British Crown;
an insignia used by the medical profession; modeled after the staff of Hermes;
an insignia worn on a military uniform;
something worn on the shoulder of a military uniform as an emblem of a division etc.;
an insignia worn to indicate years of service;
evidence of identity; something that identifies a person or thing;
evidence proving that you are who you say you are; evidence establishing that you are among the group of people already known to the system; recognition by the system leads to acceptance; a system for positive identification can prevent the use of a single identity by several people;
evidence proving that you are not who you say you are not; evidence establishing that you are not among a group of people already known to the system; recognition by the system leads to rejection; a system for negative identification can prevent the use of multiple identities by a single person;
identification of criminals and terrorist by means of videotapes of their faces; facial profiling is a new form of airport security;
a generic term for any identifying characteristic; that tax bill had the senator's fingerprints all over it;
using speech characteristics or dialect to identify a speaker's race or religion or social class;
recording a person's behavior and analyzing psychological characteristics in order to predict or assess their ability in a certain sphere or to identify a particular group of people;
a card that identifies the bearer as an alien with permanent resident status in the United States; he was surprised to discover that green cards are no longer green;
a card or badge used to identify the bearer; you had to show your ID in order to get in;
a number you choose and use to gain access to various accounts;
the projection of an image from a film onto a screen;
exhibiting openly in public view; a display of courage;
(psychiatry) the display of previously inhibited emotions (often in actions rather than words); considered to be healthy and therapeutic;
an impressive display; it was a bewildering array of books; his tools were in an orderly array on the basement wall;
the display of a motion picture;
a screening for a select audience in advance of release for the general public;
an advertisement consisting of short scenes from a motion picture that will appear in the near future;
a preview to test audience reactions;
anything that is seen; he was a familiar sight on the television; they went to Paris to see the sights;
something or someone seen (especially a notable or unusual sight); the tragic spectacle of cripples trying to escape;
a gaudy outward display;
a swaggering show of courage;
extravagant and conspicuous behavior intended to attract attention to yourself;
ostentatious display of elegance; they put on the ritz;
an ostentatious display (of effort or extravagance etc.);
an ostentatious and inappropriate display of learning;
the act of waving;
a display of ornamental speech or language;
a showy gesture; she entered with a great flourish;
an ornamental embellishment in writing;
a flourish added after or under your signature (originally to protect against forgery);
the act of displaying something ostentatiously; his behavior was an outrageous flaunt;
the act of making something publicly available; presenting news or other information by broadcasting or printing it; he prepared his presentation carefully in advance;
putting on display for the first time; he attended the unveiling of the statue;
a dramatic or musical entertainment; they listened to ten different performances; the play ran for 100 performances; the frequent performances of the symphony testify to its popularity;
a short theatrical performance that is part of a longer program; he did his act three times every evening; she had a catchy little routine; it was one of the best numbers he ever did;
an act so striking or impressive that the show must be delayed until the audience quiets down;
a performance to raise money for a charitable cause;
a concert given for the benefit of some charitable cause;
a performance of music by players or singers not involving theatrical staging;
a performance of rock music;
performance by or technique of a pianist; a program of pianism;
performance of a play by a group of readers;
the first public performance of a play or movie;
performance of music or dance especially by soloists;
a performance of a musical composition or a dramatic role etc.; they heard a live rendition of three pieces by Schubert;
theatrical performance combining singing and dancing;
a performance of a play;
a theatrical performance held during the daytime (especially in the afternoon);
a lavishly produced performance; they put on a Christmas spectacular;
(music) the first public performance (as of a dramatic or musical work) anywhere in the world;
a language that is deliberately created for a specific purpose;
an artificial language related to Ido;
an artificial language intended for international use as an auxiliary language;
a simplified form of English proposed for use as an auxiliary language for international communication; devised by C. K. Ogden and I. A. Richards;
an artificial language;
an artificial language based on Esperanto and Ido;
an artificial language based as far as possible on words common to all the European languages;
an artificial language proposed as an auxiliary European language;
an artificial language proposed for use as an auxiliary international language; based on Volapuk but with a vocabulary selected on the basis of the maximum internationality of the roots;
an artificial language proposed for use as an auxiliary international language; based on words common to English and the Romance languages;
an artificial language that is a revision and simplification of Esperanto;
