nocturnal flightless bird of New Zealand having a long neck and stout legs; only surviving representative of the order Apterygiformes;
a ratite bird order: birds intermediate in characteristics between ostriches and emus: recent and extinct rheas;
a family of birds coextensive with the order Rheiformes;
type genus of the Rheidae; large tall flightless South American birds similar to but smaller than ostriches;
larger of two tall fast-running flightless birds similar to ostriches but three-toed ; found from Brazil to Patagonia;
a genus of birds of the family Rheidae;
smaller of two tall fast-running flightless birds similar to ostriches but three-toed ; found from Peru to Strait of Magellan;
huge extinct flightless birds: elephant birds;
coextensive with the order Aepyorniformes;
type genus of the Aepyornidae: elephant birds;
huge (to 9 ft.) extinct flightless bird of Madagascar;
a ratite bird order: recently extinct flightless birds of New Zealand;
moas;
type genus of the Dinornithidae: large moas;
extinct flightless bird of New Zealand;
the largest moa; about 12 feet high;
small moas;
the smallest moa; slender moa about the size of a large turkey;
a bird with feet adapted for perching (as on tree branches); this order is now generally abandoned by taxonomists;
largest order of birds comprising about half the known species; rooks; finches; sparrows; tits; warblers; robins; wrens; swallows; etc.; the four suborders are Eurylaimi and Tyranni and Menurae and Oscines or Passeres;
perching birds mostly small and living near the ground with feet having 4 toes arranged to allow for gripping the perch; most are songbirds; hatchlings are helpless;
chiefly arboreal birds especially of the order Coraciiformes;
two names for the suborder of typical songbirds;
passerine bird having specialized vocal apparatus;
any bird having a musical call;
honey eaters;
Australasian bird with tongue and bill adapted for extracting nectar;
hedge sparrow;
type genus of the Prunellidae;
small sparrow-like songbird of mountainous regions of Eurasia;
small brownish European songbird;
larks;
any of numerous predominantly Old World birds noted for their singing;
type genus of the Alaudidae: skylarks;
brown-speckled European lark noted for singing while hovering at a great height;
pipits and wagtails;
type genus of the Motacillidae: wagtails;
Old World bird having a very long tail that jerks up and down as it walks;
pipits;
a songbird that lives mainly on the ground in open country; has streaky brown plumage;
a common pipit that is brown above and white below; widely distributed in northern and central Europe and in Asia;
finches: goldfinches; bullfinches; chaffinches; siskins; canaries; cardinals; grosbeaks; crossbills; linnets; buntings;
any of numerous small songbirds with short stout bills adapted for crushing seeds;
type genus of the Fringillidae: chaffinch, brambling;
small European finch with a cheerful song;
Eurasian finch;
used in some classifications for a subgroup of finches;
in some classifications considered the type genus of a subfamily Carduelinae of the family Fringillidae: goldfinches; siskins; redpolls; linnets;
small European finch having a crimson face and yellow-and-black wings;
small Old World finch whose male has a red breast and forehead;
small yellow-and-black Eurasian finch with a sharp beak;
South American species of scarlet finch with black head and wings and tail;
small siskin-like finch with a red crown and a rosy breast and rump;
small siskin-like finch with a red crown;
in some classifications considered a subgenus of Carduelis: siskins and New World goldfinches;
American finch whose male has yellow body plumage in summer;
small finch of North American coniferous forests;
house finches and purple finches;
small finch originally of the western United States and Mexico;
North American finch having a raspberry-red head and breast and rump;
Old World finches; e.g. canaries and serins;
any of several small Old World finches;
native to the Canary Islands and Azores; popular usually yellow cage bird noted for its song;
any of various brown and yellow finches of parts of Europe;
crossbill;
finch with a bill whose tips cross when closed;
bullfinches;
common European finch mostly black and white with red throat and breast;
American finches;
small North American finch seen chiefly in winter;
common North American junco having grey plumage and eyes with dark brown irises;
sparrow-like North American finches;
a genus of Fringillidae;
common North American finch noted for its evening song;
large New World sparrows;
common North American finch with a white patch on the throat and black-and-white striped crown;
finch with black-and-white striped crown;
chipping sparrow; field sparrow; tree sparrow;
small North American finch common in urban areas;
common North American finch of brushy pasturelands;
finch common in winter in the northern U.S.;
American song sparrow and swamp sparrow;
small songbird common in North America;
North American finch of marshy area;
buntings and some New World sparrows;
any of numerous seed-eating songbirds of Europe or North America;
a genus of small North American finches including the New World buntings;
small deep blue North American bunting;
Old World buntings;
brownish Old World bunting often eaten as a delicacy;
European bunting inhabiting marshy areas;
European bunting the male being bright yellow;
common in Russia and Siberia;
snow bunting;
white Arctic bunting;
the honeycreepers;
small bright-colored tropical American songbird with a curved bill for sucking nectar;
type genus of the Coerebidae;
any of several honeycreepers;
true sparrows: Old world birds formerly considered weaverbirds;
