large fossil protozoan of the Tertiary period;
testacean rhizopods;
any of various rhizopods of the order Testacea characterized by having a shell;
soil and freshwater protozoa; cosmopolitan in distribution;
type genus of the Arcellidae;
an amoeba-like protozoan with a chitinous shell resembling an umbrella;
genus of protozoans related to ameba;
a protozoan with an ovoid shell of cemented sand grains;
class of protozoa having cilia or hairlike appendages on part or all of the surface during some part of the life cycle;
a protozoan with a microscopic appendage extending from the surface of the cell;
in some recent classifications, coextensive with the Ciliata: minute organisms found in decomposing infusions of organic matter;
any member of the subclass Infusoria;
freshwater ciliate with an oval body and long deep oral groove;
any member of the genus Paramecium;
protozoa having four membranous ciliary organelles;
relative of the paramecium; often used in genetics research;
trumpet-shaped protozoa with a ciliated spiral feeding funnel;
any of several trumpet-shaped ciliate protozoans that are members of the genus Stentor;
ciliated protozoans that have a goblet-shaped body with a retractile stalk;
any of various protozoa having a transparent goblet-shaped body with a retractile stalk;
primitive chlorophyll-containing mainly aquatic eukaryotic organisms lacking true stems and roots and leaves;
plant growing in the sea, especially marine algae;
an edible seaweed with a mild flavor;
dried seaweed especially that cast ashore;
any of various seaweeds that grow underwater in shallow beds; seagrass provides a protective environment in which young fish can develop;
growth of marine vegetation especially of the large forms such as rockweeds and kelp;
any of a group of green pigments found in photosynthetic organisms; there are four naturally occurring forms;
a blue-black plant pigment having a blue-green alcohol solution; found in all higher plants;
a dark-green plant pigment having a brilliant green alcohol solution; generally characteristic of higher plants;
the chlorophyll present in brown algae, diatoms, and flagellates;
the chlorophyll found (together with chlorophyll a) in red algae;
a substance in photosensitive bacteria that is related to but different from chlorophyll of higher plants;
water-soluble proteinaceous pigments found in red algae and cyanobacteria;
red pigment in red algae;
blue pigment in algae;
algae having chlorophyll a and usually c, and flagella of unequal lengths; terminology supersedes Chrysophyta in some classifications;
mostly freshwater eukaryotic algae having the chlorophyll masked by brown or yellow pigment; yellow-green and golden-brown algae and diatoms: Xanthophyceae, Chrysophyceae, Bacillariophyceae; some classification systems superseded or subsumed by Heterokontophyta;
algae having the pigments chlorophyll and carotene and xanthophyll;
any alga of the division Chrysophyta with its chlorophyll masked by yellow pigment;
all the yellow-green algae having flagella of unequal length;
yellow-green algae;
marine and freshwater eukaryotic algae: diatoms;
microscopic unicellular marine or freshwater colonial alga having cell walls impregnated with silica;
yellow-green algae with simple or branching filaments; comprising the single family Tribonemaceae;
simple filamentous freshwater yellow-green algae;
type genus of Tribonemaceae;
any of various algae of the genus Tribonema; algae with branching filaments that form scum in still or stagnant fresh water;
algae resembling confervae especially in having branching filaments;
brown algae; mostly marine and littoral eukaryotic algae;
coextensive with class Phaeophyceae; in some classifications subsumed in the division Heterokontophyta;
algae having the chlorophyll masked by brown and yellow pigments;
in some classifications coextensive with family Laminariaceae: marine brown algae of cold or polar seas;
large family of marine brown algae including many economically important large kelps chiefly of northern waters;
type genus of the family Laminariaceae: perennial brown kelps;
large brown seaweeds having fluted leathery fronds;
any of various kelps especially of the genus Laminaria;
any of various coarse seaweeds;
coextensive with the family Fucaceae;
in more recent classifications superseded by the order Fucales;
small family of brown algae: gulfweeds; rockweeds;
any of various algae of the family Fucaceae;
a fossilized cast or impression of algae of the order Fucales;
coarse brown seaweed growing on rocks exposed at low tide;
type genus of the family Fucaceae: cartilaginous brown algae;
any member of the genus Fucus;
brown algae seaweed with serrated edges;
a common rockweed used in preparing kelp and as manure;
brown algae distinguished by compressed or inflated branchlets along the axis;
similar to and found with black rockweed;
a genus of protoctist;
brown algae with rounded bladders forming dense floating masses in tropical Atlantic waters as in the Sargasso Sea;
free-swimming flagellate algae;
coextensive with the division Euglenophyta;
considered green algae;
type genus of the family Euglenaceae: green algae with a single flagellum;
minute single-celled green freshwater organism having a single flagella; often classed as algae;
marine and freshwater green or colorless flagellate organism;
large division of chiefly freshwater eukaryotic algae that possess chlorophyll a and b, store food as starch, and cellulose cell walls; classes Chlorophyceae, Ulvophyceae, and Charophyceae; obviously ancestral to land plants;
algae distinguished chiefly by having flagella and a clear green color, their chlorophyll being masked little if at all by other pigments;
algae that are clear green in color; often growing on wet ricks or damp wood or the surface of stagnant water;
alternative name for the class Chlorophyceae in some classifications;
an order of protoctist;
thin flat or tubular green algae;
type genus of the family Ulvaceae; green seaweed having a thallus two cells thick: sea lettuce;
seaweed with edible translucent crinkly green fronds;
chiefly freshwater green algae; solitary or colonial;
unicellular or colonial biflagellate free-swimming flagellates;
type genus of the Volvocaceae; minute pale green flagellates occurring in tiny spherical colonies; minute flagella rotate the colony about an axis;
green algae some of which are colored red by hematochrome;
type genus of the Chlamydomonadaceae; solitary doubly-flagellated plant-like algae common in fresh water and damp soil; multiply freely; often a pest around filtration plants;
pond scums; desmids;
pond scums: common freshwater algae forming green slimy masses;
type genus of the family Zygnemataceae;
free-floating freshwater green algae;
a genus of protoctist;
freshwater algae consisting of minute filaments containing spiral chlorophyll bands;
unicellular green algae that reproduce by spores;
type genus of Chlorococcales; unicellular green algae occurring singly or in a layer on soil or damp rock;
nonmotile unicellular green algae potentially important as source of high-grade protein and B-complex vitamins;
any alga of the genus Chlorella;
