cause to regain consciousness; The doctors revived the comatose man;
cause to load (an operating system) and start the initial processes; boot your computer;
cause to become alive again; raise from the dead; Slavery is already dead, and cannot be resurrected; Upraising ghosts;
return from the dead; Christ is risen!; The dead are to uprise;
form a scab; the wounds will eventually scab;
grow new skin over an injury;
get healthy again; The wound is healing slowly;
form granulating tissue; wounds and ulcers can granulate;
use up all one's strength and energy and stop working; At the end of the march, I pooped out;
do physical exercise; She works out in the gym every day;
exercise in order to prepare for an event or competition; She is training for the Olympics;
do gymnastics, roll and turn skillfully;
execute a roll, in tumbling; The gymnasts rolled and jumped;
give a workout to; Some parents exercise their infants; My personal trainer works me hard; work one's muscles; this puzzle will exercise your mind;
cause to do preliminary exercises so as to stretch the muscles; The coach warmed up the players before the game;
cause to become limber; The violist limbered her wrists before the concert;
give a healthy elasticity to; Let's tone our muscles;
extend one's body or limbs; Let's stretch for a minute--we've been sitting here for over 3 hours;
expel intestinal gases through the anus;
snuff up mucus through the nose;
expel or eject (saliva or phlegm or sputum) from the mouth; The father of the victim spat at the alleged murderer;
spit up in an explosive manner;
strike (one's toe) accidentally against an object; She stubbed her toe in the dark and now it's broken;
cause or do harm to; These pills won't harm your system;
produce saliva; We salivated when he described the great meal;
let saliva drivel from the mouth; The baby drooled;
turn red, as if in embarrassment or shame; The girl blushed when a young man whistled as she walked by;
turn pale, as if in fear;
make pale or sickly; alcohol etiolates your skin;
get a tan, from wind or sun;
get a tan from being exposed to the sun;
expose one's body to the sun;
get a sunburn by overexposure to the sun;
become systemic and spread throughout the body; this kind of infection generalizes throughout the immune system;
spread throughout the body; the cancer had metastasized and the patient could not be saved;
eliminate (a substance) ; combustion products are exhausted in the engine; the plant releases a gas;
expel (gases or odors) ;
act in a funny or teasing way;
act as or like a clown;
be conscious of a physical, mental, or emotional state; My cold is gone--I feel fine today; She felt tired after the long hike; She felt sad after her loss;
be in excellent health and spirits; he feels like a million after he got the promotion;
feel uncomfortable for lack of fresh air; The room was hot and stuffy and we were suffocating;
dress in a gown;
affect with, or as if with, jaundice;
act in a trivial or ineffective way;
injure or kill by running over, as with a vehicle;
gain (weight) ; He packed on two pounds over the summer;
rouse somebody from sleep with a call; I was called at 5 A.M. this morning;
behave in a certain way; make merry;
begin or appear to begin an action; He made as if to shake my hand;
diminish or discontinue abruptly; The patient's fever broke last night;
fracture a bone of; I broke my foot while playing hockey;
break (a bone) ; She broke her clavicle;
break (a bone) that was previously broken but mended in an abnormal way; The surgeon had to refracture her wrist;
become fractured; The tibia fractured from the blow of the iron pipe;
have grow through the gums; The baby cut a tooth;
proffer (a body part) ; She gave her hand to her little sister;
consent to engage in sexual intercourse with a man; She gave herself to many men;
treat the body or any part of it by wrapping it, as with blankets or sheets, and applying compresses to it, or stuffing it to provide cover, containment, or therapy, or to absorb blood; The nurse packed gauze in the wound; You had better pack your swollen ankle with ice;
inhale audibly through the nose; snuff coke;
exude or expel foam; the angry man was frothing at the mouth;
exude sweat or lather; this unfit horse lathers easily;
undergo a change; become different in essence; losing one's or its original nature; She changed completely as she grew older; The weather changed last night;
pass from one quality such as color to another by a slight degree; the butterfly wings shade to yellow;
vary slightly; shade the meaning;
become a gel; The solid, when heated, gelled;
become brutal or insensitive and unfeeling;
make brutal, unfeeling, or inhuman; Life in the camps had brutalized him;
convert to caramel;
convert (an image) into pixels;
be converted into caramel; The sugar caramelized;
change in nature, purpose, or function; undergo a chemical change; The substance converts to an acid;
change the nature, purpose, or function of something; convert lead into gold; convert hotels into jails; convert slaves to laborers;
convert (plant remains) into humus;
convert into a verb; many English nouns have become verbalized;
develop into a creole; pidgins often creolize;
convert into spores;
convert into the form or the style of a novel; The author novelized the historical event;
convert (metallic mercury) into a grey powder consisting of minute globules, as by shaking with chalk or fatty oil;
replace or convert into opal; opalized tree trunks;
make opalescent;
convert into sounds or pictures; receive the incoming radio signals;
convert back; Hollywood is reconverting old films;
convert into malt;
convert grain into malt;
turn into malt, become malt;
stay the same; remain in a certain state; The dress remained wet after repeated attempts to dry it; rest assured; stay alone; He remained unmoved by her tears; The bad weather continued for another week;
remain outside;
exist over a prolonged period of time; The bad weather continued for two more weeks;
keep informed; He kept up on his country's foreign policies;
maintain the same position; wait it out; Let's not make a decision--let's sit tight;
become distinct and acquire a different character;
evolve so as to lead to a new species or develop in a way most suited to the environment;
become different during development; cells differentiate;
lose specialization in form or function;
undergo mutation; cells mutate;
change venous blood into arterial blood;
undergo reversion, as in a mutation;
give certain properties to something; get someone mad; She made us look silly; He made a fool of himself at the meeting; Don't make this into a big deal; This invention will make you a millionaire; Make yourself clear;
cause to become; The shot rendered her immobile;
