make a marcel in a woman's hair;
set waves in; she asked the hairdresser to wave her hair;
make wavy with a heated goffering iron; goffer the trim of the dress;
give a permanent wave to; She perms her hair;
apply a styling gel to; she mousses her hair;
apply pomade to (hair) ;
ruffle (one's hair) by combing the ends towards the scalp, for a full effect;
care for one's external appearance; He is always well-groomed;
make oneself clean, presentable or neat; Clean up before you go to the party;
apply make-up or cosmetics to one's face to appear prettier; She makes herself up every morning;
apply a highlighter to one's cheeks or eyebrows in order to make them more prominent; highlight the area above your eyebrows;
apply lipstick to; She lipsticked her mouth;
redden by applying rouge to; she rouged her cheeks;
apply conditioner to in order to make smooth and shiny; I condition my hair after washing it;
use dental floss to clean; floss your teeth after every meal;
use shampoo on (hair) ;
apply powder to; She powdered her nose; The King wears a powdered wig;
apply talcum powder to (one's body) ;
care for (one's hand) by cutting and shaping the nails, etc.;
trim carefully and neatly; manicure fingernails;
perform the services of a barber: cut the hair and/or beard of;
care for one's feet by cutting and shaping the nails, etc.;
use special care in dressing, making-up , etc.; She dolled herself up for the night out with her friends;
dress and groom with particular care, as for a special occasion; He spruced up for the party;
apply perfume to; She perfumes herself every day;
dress or groom with elaborate care; She likes to dress when going to the opera;
dress up showily; He pranked himself out in his best clothes;
dress up in a cheap and provocative way;
put on special clothes to appear particularly appealing and attractive; She never dresses up, even when she goes to the opera; The young girls were all fancied up for the party;
dress in a certain manner; She dresses in the latest Paris fashion; he dressed up in a suit and tie;
adorn with a robe;
dress primly;
dress up garishly and tastelessly;
dress informally and casually; On Fridays, employees can underdress;
dress very carefully and in a finicky manner;
give a neat appearance to; groom the dogs; dress the horses;
take off weight;
lose weight by sweating; I sweated off 3 pounds in the sauna;
increase (one's body weight) ; She gained 20 pounds when she stopped exercising;
become round, plump, or shapely; The young woman is fleshing out;
put on clothes; we had to dress quickly; dress the patient; Can the child dress by herself?;
dress warmly; Mother bundled up the children for the long way to school;
put on or wear a hat; He was unsuitably hatted;
put on a garment in order to see whether it fits and looks nice; Try on this sweater to see how it looks;
dress in a bonnet;
have or show an appearance of; wear one's hair in a certain way;
have on one's person; He wore a red ribbon; bear a scar;
provide with clothes or put clothes on; Parents must feed and dress their child;
clothe, as if for protection from the elements; cover your head!;
put a jacket on; The men were jacketed;
put a frock on;
put a shirt on;
put a habit on;
provide or cover with a cloak;
dress too warmly; You should not overclothe the child--she will be too hot;
dress without sufficient warmth; She was underdressed for the hiking trip and suffered hypothermia;
dress with a corset;
furnish with shoes; the children were well shoed;
get undressed; please don't undress in front of everybody!; She strips in front of strangers every night for a living;
take off, as with some difficulty; He peeled off his blood-soaked shirt;
remove clothes; take off your shirt--it's very hot in here;
put clothing on one's body; What should I wear today?; He put on his best suit for the wedding; The princess donned a long blue dress; The queen assumed the stately robes; He got into his jeans;
wrap in or adorn with a scarf;
put on with ease or speed; slip into something more comfortable after work; slip on one's shoes;
take off with ease or speed; She slipped off her jacket;
cover or provide with a coat;
dress in the clothes of the other sex;
dress in a costume; We dressed up for Halloween as pumpkins;
dress like a dandy;
clothe formally; especially in ecclesiastical robes;
clothe oneself in ecclesiastical garments;
be dressed in; She was wearing yellow that day;
introduce semen into (a female) ;
render fertile and preserve by placing between layers of earth or sand; stratify seeds;
show signs of life; the fetus quickened;
make pregnant; He impregnated his wife again;
fertilize and cause to grow; the egg was impregnated;
impregnate with the virus or germ of a disease in order to render immune;
cause to undergo cross-fertilization; Mendel cross-fertilized different kinds of beans;
undergo cross-fertilization; become fertile;
fertilize by transfering pollen;
become pregnant; undergo conception; She cannot conceive; My daughter was conceived in Christmas Day;
mate successfully; of livestock;
make children; Abraham begot Isaac; Men often father children but don't recognize them;
eject semen;
have offspring or produce more individuals of a given animal or plant; The Bible tells people to procreate;
multiply sexually or asexually;
propagate asexually; The bacterial growth vegetated along;
cause to propagate, as by grafting or layering;
insert a bud for propagation;
bear fruit; the apple trees fructify;
have young (animals) or reproduce (organisms) ; pandas rarely breed in captivity; These bacteria reproduce;
breed freely and abundantly;
lay spawn; The salmon swims upstream to spawn;
spawn; oysters spat;
cause to be born; My wife had twins yesterday!;
be in confinement for childbirth;
undergo the efforts of childbirth;
give birth to twins;
give birth; used for animals; The cow dropped her calf this morning;
