a way of conceiving something; Luther had a new perception of the Bible;
a general inclusive concept;
a traditional notion that is obstinately held although it is unreasonable; he still holds to the old mumpsimus that a woman's place is in the kitchen;
an idea that preoccupies the mind and holds the attention;
preoccupation with yourself to the exclusion of everything else;
a plan or design of something that is laid out;
something (often something deceptively attractive) that catches you unawares; the exam was full of trap questions; it was all a snare and delusion;
a trap from which there is no escape;
a trap arranged on a roadway for catching speeders;
a personal view; he has an idea that we don't like him;
an opinion formed by judging something; he was reluctant to make his judgment known; she changed her mind;
a position or opinion or judgment reached after consideration; a decision unfavorable to the opposition; his conclusion took the evidence into account; satisfied with the panel's determination;
a mental determination or resolve in advance; an antecedent intention to do something; he entered the argument with a predetermination to prove me wrong;
a general concept that marks divisions or coordinations in a conceptual scheme;
a category of things distinguished by some common characteristic or quality; sculpture is a form of art; what kinds of desserts are there?;
a special type; Google represents a new breed of entrepreneurs;
a specific (often simplistic) category;
category name; it is usually discussed under the rubric of functional obesity;
a general category of things; used in the expression in the way of; they didn't have much in the way of clothing;
sort or variety; every description of book was there;
a subdivision of a particular kind of thing; what type of sculpture do you prefer?;
a particular type of thing; problems of this type are very difficult to solve; he's interested in trains and things of that nature; matters of a personal nature;
something a little different from others of the same type; an experimental version of the night fighter; a variant of the same word; an emery wheel is the modern variation of a grindstone; the boy is a younger edition of his father;
an opposite or contrasting type;
(architecture) a form of artistic expression (such as writing or painting or architecture);
architecture as a kind of art form;
a German style of architecture begun by Walter Gropius in 1918;
the style of architecture developed in the Byzantine Empire developed after the 5th century; massive domes with square bases and round arches and spires and much use of mosaics;
architecture influenced by the ancient Greeks or Romans;
the architecture of ancient Greece;
the architecture of ancient Rome;
a style of architecture developed in northern France that spread throughout Europe between the 12th and 16th centuries; characterized by slender vertical piers and counterbalancing buttresses and by vaulting and pointed arches;
a style of architecture developed in Italy and western Europe between the Roman and the Gothic styles after 1000 AD; characterized by round arches and vaults and by the substitution of piers for columns and profuse ornament and arcades;
a Romanesque style first appearing in Normandy around 950 AD and used in Britain from the Norman Conquest until the 12th century;
a Gothic style in 14th and 15th century England; characterized by vertical lines and a four-centered (Tudor) arch and fan vaulting;
a style of English-Gothic architecture popular during the Tudor period; characterized by half-timbered houses;
a style of architecture common in Spain from the 13th to 16th centuries; characterized by horseshoe-shaped arches;
a style of architecture used in Britain during the reign of Queen Victoria; characterized by massive construction and elaborate ornamentation;
a particular kind (as to appearance); this style of shoe is in demand;
(physics) the six kinds of quarks;
(physics) one of the six flavors of quark;
(physics) one of the six flavors of quark;
(physics) the characteristic of quarks that determines their role in the strong interaction; each flavor of quarks comes in three colors;
a specific kind of something; a species of molecule; a species of villainy;
a general kind of something; ignore the genus communism;
a recognizable kind; there's a new brand of hero in the movies now; what make of car is that?;
a kind of literary or artistic work;
a kind of person; We'll not see his like again; I can't tolerate people of his ilk;
a kind; what manner of man are you?;
a type of product; his car was an old model;
a kind or category; businessmen of every stripe joined in opposition to the proposal;
a similar kind; dogs, foxes, and the like, we don't want the likes of you around here;
a principle or condition that customarily governs behavior; it was his rule to take a walk before breakfast; short haircuts were the regulation;
a principle that limits the extent of something; I am willing to accept certain restrictions on my movements;
a restriction of range or scope; the problem with achievement tests is the narrowness they impose on students; the attraction of the book is precisely its narrowness of focus; frustrated by the narrowness of people's horizons;
(mathematics) a standard procedure for solving a class of mathematical problems; he determined the upper bound with Descartes' rule of signs; he gave us a general formula for attacking polynomials;
a rule that describes how other rules should be used (as in AI);
a precise rule (or set of rules) specifying how to solve some problem;
an algorithm for sorting a list;
an algorithm for removing inflectional and derivational endings in order to reduce word forms to a common stem;
a commonsense rule (or set of rules) intended to increase the probability of solving some problem;
a heuristic for solving problems; you try to look at the problem from many angles instead of tackling it head-on;
(mathematics) an expression such that each term is generated by repeating a particular mathematical operation;
a rule or principle that provides guidance to appropriate behavior;
a rule that when literal compliance is impossible the intention of a donor or testator should be carried out as nearly as possible;
a rule that is adequate to permit work to be done;
a construct whereby objects or individuals can be distinguished; self-confidence is not an endearing property;
a characteristic property that defines the apparent individual nature of something; each town has a quality all its own; the radical character of our demands;
the essential quality of something; the texture of Neapolitan life;
a prominent attribute or aspect of something; the map showed roads and other features; generosity is one of his best characteristics;
(linguistics) a distinctive characteristic of a linguistic unit that serves to distinguish it from other units of the same kind;
a feature (quantity or property or function) that remains unchanged when a particular transformation is applied to it;
a distinct feature or element in a problem; he studied every facet of the question;
a characteristic that provides pleasure and attracts; flowers are an attractor for bees;
any feature that is regarded as a sign of status (a particular power or quality or rank); wearing a tie was regarded as a badge of respectability;
the central or most important feature; education was the centerpiece of the Democratic Party's political platform;
a feature (or the order or arrangement of features) of anything having a complex structure; the contours of the melody; it defines a major contour of this administration;
an outstanding feature; something in which something or someone excels; a center of manufacturing excellence; the use of herbs is one of the excellencies of French cuisine;
outward features; he enjoyed the solemn externals of religion;
an odd or unusual characteristic;
a distinguishing characteristic or behavior; bombs are a terrorist's calling cards;
feature of an artifact that is added to insure a user's safety;
an aspect of something (as contrasted with some other implied aspect); he was on the heavy side; he is on the purchasing side of the business; it brought out his better side;
a negative aspect of something that is generally positive; there is a downside even to motherhood;
one of two sides of an issue; on the one hand..., but on the other hand...;
a particular aspect of life or activity; he was helpless in an important sector of his life;
a specialized sphere of knowledge; baking is not my department; his work established a new department of literature;
a superficial aspect as opposed to the real nature of something; it was not what it appeared to be on the surface;
a general interest that leads people to want to know more; She was the center of attention;
a characteristic that attracts tourists;
anything that serves by contrast to call attention to another thing's good qualities; pretty girls like plain friends as foils;
a concept or idea not associated with any specific instance; he loved her only in the abstract--not in person;
something that is conceived or that exists independently and not in relation to other things; something that does not depend on anything else and is beyond human control; something that is not relative; no mortal being can influence the absolute;
a personified abstraction that teaches; books were his teachers; experience is a demanding teacher;
a special abstraction; a thing of the spirit; things of the heart;
the concept that something has a magnitude and can be represented in mathematical expressions by a constant or a variable;
(physics) the smallest discrete quantity of some physical property that a system can possess (according to quantum theory);
a discrete amount of something that is analogous to the quantities in quantum theory;
any distinct quantity contained in a polynomial; the general term of an algebraic equation of the n-th degree;
a quantity expressed as a number;
