a change in the form of a word (usually by adding a suffix) to indicate a change in its grammatical function;
the inflection of verbs;
the inflection of nouns and pronouns and adjectives in Indo-European languages;
systematic arrangement of all the inflected forms of a word;
the act of pluralizing or attributing plurality to;
the beginning or duration or completion or repetition of the action of a verb;
the aspect of a verb that expresses a completed action;
aspect without regard to the beginning or completion of the action of the verb;
the aspect of a verb that expresses its duration;
the aspect of a verb that expresses its on-going action;
aspect with regard to the beginning of the action of the verb;
the aspect of the verb that expresses the repetition of an action;
a tense of verbs used in describing action that is on-going;
a tense used to express action that is on-going at the time of utterance;
a tense of verbs used in describing action that has been completed (sometimes regarded as perfective aspect);
a perfective tense used to express action completed in the present; I have finishedis an example of the present perfect;
a term formerly used to refer to the simple past tense;
a perfective tense used to express action completed in the past; I had finishedis an example of the past perfect;
a progressive tense used to describe on-going action in the past; I had been runningis an example of the past progressive;
a perfective tense used to describe action that will be completed in the future; I will have finishedis an example of the future perfect;
a progressive tense used to express action that will be on-going in the future; I will be runningis an example of the future progressive;
a relation between meanings;
the semantic relation of being subordinate or belonging to a lower rank or class;
the semantic relation of being superordinate or belonging to a higher rank or class;
the semantic relation that holds between two words that can (in a given context) express the same meaning;
the semantic relation that holds between two words that can (in a given context) express opposite meanings;
the semantic relation that holds between a whole and its parts;
the semantic relation that holds between a part and the whole;
the semantic relation of being a manner of does something;
the relation between two words that are spelled the same way but differ in meaning or the relation between two words that are pronounced the same way but differ in meaning;
something determined in relation to something that includes it; he wanted to feel a part of something bigger than himself; I read a portion of the manuscript; the smaller component is hard to reach; the animal constituent of plankton;
the most important or necessary part of something; the basis of this drink is orange juice;
a small part that can be considered separately from the whole; it was perfect in all details;
the most interesting or memorable part; the highlight of the tour was our visit to the Vatican;
an individual or group or structure or other entity regarded as a structural or functional constituent of a whole; the reduced the number of units and installations; the word is a basic linguistic unit;
anything that belongs to a set or class; snakes are members of the class Reptilia; members of the opposite sex;
something left after other parts have been taken away; there was no remainder; he threw away the rest; he took what he wanted and I got the balance;
a small part or portion that remains after the main part no longer exists;
a part of a part;
a close connection marked by community of interests or similarity in nature or character; found a natural affinity with the immigrants; felt a deep kinship with the other students; anthropology's kinship with the humanities;
a relationship of mutual understanding or trust and agreement between people;
a relation of affinity or harmony between people; whatever affects one correspondingly affects the other; the two of them were in close sympathy;
sympathy of each person for the other;
(biology) state of relationship between organisms or groups of organisms resulting in resemblance in structure or structural parts; in anatomical structure prehistoric man shows close affinity with modern humans;
(anthropology) relatedness or connection by blood or marriage or adoption;
the kinship relation between an individual and the individual's progenitors;
(anthropology) kinship by marriage or adoption; not a blood relationship;
a family relationship by virtue of remarriage;
(anthropology) related by blood;
the kinship relation of an offspring to the parents;
the kinship relation between an offspring and the father;
the kinship relation between an offspring and the mother;
the kinship relation between a female offspring and the siblings;
the kinship relation between a male offspring and the siblings;
line of descent traced through both the maternal and paternal sides of the family;
line of descent traced through one side of the family;
line of descent traced through the maternal side of the family;
line of descent traced through the paternal side of the family;
the relationship between wife and husband;
a relation between magnitudes;
relative magnitude; they entertained on a grand scale;
the relation between things (or parts of things) with respect to their comparative quantity, magnitude, or degree; an inordinate proportion of the book is given over to quotations; a dry martini has a large proportion of gin;
the quotient obtained when the magnitude of a part is divided by the magnitude of the whole;
the number of cases of a disease ending in death divided by the number of cases of the disease; usually expressed as a percentage or as the number of deaths per 1000 cases;
the number of cases of a disease divided by the number of infections with the agent that causes the disease;
the proportion of a substance that is contained in a mixture or alloy etc.;
a quantity or amount or measure considered as a proportion of another quantity or amount or measure; the literacy rate; the retention rate; the dropout rate;
the ratio between the size of something and a representation of it; the scale of the map; the scale of the model;
the proportional relation between two divisions of line or two dimension of a plane figure such that short : long :: long : (short + long);
the relation of corresponding in degree or size or amount;
a proportion in relation to a whole (which is usually the amount per hundred);
the percentage of workers who do not report to work;
(baseball) a measure of a batter's performance; the number of base hits divided by the number of official times at bat; Ted Williams once had a batting average above .400;
(an extension of the baseball term) the proportion of times some effort succeeds; the salesman's batting average was 7 out of 12;
(baseball) a measure of a fielder's performance; the number of assists and putouts divided by the number of chances;
the percentage of all rental units (as in hotels) are occupied or rented at a given time;
occupancy rate for hospitals;
occupancy rate for hotels;
the percentage of all rental units (as in hotels) that are unoccupied or not rented at a given time;
the percentage of the work force that is unemployed at any given date;
the relative magnitudes of two quantities (usually expressed as a quotient);
(chemistry) the ratio of the total mass of an element in the earth's crust to the total mass of the earth's crust; expressed as a percentage or in parts per million;
(physics) the ratio of the number of atoms of a specific isotope of an element to the total number of isotopes present;
the ratio of reflected to incident light;
the ratio of the width to the height of a tv picture;
(sports) the ratio of successful performances to opportunities;
ratio (in percent) of the maximum breadth to the maximum length of a skull;
the ratio of the output to the input of any system;
a numerical expression representing the efficiency of a given system, material, or procedure;
the ratio (in percent) of the maximum width to the maximum height of the face;
the ratio of the focal length to the diameter of a (camera) lens system;
the ratio of the number of observations in a statistical category to the total number of observations;
the ratio of the volume occupied by packed red blood cells to the volume of the whole blood as measured by a hematocrit;
a measure of a person's intelligence as indicated by an intelligence test; the ratio of a person's mental age to their chronological age (multiplied by 100);
the average IQ of the adults in a given population;
the minimal IQ required for someone to function normally and independently in the world (without some form of institutional assistance);
(aeronautics) the ratio of an external load to the weight of the aircraft (measured in g);
the ratio of the annual claims paid by an insurance company to the premiums received;
the ratio of the speed of a moving body to the speed of sound;
the ratio of the size of an image to the size of the object;
