the basic unit of money in Bahrain; equal to 1,000 fils;
a fractional monetary unit in Bahrain and Iraq and Jordan and Kuwait; equal to one thousandth of a dinar;
monetary unit in Iraq;
the basic unit of money in Iraq; equal to 1,000 fils;
monetary unit in Jordan;
the basic unit of money in Jordan; equal to 1,000 fils;
monetary unit in Kuwait;
the basic unit of money in Kuwait; equal 1,000 fils;
worth one tenth of a Kuwaiti dinar; equal 100 fils;
monetary unit in Libya;
the basic unit of money in Libya;
100 dirhams equal 1 dinar in Libya;
monetary unit in Tunisia;
the basic unit of money in Tunisia;
100 dirhams equal 1 dinar in Tunisia;
1,000 millimes equal 1 dinar in Tunisia;
monetary unit in Yugoslavia;
the basic unit of money in Yugoslavia;
100 para equal 1 dinar in Yugoslavia;
monetary unit in Morocco;
the basic unit of money in Morocco; equal to 100 centimes;
monetary unit in the United Arab Emirates;
the basic unit of money in the United Arab Emirates; equal to 1,000 fils;
the basic unit of money in Australia and Nauru;
the basic unit of money in the Bahamas;
the basic unit of money in Barbados;
the basic unit of money in Belize;
the basic unit of money in Bermuda;
the basic unit of money in Brunei;
a fractional monetary unit of Japan and Indonesia and Cambodia; equal to one hundredth of a yen or rupiah or riel;
the basic unit of money in Canada; the Canadian dollar has the image of loon on one side of the coin;
the basic unit of money in the Cayman Islands;
the basic unit of money in Dominica;
the basic unit of money in Fiji;
the basic unit of money in Grenada;
the basic unit of money in Guyana;
the basic unit of money in Hong Kong;
the basic unit of money in Jamaica;
the basic unit of money in Kiribati;
the basic unit of money in Liberia;
the basic unit of money in New Zealand;
the basic unit of money in Singapore;
the basic unit of money in Taiwan;
the basic unit of money in Trinidad and Tobago;
the basic unit of money in Tuvalu;
the basic unit of money in the United States;
a United States dollar deposited in a European bank and used as an international currency to finance trade;
the basic unit of money in Zimbabwe;
monetary unit in Vietnam;
the basic unit of money in Vietnam;
10 hao equal 1 dong in Vietnam;
monetary unit in Greece;
formerly the basic unit of money in Greece;
100 lepta equal 1 drachma in Greece;
monetary unit on Sao Tome e Principe;
the basic unit of money on Sao Tome e Principe;
monetary unit on Cape Verde;
the basic unit of money on Cape Verde; equal to 100 centavos;
monetary unit in Portugal;
formerly the basic monetary unit of Portugal; equal to 100 centavo;
1 conto equals 1,000 escudos in Portugal;
monetary unit in Hungary;
the basic unit of money in Hungary;
100 filler equal 1 forint in Hungary;
formerly the basic unit of money in Hungary until it was replaced by the forint in 1946;
formerly the basic unit of money in Belgium;
the basic unit of money in Benin;
the basic unit of money in Burundi;
the basic unit of money in Cameroon;
the basic unit of money in the Central African Republic;
the basic unit of money in Chad;
the basic unit of money in the Congo;
the basic unit of money in Djibouti;
formerly the basic unit of money in France;
the basic unit of money in Gabon;
the basic unit of money in the Ivory Coast;
formerly the basic unit of money in Luxembourg;
the basic unit of money in Madagascar;
the basic unit of money in Mali;
the basic unit of money in Niger;
the basic unit of money in Rwanda;
the basic unit of money in Senegal;
the basic unit of money in Switzerland;
the basic unit of money in Togo;
the basic unit of money in Burkina Faso;
the monetary unit in Haiti;
the basic unit of money in Haiti;
100 centimes equal 1 gourde in Haiti;
monetary unit in Paraguay;
the basic unit of money in Paraguay; equal to 100 centimos;
monetary unit in the Netherlands;
formerly the basic unit of money in the Netherlands; equal to 100 cents;
monetary unit in Suriname;
the basic unit of money in Suriname; equal to 100 cents;
monetary unit in Peru;
the basic unit of money in Peru;
monetary unit in Papua New Guinea;
the basic unit of money in Papua New Guinea;
100 toea equal 1 kina in Papua New Guinea;
monetary unit in Laos;
