accidental contact between two points in an electric circuit that have a potential difference;
a route shorter than the usual one;
an iron with a short shaft and pitched face; for hitting short high shots;
a transportation system that operates over relatively short distances;
trousers that end at or above the knee;
a sleeve extending from the shoulder to the elbow;
a diathermy machine that uses short wave radiation as the source of heat;
a solid missile discharged from a firearm; the shot buzzed past his ear;
an explosive charge used in blasting;
sports equipment consisting of a heavy metal ball used in the shot put; he trained at putting the shot;
a small glass adequate to hold a single swallow of whiskey;
firearm that is a double-barreled smoothbore shoulder weapon for firing shot at short ranges;
a shell containing lead shot; used in shotguns;
drill hole for a charge of an explosive;
tower of a kind once used to make shot; molten lead was poured through a sieve and dropped into water;
a narrow edge of land (usually unpaved) along the side of a road; the car pulled off onto the shoulder;
the part of a garment that covers or fits over the shoulder; an ornamental gold braid on the shoulder of his uniform;
a large handbag that can be carried by a strap looped over the shoulder;
epaulets that indicate rank;
an arch consisting of a horizontal lintel supported at each end by corbels that project into the aperture;
a holster worn over your shoulder so a gun can be concealed under your jacket;
protective garment consisting of a hard rounded pad worn by football players to protect their shoulders;
patch worn on the shoulder of a military uniform to indicate rank;
a hand tool for lifting loose material; consists of a curved container or scoop and a handle;
a fire iron consisting of a small shovel used to scoop coals or ashes in a fireplace;
a stiff broad-brimmed hat with the brim turned up at the sides and projecting in front; worn by some clergymen in Britain;
a river steamboat on which theatrical performances could be given (especially on the Mississippi River);
a plumbing fixture that sprays water over you; they installed a shower in the bathroom;
a tight cap worn to keep hair dry while showering;
a curtain that keeps water from splashing out of the shower area;
a perforated nozzle that showers water on a bather;
a room with several showers;
booth for washing yourself, usually in a bathroom;
an area where merchandise (such as cars) can be displayed; in Britain a showroom is called a salesroom;
shell containing lead pellets that explodes in flight;
a device that shreds documents (usually in order to prevent the wrong people from reading them);
a vessel engaged in shrimping;
a place of worship hallowed by association with some sacred thing or person;
the clinging transparent plastic film that is used to shrinkwrap something;
a line that suspends the harness from the canopy of a parachute;
implant consisting of a tube made of plastic or rubber; for draining fluids within the body;
a conductor having low resistance in parallel with another device to divert a fraction of the current;
a small locomotive used to move cars around but not to make trips;
a hinged blind for a window;
a mechanical device on a camera that opens and closes to control the time of a photographic exposure;
the gatepost against which the gate closes;
bobbin that passes the weft thread between the warp threads;
public transport that consists of a bus or train or airplane that plies back and forth between two points;
shuttle consisting of a bus that travels between two points;
badminton equipment consisting of a ball of cork or rubber with a crown of feathers;
a helicopter that shuttles back and forth;
an inlet with two or more couplings to which a hose can be attached so that fire engines can pump water into the sprinkler system of a building;
a light conical canvas tent erected on a tripod with ventilation at the top;
a bag provided on an airplane for passengers who are suffering from airsickness and need to vomit;
(nautical) a room for the treatment of the sick or injured (as on a ship);
the bed on which a sick person lies;
an edge tool for cutting grass or crops; has a curved blade and a short handle;
a room to which a sick person is confined;
an extended outer surface of an object; he turned the box over to examine the bottom side; they painted all four sides of the house;
a board that forms part of the side of a bed or crib;
a removable board fitted on the side of a wagon to increase its capacity;
conveyance consisting of a small carrier attached to the side of a motorcycle;
a small chapel off the side aisle of a church;
an exterior door at one side of a building;
light carried by a boat that indicates the boat's direction; vessels at night carry a red light on the port bow and a green light on the starboard bow;
an auxiliary line of merchandise;
a pocket on the side of a billiard table;
a minor road branching off of a main road;
a saddle for a woman; rider sits with both feet on the same side of the horse;
a street intersecting a main street and terminating there;
walk consisting of a paved area for pedestrians; usually beside a street or roadway;
a wall that forms the side of a structure;
the side of an automobile tire; the car had white sidewalls;
a paddle steamer having a paddle wheel on each side;
air-to-air missile with infrared homing device;
the grounds at either side of a house;
a short stretch of railroad track used to store rolling stock or enable trains on the same line to pass;
the legendary seat at King Arthur's Round Table reserved for the knight who would find the Holy Grail; it was fatal for anyone else to sit in it;
German fortifications facing the Maginot Line;
a strainer for separating lumps from powdered material or grading particles;
a household sieve (as for flour);
an optical instrument for aiding the eye in aiming, as on a firearm or surveying instrument;
the adjustment of a gunsight for elevation and windage on a particular range under favorable light conditions;
an endoscope (a flexible fiberoptic probe) for examining the sigmoid colon;
a building from which signals are sent to control the movements of railway trains;
a device used to send signals;
structure displaying a board on which advertisements can be posted; the highway was lined with signboards;
a seal (especially one used to mark documents officially);
a ring bearing a signet;
virility drug (trade name Viagra) used to treat erectile dysfunction in men;
a tubular acoustic device inserted in the exhaust system that is designed to reduce noise;
short tube attached to the muzzle of a gun that deadens the sound of firing;
a small receptacle with a handle and a hinged lid; used for collecting crumbs or ashes;
a sturdy twill-weave cotton fabric; used for pockets and linings;
a vacuum coffee maker;
a drawing of the outline of an object; filled in with some uniform color;
a fabric made from the fine threads produced by certain insect larvae;
the brightly colored garments of a jockey; emblematic of the stable;
a print made using a stencil process in which an image or design is superimposed on a very fine mesh screen and printing ink is squeegeed onto the printing surface through the area of the screen that is not covered by the stencil;
structural member consisting of a continuous horizontal timber forming the lowest member of a framework or supporting structure;
