air passage provided by a retractable device containing intake and exhaust pipes; permits a submarine to stay submerged for extended periods of time;
breathing device consisting of a bent tube fitting into a swimmer's mouth and extending above the surface; allows swimmer to breathe while face down in the water;
something that is extraordinary or remarkable or prominent; a snorter of a sermon; the storm wasn't long but it was a snorter;
snow pressed into a ball for throwing (playfully);
a mound or heap of snow;
a board that resembles a broad ski or a small surfboard; used in a standing position to slide down snow-covered slopes;
a figure of a person made of packed snow;
tracked vehicle for travel on snow having skis in front;
a vehicle used to push snow from roads;
a device to help you walk on deep snow; a lightweight frame shaped like a racquet is strengthened with cross pieces and contains a network of thongs; one is worn on each foot;
a child's overgarment for cold weather;
a machine that removes snow by scooping it up and throwing it forcefully through a chute;
an automobile pneumatic tire with deep tread to give traction in snow;
finely powdered tobacco for sniffing up the nose;
a small ornamental box for carrying snuff in your pocket;
a cone-shaped implement with a handle; for extinguishing candles;
scissors for cropping and holding the snuff of a candlewick;
a cleansing agent made from the salts of vegetable or animal fats;
street names for gamma hydroxybutyrate;
a crate for packing soap;
a bathroom or kitchen fixture for holding a bar of soap;
dispenser of liquid soap;
a film left on objects after they have been washed in soap;
soap that has been cut into flakes to make suds faster;
a cleaning pad containing soap;
soap in powdered form mixed with alkaline builders;
an inflated ball used in playing soccer;
hosiery consisting of a cloth covering for the foot; worn inside the shoe; reaches to between the ankle and the knee;
a receptacle into which an electric device can be inserted;
receptacle where something (a pipe or probe or end of a bone) is inserted;
a wrench with a handle onto which sockets of different sizes can be fitted;
a plain plinth that supports a wall;
a can for holding soft drinks;
an apparatus for dispensing soda water;
a counter where ice cream and sodas and sundaes are prepared and served;
a house built of sod or adobe laid in horizontal courses;
a crystalline salt used as an analgesic and antipyretic;
a long-acting barbiturate used as a sedative;
lamp in which an electric current passed through a tube of sodium vapor makes a yellow light; used is street lighting;
an upholstered seat for more than one person;
the underside of a part of a building (such as an arch or overhang or beam etc.);
ball used in playing softball;
a drug of abuse that is considered relatively mild and not likely to cause addiction;
a pedal on a piano that moves the action closer to the strings and so soften the sound;
a soft (or liquid) soap made from vegetable oils; used in certain skin diseases;
merchandise consisting of a computer program that is offered for sale;
drain that conveys liquid waste from toilets, etc.;
electrical device consisting of a large array of connected solar cells;
a cell that converts solar energy into electrical energy;
a concave mirror that concentrates the rays of the sun; can produce high temperatures;
a heater that makes direct use of solar energy;
a house designed to use solar radiation for heating; usually has large areas of glass in front of heat-absorbing materials;
a telescope designed to make observations of the sun;
a system that converts sunlight into heat;
a hand tool with a heatable tip; used to melt and apply solder;
the underside of footwear or a golf club;
a coil of wire around an iron core; becomes a magnet when current passes through the coil;
a gem (usually a diamond) in a setting by itself;
armor plate that protects the foot; consists of mail with a solid toe and heel;
a straw hat with a tall crown and broad brim; worn in American southwest and in Mexico;
a measuring instrument that sends out an acoustic pulse in water and measures distances in terms of the time for the echo of the pulse to return; sonar is an acronym for sound navigation ranging; asdic is an acronym for antisubmarine detection investigation committee;
depth finder for determining depth of water or a submerged object by means of ultrasound waves;
an image of a structure that is produced by ultrasonography (reflections of high-frequency sound waves); used to observe fetal growth or to study bodily organs;
an instrument that uses the differential transmission and reflection of ultrasonic waves in order to provide an image of a bodily organ;
medicine in the form of a syrup that has a calming effect;
a drug that induces sleep;
a machine for sorting things (such as punched cards or letters) into classes;
an open-air market in an Arabian city;
contact (the part of a bell) against which the clapper strikes;
a resonating chamber in a musical instrument (as the body of a violin);
a movie camera that records sounds in synchrony with the visual images;
a device for making soundings;
motion-picture film with sound effects and dialogue recorded on it;
a hole in a soundboard (as of a violin) designed to resonate with the tones;
(music) resonator consisting of a thin board whose vibrations reinforce the sound of the instrument;
a metal bob at the end of a sounding line;
a research rocket used to obtain information about the atmosphere at various altitudes;
a recording of acoustic signals;
a spectrograph for acoustic spectra;
sound recording on a narrow strip of a motion picture film;
a truck equipped with a loudspeaker and used for advertising;
a bowl for serving soup;
a ladle for serving soup;
a deep plate with a wide rim;
a spoon with a rounded bowl for eating soup;
a facility where something is available;
any device serving as a source of visible electromagnetic radiation;
an organ stop resulting in a soft muted sound;
a mute for a violin;
a narrow braid used as a decorative trimming;
a long cassock with buttons down the front; worn by Roman Catholic priests;
waterproof hat with wide slanting brim longer in back than in front;
soybeans bought or sold at an agreed price for delivery at a specified future date;
the bar-shaped typewriter key that introduces spaces when used;
a spacecraft designed to transport people and support human life in outer space;
a craft capable of traveling in outer space; technically, a satellite around the sun;
heater consisting of a self-contained (usually portable) unit to warm a room;
a helmet worn by astronauts while in outer space;
a tower 605 feet tall in Seattle; a tourist attraction;
a rocket-propelled guided missile that can escape the earth's atmosphere; makes observations of the solar system that cannot be made by terrestrial observation;
