a prearranged fight with deadly weapons by two people (accompanied by seconds) in order to settle a quarrel over a point of honor;
a powerful stroke with the fist or a weapon; a blow on the head;
a return blow; a retaliatory blow;
a sweeping blow or stroke; he took a wild swing at my head;
a fight with bare fists;
a strong blow with a knife or other sharp pointed instrument; one strong stab to the heart killed him;
(fencing) an attacking thrust made with one foot forward and the back leg straight and with the sword arm outstretched forward;
(fencing) blocking a lunge or deflecting it with a circular motion of the sword;
(fencing) a second thrust made on the same lunge (as when your opponent fails to riposte);
(fencing) a counterattack made immediately after successfully parrying the opponents lunge;
a sharp stinging blow;
a heavy blow with the hand;
a swinging blow directed upward (especially at an opponent's chin);
the act of pounding (delivering repeated heavy blows); the sudden hammer of fists caught him off guard; the pounding of feet on the hallway;
a blow hard enough to cause injury; he is still recovering from a shot to his leg; I caught him with a solid shot to the chin;
an illegal and unsportsmanlike act of unnecessary violence; he called a penalty on them when the lineman took a cheap shot at the quarterback;
a severe blow;
the act of subjecting to strong attack;
the act of overcoming or outdoing;
a noisy fight;
a noisy fight in a crowd;
fighting with knives;
a fight between rival gangs of adolescents;
a fight between two people; in all armies there were officers who needed to prove their bravery by single combat;
deliberate interference;
the act of protesting; a public (often organized) manifestation of dissent;
refusal to accept some authority or code or convention; each generation must have its own rebellion; his body was in rebellion against fatigue;
a fistfight; the quarrel ended in a punch-up;
a public display of group feelings (usually of a political nature); there were violent demonstrations against the war;
a demonstration held in opposition to another demonstration; supporters of the president organized a counterdemonstration in his support;
the act of walking out (of a meeting or organization) as a sign of protest; there was a walkout by the Black members as the chairman rose to speak;
demonstration (1773) by citizens of Boston who (disguised as Indians) raided three British ships in Boston harbor and dumped hundreds of chests of tea into the harbor; organized as a protest against taxes on tea;
a protest march against (a particular) war and in favor of peace;
a form of civil disobedience in which demonstrators occupy seats and refuse to move;
occasion when workers continue to work as a protest against e.g. proposed dismissal or closure of the factory;
occasion when you can express opposition by marching (usually on some government institution) without a license;
an insubordinate act;
obstinate rebelliousness and insubordination; resistance to authority;
the failure to obey;
a group's refusal to obey a law because they believe the law is immoral (as in protest against discrimination); Thoreau wrote a famous essay justifying civil disobedience;
a willful disobedience to or disrespect for the authority of a court or legislative body;
deliberate obstruction of the operation of the federal legislative branch;
disrespect for the rules of a court of law;
a failure to follow a court order that benefits someone else;
willful refusal to appear before a court or comply with a court order; can result in a finding of contempt of court;
an act of disrespect that impedes the administration of justice;
impeding those who seek justice in a court (as by trying to influence or intimidate any juror or witness or officer of the court); can result in a finding of contempt of court;
(law) the administration of justice according to established rules and principles; based on the principle that a person cannot be deprived of life or liberty or property without appropriate legal procedures and safeguards;
a judicial proceeding brought by one party against another; one party prosecutes another for a wrong done or for protection of a right or for prevention of a wrong;
an act by a government body or supranational organization; recent federal action undermined the segregationist position; the United Nations must have the power to propose and organize action without being hobbled by irrelevant issues; the Union action of emancipating Southern slaves;
a comprehensive term for any proceeding in a court of law whereby an individual seeks a legal remedy; the family brought suit against the landlord;
a lawsuit alleging violations of civil law by the defendant;
a lawsuit brought by a representative member of a large group of people on behalf of all members of the group;
a suit brought against someone who has sued you;
a lawsuit alleging violations of criminal law by the defendant;
a hypothetical case that law students argue as an exercise; he organized the weekly moot;
a lawsuit filed to determine the father of a child born out of wedlock (and to provide for the support of the child once paternity is determined);
a legal action brought against parties who are charged with limiting free competition in the market place;
legal action to protect a private civil right or to compel a civil remedy (as distinguished from criminal prosecution);
a claim filed in opposition to another claim in a legal action;
a legal action to determine custody (usually of children following a divorce);
a pending lawsuit;
(law) the institution of a sequence of steps by which legal judgments are invoked;
a legal proceeding that creates a parent-child relation between persons not related by blood; the adopted child is entitled to all privileges belonging to a natural child of the adoptive parents (including the right to inherit);
(law) a legal proceeding in which the appellant resorts to a higher court for the purpose of obtaining a review of a lower court decision and a reversal of the lower court's judgment or the granting of a new trial; their appeal was denied in the superior court;
a judgment by a higher court that the judgment of a lower court was incorrect and should be set aside;
a judgment by a higher court that the judgment of a lower court was correct and should stand;
a legal process intended to insure equality among the creditors of a corporation declared to be insolvent;
a court action that places property under the control of a receiver during litigation so that it can be preserved for the benefit of all;
a legal proceeding in a court; a judicial contest to determine and enforce legal rights;
litigation to settle custody of the children of a divorced couple;
litigation shown to have been instituted maliciously and without probable cause; he got an injunction against vexatious litigation by his enemies;
an accusation of crime made by a grand jury on its own initiative;
the proceeding whereby a foreigner is granted citizenship;
(law) the determination by a court of competent jurisdiction on matters submitted to it;
a judgment entered after a written confession by the debtor without the expense of ordinary legal proceedings;
a judgment entered in favor of the plaintiff when the defendant defaults (fails to appear in court);
a judgment entered in favor of the defendant when the plaintiff has not continued his action (e.g., has not appeared in court);
a judgment disposing of the case before the court; after the judgment (or an appeal from it) is rendered all that remains is to enforce the judgment;
(criminal law) a final judgment of guilty in a criminal case and the punishment that is imposed; the conviction came as no surprise;
a judgment rendered against an individual (or corporation) for the payment of money damages;
a judgment pronounced on the status of some particular subject or property or thing (as opposed to one pronounced on persons);
a judgment disposing of the matter without a trial;
judgment rendered through analysis and adjudication of the factual issues presented;
a judgment rendered by the court prior to a verdict because no material issue of fact exists and one party or the other is entitled to a judgment as a matter of law;
the act of deciding as an arbiter; giving authoritative judgment; they submitted their disagreement to arbitration;
the reason for a court's judgment (as opposed to the decision itself);
a ruling by the Supreme Court on affirmative action; the Court ruled in 1978 that medical schools are entitled to consider race as a factor in their admission policy;
a ruling on a point of Islamic law that is given by a recognized authority;
the act of umpiring; the officiating was excellent;
the decision of a court on issues of fact or law;
(law) the findings of a jury on issues of fact submitted to it for decision; can be used in formulating a judgment;
a finding as to the applicability of a rule of law to particular facts;
a verdict resulting from improper compromises between jurors on material issues;
a verdict entered by the court in a jury trial without consideration by the jury; there cannot be a directed verdict of guilty in a criminal trial;
a manifestly unjust verdict; not true to the evidence;
an ordinary verdict declaring which party prevails without any special findings of fact;
(criminal law) a finding that the defendant is guilty of some charges but innocent of others;
an improper and unacceptable kind of compromise verdict;
a verdict rendered on certain specific factual issues posed by the court without finding for one party or the other;
