having no living or known mother;
characteristic of a father;
like or befitting a father or fatherhood; kind and protective;
benevolent but sometimes intrusive;
characteristic of a mother; warm maternal affection for her guest- Dorothy Sayers;
showing maternal instincts;
suggestive of or acting like a mother;
befitting a mother; warm and nurturing;
befitting or characteristic of a wife;
befitting or characteristic of a husband;
enduring trying circumstances with even temper or characterized by such endurance; a patient smile; was patient with the children; an exact and patient scientist; please be patient;
quietly and steadily persevering especially in detail or exactness; a diligent (or patient) worker; with persevering (or patient) industry she revived the failing business;
patiently bearing continual wrongs or trouble; an enduring disposition; a long-suffering and uncomplaining wife;
showing patient and unruffled self-control and restraint under adversity; slow to retaliate or express resentment; seemly and forbearing...yet strong enough to resist aggression; was longanimous in the face of suffering;
showing the capacity for endurance; injustice can make us tolerant and forgiving; a man patient of distractions;
capable of accepting delay with equanimity; was unhurried with the small children;
restless or short-tempered under delay or opposition; impatient with the slower students; impatient of criticism;
impatient especially under restriction or delay; the government has done nothing to ease restrictions and manufacturers are growing restive;
unwilling to endure; she was unforbearing with the slower students;
characteristic of a form of social organization in which the male is the family head and title is traced through the male line;
(of societies) being ruled by or having descent traced through the male line;
centered upon the father;
characteristic of a matriarchy;
(of societies or families) having a female as the family head or having descent traced through the female line;
centered upon the mother;
having patronage or clients; street full of flourishing well-patronized shops;
having little patronage or few clients; a restaurant unpatronized by the elite;
(of lawyers or barristers) lacking clients;
enclosed in a package or protective covering; packaged cereals;
prepared and wrapped beforehand and ready for sale; prepackaged foods;
not packaged or put into packets; unpackaged nuts;
not carefully arranged in a package; a box of loose nails;
covered with a firm surface;
having been paved;
having been paved;
not having a paved surface;
covered with caliche, a hard calcium-carbonate encrusted soil;
inspired by love for your country;
fanatically patriotic;
showing lack of love for your country;
considered contrary to the best interests of the United States;
not disturbed by strife or turmoil or war; a peaceful nation; peaceful times; a far from peaceful Christmas; peaceful sleep;
idyllically calm and peaceful; suggesting happy tranquillity; a halcyon atmosphere;
conducive to peace; irenic without being namby-pamby; an irenic attitude toward former antagonists;
not directly at war; nonbelligerent nations;
disposed to peace or of a peaceful nature; the pacific temper seeks to settle disputes on grounds of justice rather than by force; a quiet and peaceable person; in a peaceable and orderly manner;
opposed to war;
inclined or disposed to peace; they met in a peaceable spirit; peace-loving citizens;
not peaceful; unpeaceful times; an unpeaceful marriage;
engaged in war; belligerent (or warring) nations;
disposed to warfare or hard-line policies; militant nations; hawkish congressman; warlike policies;
characterized by violent emotions or behavior; a stormy argument; a stormy marriage;
not disposed to peace;
feeling or expressing remorse for misdeeds;
feeling or expressing pain or sorrow for sins or offenses;
showing or constituting penance; penitential tears; wrote a penitential letter apologizing for her hasty words;
not penitent or remorseful;
having the ability to perceive or understand; keen in discernment; a perceptive eye; a perceptive observation;
having or demonstrating ability to recognize or draw fine distinctions; an acute observer of politics and politicians; incisive comments; icy knifelike reasoning; as sharp and incisive as the stroke of a fang; penetrating insight; frequent penetrative observations;
quick to understand; a kind and apprehensive friend- Nathaniel Hawthorne;
able to relate new percepts to past experience;
exhibiting insight or clear and deep perception; an insightful parent; the chapter is insightful and suggestive of new perspectives-R.C.Angell;
quick to notice; showing quick and keen perception;
keenly perceptive or alert; quick-sighted into the faults of the time- Leonard Bacon;
able to make fine distinctions; a subtle mind;
characterized by understanding based on comprehension and discernment and empathy; an understanding friend;
lacking perception; as unperceptive as a boulder;
unable or unwilling to perceive or understand; blind to a lover's faults; blind to the consequences of their actions;
not consciously observing; looked through him with blank unseeing eyes;
capable of being perceived by the mind or senses; a perceptible limp; easily perceptible sounds; perceptible changes in behavior;
capable of being detected; after a noticeable pause the lecturer continued;
capable of being perceived clearly; an essay with a meaning that was not always discernible;
deficient in magnitude; barely perceptible; lacking clarity or brightness or loudness etc; a faint outline; the wan sun cast faint shadows; the faint light of a distant candle; weak colors; a faint hissing sound; a faint aroma; a weak pulse;
can be felt by palpation; a palpable tumor;
capable of being perceived especially by sight or hearing; perceivable through the mist;
easily perceived; easy to become aware of; this situation produces recognizable stress symptoms;
readily perceived by the senses; the sensible universe; a sensible odor;
impossible or difficult to perceive by the mind or senses; an imperceptible drop in temperature; an imperceptible nod; color is unperceivable to the touch;
not perceptible to the touch; an impalpable pulse;
incapable of being perceived or known;
barely able to be perceived; the transition was almost indiscernible; an almost insensible change;
below the threshold of conscious perception;
not accessible to direct observation;
being complete of its kind and without defect or blemish; a perfect circle; a perfect reproduction; perfect happiness; perfect manners; a perfect specimen; a perfect day;
(of a record) having no marks of discredit or offense; a clean voting record; a clean driver's license;
free from flaw or blemish or impurity; a clear perfect diamond; the clear complexion of a healthy young woman;
marked by errorless familiarity; had her lines cold before rehearsals started;
perfect and complete in every respect; having all necessary qualities; a complete gentleman; consummate happiness; a consummate performance;
understood perfectly; had his algebra problems down;
free from error; an errorless baseball game;
without fault or error; faultless logic; speaks impeccable French; timing and technique were immaculate; an immaculate record;
without a flaw; a flawless gemstone;
conforming to an ultimate standard of perfection or excellence; embodying an ideal;
exalted to an ideal perfection or excellence;
excellent and delightful in all respects; an idyllic spot for a picnic;
as if new; in mint condition;
capable of becoming or being made perfect;
more than perfect; he spoke with pluperfect precision;
(of language) not having its purity or excellence debased; uncorrupted English; learn to speak pure English undefiled- Van Wyck Brooks;
not perfect; defective or inadequate; had only an imperfect understanding of his responsibilities; imperfect mortals; drainage here is imperfect;
