have sexual intercourse with; This student sleeps with everyone in her dorm; Adam knew Eve; Were you ever intimate with this man?;
have sex with; archaic use; He had taken this woman when she was most vulnerable;
have sex without being married;
engage freely in promiscuous sex, often with the husband or wife of one's friends; There were many swinging couples in the 1960's;
have unlawful sex with a whore;
frequent prostitutes;
mate with; male birds tread the females;
mate with; male animals serve the females for breeding purposes;
be available for stud services; male domestic animals such as stallions serve selected females;
deprive of virginity; This dirty old man deflowered several young girls in the village;
induce to have sex; Harry finally seduced Sally; Did you score last night?; Harry made Sally;
engage in sexual intercourse; Birds mate in the Spring;
copulate with; The bull was riding the cow;
cause to procreate (animals) ; She breeds dogs;
cause to become a mongrel; mongrelized dogs;
mate a hybrid of the first generation with one of its parents;
breed animals or plants using parents of different races and varieties; cross a horse and a donkey; Mendel tried crossbreeding; these species do not interbreed;
copulate with a female, used especially of horses; The horse covers the mare;
get sexual gratification through self-stimulation;
stimulate sexually; The old man wanted to be masturbated by the prostitute;
masturbate while strangling oneself;
touch with the lips or press the lips (against someone's mouth or other body part) as an expression of love, greeting, etc.; The newly married couple kissed; She kissed her grandfather on the forehead when she entered the room;
touch lightly or gently; the blossoms were kissed by the soft rain;
kiss lightly;
touch or stroke lightly; The grass tickled her calves;
pass the tongue over; the dog licked her hand;
lick or explore with the tongue;
touch with the mouth;
move while holding up or supporting; Bear gifts; bear a heavy load; bear news; bearing orders;
carry away rapidly and secretly, as if mysteriously;
carry in a bucket;
make a return; return a kickback;
go or come after and bring or take back; Get me those books over there, please; Could you bring the wine?; The dog fetched the hat;
take away or remove; The devil will fetch you!;
run after, pick up, and bring to the master; train the dog to retrieve;
go for and bring back; retrieve the car from the parking garage;
be accompanied by; Can I bring my cousin to the dinner?;
remove from a certain place, environment, or mental or emotional state; transport into a new location or state; Their dreams carried the Romantics away into distant lands; The car carried us off to the meeting; I'll take you away on a holiday; I got carried away when I saw the dead man and I started to cry;
place or lay as if in a pile; The teacher piled work on the students until the parents protested;
carry off mysteriously; as if by magic;
take away quickly and suddenly;
brush or wipe off lightly;
send from one person or place to another; transmit a message;
transfer (ideas or principles) from one domain into another;
transmit; propagate sound or light through air;
bring to a certain spiritual state;
transport to a destiny through pipes; We have to pipe in oil;
let (something) fall or spill from a container; turn the flour onto a plate;
release contained air or gas from; deflate the air mattress;
collapse by releasing contained air or gas; deflate a balloon;
throw (a die) out onto a flat surface; Throw a six;
throw dice, as in a crap game;
to cause or order to be taken, directed, or transmitted to another place; He had sent the dispatches downtown to the proper people and had slept;
mail in; cause to be delivered; Send in your comments;
transmit by mail; The company mailed out the catalog to all potential customers;
send via the postal service; I'll mail you the check tomorrow;
send by special mail that goes through diplomatic channels;
bring to a destination, make a delivery; our local super market delivers;
deliver to the wrong address;
deliver a warrant or summons to someone; He was processed by the sheriff;
cause to come into a particular state or condition; Long hard years of on the job training had brought them to their competence; bring water to the boiling point;
take hold of so as to seize or restrain or stop the motion of; Catch the ball!; Grab the elevator door!;
capture again; recapture the escaped prisoner;
to grasp hastily or eagerly; Before I could stop him the dog snatched the ham bone;
seize or catch with a swooping motion;
move forward or upward in order to touch; also in a metaphorical sense; Government reaches out to the people;
seize on its way; The fighter plane was ordered to intercept an aircraft that had entered the country's airspace;
cut off and stop; The bicyclist was cut out by the van;
make a small hole into, as with a needle or a thorn; The nurse pricked my finger to get a small blood sample;
make a hole into; The needle pierced her flesh;
penetrate or cut, as with a knife; The fork bit into the surface;
penetrate or cut through with a sharp instrument;
pierce or penetrate or puncture with something pointed; He stuck the needle into his finger;
pierce with a thrust using a pointed instrument; he stuck the cloth with the needle;
pierce with a wooden pin or knock or thrust a wooden pin into;
cut or make a way through; the knife cut through the flesh; The path pierced the jungle; Light pierced through the forest;
attack with or as if with a pickaxe of ice or rocky ground, for example; Pick open the ice;
make a hole into or between, as for ease of separation; perforate the sheets of paper;
make a hole, especially with a pointed power or hand tool; don't drill here, there's a gas pipe; drill a hole into the wall; drill for oil; carpenter bees are boring holes into the wall;
initiate drilling operations, as for petroleum; The well was spudded in April;
drill in an opposite direction;
make a small hole in something as a guide for a drill;
cut a hole with a trepan, as in surgery;
force a way through;
move or pour through a funnel; funnel the liquid into the small bottle;
pierce with a sharp stake or point; impale a shrimp on a skewer;
drive a skewer through; skewer the meat for the BBQ;
pierce with a pin; pin down the butterfly;
pierce with a spear; spear fish;
stab or pierce with a horn or tusk; the rhino horned the explorer;
wound by piercing with a sharp or penetrating object or instrument;
deliver a sting to; A bee stung my arm yesterday;
bite or chew on with the teeth; gnaw an old cracker;
bite off with a quick bite; The dog snapped off a piece of cloth from the intruder's pants;
to grip, cut off, or tear with or as if with the teeth or jaws; Gunny invariably tried to bite her;
bring the jaws together; he snapped indignantly;
bite gently; The woman tenderly nibbled at her baby's ear;
give a small sharp bite to; The Queen's corgis always nip at her staff's ankles;
bite off very small pieces; She nibbled on her cracker;
move or swing back and forth; She waved her gun;
