dark reddish-purple table grape of California;
pale yellow seedless grape used for raisins and wine;
variety of wine grape originally grown in Hungary; the prototype of vinifera grapes;
purplish-red table grape;
seedless green table grape of California;
the fruit of any of several tropical American trees of the genus Annona having soft edible pulp;
large tropical fruit with leathery skin and soft pulp; related to custard apples;
large spiny tropical fruit with tart pulp related to custard apples;
large heart-shaped tropical fruit with soft acid pulp;
sweet pulpy tropical fruit with thick scaly rind and shiny black seeds;
whitish tropical fruit with a pinkish tinge related to custard apples; grown in the southern United States;
ovoid yellow fruit with very fragrant peach-colored flesh; related to custard apples;
fruit with yellow flesh; related to custard apples;
large oval melon-like tropical fruit with yellowish flesh;
South African fruit smelling and tasting like apricots; used for pickles and preserves;
maroon-purple gooseberry-like fruit of India having tart-sweet purple pulp used especially for preserves;
red pear-shaped tropical fruit with poisonous seeds; flesh is poisonous when unripe or overripe;
huge fruit native to southeastern Asia smelling like Hell and tasting like Heaven; seeds are roasted and eaten like nuts;
dark-green kiwi-sized tropical fruit with white flesh; used chiefly for jellies and preserves;
round one-inch Caribbean fruit with green leathery skin and sweet juicy translucent pulp; eaten like grapes;
a succulent orange-sized tropical fruit with a thick rind;
fuzzy brown egg-shaped fruit with slightly tart green flesh;
yellow olive-sized semitropical fruit with a large free stone and relatively little flesh; used for jellies;
two- to three-inch tropical fruit with juicy flesh suggestive of both peaches and pineapples;
large oval tropical fruit having smooth skin, juicy aromatic pulp, and a large hairy seed;
tropical fruit with a rough brownish skin and very sweet brownish pulp;
brown oval fruit flesh makes excellent sherbet;
large tropical seed pod with very tangy pulp that is eaten fresh or cooked with rice and fish or preserved for curries and chutneys;
a pear-shaped tropical fruit with green or blackish skin and rich yellowish pulp enclosing a single large seed;
sweet edible fruit of the date palm with a single long woody seed;
berrylike fruit of an elder used for e.g. wines and jellies;
tropical fruit having yellow skin and pink pulp; eaten fresh or used for e.g. jellies;
purplish tropical fruit;
yellow oval tropical fruit;
fruit of the wild plum of southern United States;
tough-skinned purple grapelike tropical fruit grown in Brazil;
dark red plumlike fruit of Old World buckthorn trees;
Chinese fruit having a thin brittle shell enclosing a sweet jellylike pulp and a single seed; often dried;
Asian fruit similar to litchi;
globular or ovoid tropical fruit with thick russet leathery rind and juicy yellow or reddish flesh;
tropical fruit from the Philippines having a mass of small seeds embedded in sweetish white pulp;
crabapple-like fruit used for preserves;
a South African globular fruit with brown leathery skin and pithy flesh having a sweet-acid taste;
sweet usually dark purple blackberry-like fruit of any of several mulberry trees of the genus Morus;
one-seeded fruit of the European olive tree usually pickled and used as a relish;
olives picked ripe and cured in brine then dried or pickled or preserved canned or in oil;
olives picked green and pickled in brine; infrequently stuffed with e.g. pimento;
sweet juicy gritty-textured fruit available in many varieties;
greenish-yellow pear;
a pear with firm flesh and a green skin;
juicy yellow pear;
small yellowish- to reddish-brown pear;
starchy banana-like fruit; eaten (always cooked) as a staple vegetable throughout the tropics;
hybrid between plum and apricot;
large globular fruit having many seeds with juicy red pulp in a tough brownish-red rind;
round or pear-shaped spiny fruit of any of various prickly pear cacti;
small berrylike fruit;
small yellow to orange fruit of the Barbados gooseberry cactus used in desserts and preserves and jellies;
red Australian fruit; used for dessert or in jam;
edible nutlike seed of the quandong fruit;
aromatic acid-tasting pear-shaped fruit used in preserves;
pleasantly acid bright red oval Malayan fruit covered with soft spines;
fruit of an East Indian tree similar to the rambutan but sweeter;
fragrant oval yellowish tropical fruit used in jellies and confections;
acid gritty-textured fruit;
acid-tasting Australian gourd-like fruit with a woody rind and large seeds;
African gourd-like fruit with edible pulp;
many are used as seasoning;
the edible seed of a pumpkin;
seed of betel palm; chewed with leaves of the betel pepper and lime as a digestive stimulant and narcotic in southeastern Asia;
small sweet triangular nut of any of various beech trees;
nut of any of various walnut trees having a wrinkled two-lobed seed with a hard shell;
American walnut having a very hard and thick woody shell;
nut with a wrinkled two-lobed seed and hard but relatively thin shell; widely used in cooking;
three-sided tropical American nut with white oily meat and hard brown shell;
oily egg-shaped nut of an American tree of the walnut family;
a large nutlike seed of a South American tree;
kidney-shaped nut edible only when roasted;
edible nut of any of various chestnut trees of the genus Castanea;
small nut of either of two small chestnut trees of the southern United States; resembles a hazelnut;
edible nutlike seeds of an American lotus having the flavor of a chinquapin;
nut of any of several trees of the genus Corylus;
large hard-shelled oval nut with a fibrous husk containing thick white meat surrounding a central cavity filled (when fresh) with fluid or milk;
the edible white meat of a coconut; often shredded for use in e.g. cakes and curries;
clear to whitish fluid from within a fresh coconut;
the dried meat of the coconut from which oil is extracted;
edible oil-rich seed of wild mango;
somewhat astringent paste prepared by grinding and heating seeds of the African wild mango; a staple food of some African peoples;
nutlike tuber; important food of Native Americans;
nut of Brazilian or West Indian palms;
small hard-shelled nut of North American hickory trees especially the shagbark hickories;
a flavoring extracted from the kola nut;
nutlike seed with sweet and crisp white meat;
smooth brown oval nut of south central United States;
edible seed of any of several nut pines especially some pinons of southwestern North America;
nut of Mediterranean trees having an edible green kernel;
edible seed of sunflowers; used as food and poultry feed and as a source of oil;
the flesh of fish used as food; in Japan most fish is eaten raw; after the scare about foot-and-mouth disease a lot of people started eating fish instead of meat; they have a chef who specializes in fish;
flesh of fish from the sea used as food;
flesh of fish from fresh water used as food;
