the quality of being incapable of mutation; Darwin challenged the fixity of species;
the quality of not being alterable;
incapability of being altered in disposition or habits; the incurability of his optimism;
the quality of being timeless and eternal;
the quality of being alike; sameness of purpose kept them together;
the quality of being not alike; being distinct or different from that otherwise experienced or known;
exact sameness; they shared an identity of interests;
the quality of being united into one;
the quality of being identical with itself;
the quality of being similar;
the quality of coming near to identity (especially close in quantity);
(biology) similarity because of common evolution;
the quality of being similar or corresponding in position or value or structure or function;
similarity of form;
(biology) similarity or identity of form or shape or structure;
similarity in appearance or character or nature between persons or things; man created God in his own likeness;
similarity by virtue of corresponding;
the quality of lacking diversity or variation (even to the point of boredom);
the quality of being similar or comparable in kind or nature; there is a remarkable homogeneity between the two companies;
a harmonious uniformity or agreement among things or parts;
a close approximation; the nearest approach to genius;
an approximate definition or example; she wore a sort of magenta dress; she served a creamy sort of dessert thing;
something having the property of being analogous to something else;
a close parallel of a feeling, idea, style, etc.; his contention contains more than an echo of Rousseau; Napoleon III was an echo of the mighty Emperor but an infinitely better man;
qualities that are comparable; no comparison between the two books; beyond compare;
a likeness in which left and right are reversed;
the likeness of a representation to the thing represented; engineers strove to increase the naturalness of recorded music;
similarity in appearance or external or superficial details;
a perfect likeness or counterpart;
symmetrical resemblance;
inherent resemblance between persons or things;
the quality of being the same in quantity or measure or value or status;
capability of being equated;
essential equality and interchangeability;
functional equality;
the quality of being balanced;
equality of measure (e.g., equality of height above sea level or equality of loudness etc.);
the quality of being unlike or dissimilar; there are many differences between jazz and rock;
a quality that differentiates between similar things;
distinguishing characteristics (especially in different species of a genus);
a distinguishing difference; he learned the distinction between gold and lead;
a difference between conflicting facts or claims or opinions; a growing divergence of opinion;
a permissible difference; allowing some freedom to move within limits;
the quality of being dissimilar;
utter dissimilarity;
(biology) the lack of correspondence of apparently similar body parts;
dissimilarity evidenced by an absence of likeness;
the quality of being diverse and interesting;
the quality of being diverse and not comparable in kind;
noticeable heterogeneity; a diversity of possibilities; the range and variety of his work is amazing;
the diversity of plant and animal life in a particular habitat (or in the world as a whole); a high level of biodiversity is desirable;
the quality of being inconsistent and lacking a harmonious uniformity among things or parts;
a difference that is usually pleasant; he goes to France for variety; it is a refreshing change to meet a woman mechanic;
lack of equality; the growing inequality between rich and poor;
not interchangeable;
inequality or difference in some respect;
a disappointing disparity; it was a far cry from what he had expected;
a conspicuous disparity or difference as between two figures; gap between income and outgo; the spread between lending and borrowing costs;
an unbridgeable disparity (as from a failure of understanding); he felt a gulf between himself and his former friends; there is a vast disconnect between public opinion and federal policy;
the quality of being unbalanced;
something that is certain; his victory is a certainty;
an absolute certainty; it's a dead cert;
the quality of being impossible to avoid or evade;
the quality of being unavoidable;
the quality of being predictable with great confidence;
the quality of being final or definitely settled; the finality of death;
something clearly established;
the quality of being beyond question or dispute or doubt;
the quality of being undeniable and not worth arguing about;
capability of being demonstrated or logically proved;
the quality of being granted as a supposition; of being acknowledged or assumed;
certainty based on an inner conviction; she believed in the importance of moral absolutes and moral certainty; the prosecutor had a moral certainty that the prisoner was guilty;
the quality of being predictable;
the quality of being probable; a probable event or the most probable event; for a while mutiny seemed a probability; going by past experience there was a high probability that the visitors were lost;
the likelihood of a thing occurring rather than not occurring;
the probability of a specified outcome;
being unsettled or in doubt or dependent on chance; the uncertainty of the outcome; the precariousness of his income;
something that is a sure to occur; a foregone conclusion; predicting his success was a slam dunk;
uncertainty about the truth or factuality or existence of something; the dubiousness of his claim; there is no question about the validity of the enterprise;
the quality of being vague and poorly defined;
the quality of being inconclusive;
lacking predictability;
the quality of being improbable; impossibility should never be confused with improbability; the improbability of such rare coincidences;
the improbability of a specified outcome;
the quality of happening accidentally and by lucky chance;
the quality of being a conclusion or opinion based on supposition and conjecture rather than on fact or investigation; her work is highly contentious because of its speculativeness and lack of supporting evidence;
the quality of being actual or based on fact; the realm of factuality must be distinguished from the realm of imagination;
the quality of being contrary to fact;
the quality of being concrete (not abstract);
the quality of being perceivable by touch;
the quality of being intangible and not perceptible by touch;
adhereing to the concrete construal of something;
the quality of being physical; consisting of matter;
the quality of being substantial or having substance;
the quality of not being physical; not consisting of matter;
lacking substance or reality;
something with no concrete substance; his dreams all turned to smoke; it was just smoke and mirrors;
the quality of being considered apart from a specific instance or object;
the quality possessed by something that is real;
the quality possessed by something that is unreal;
