a verse line having five metrical feet;
a verse line having six metrical feet;
a verse line having eight metrical feet;
a verse line having eight syllables or a poem of octosyllabic lines;
a verse line having ten syllables;
correspondence in the sounds of two or more lines (especially final sounds);
a rhyme between words in the same line;
use of the same consonant at the beginning of each stressed syllable in a line of verse; around the rock the ragged rascal ran;
the repetition of similar vowels in the stressed syllables of successive words;
the repetition of consonants (or consonant patterns) especially at the ends of words;
a two-syllable rhyme; endedand blendedform a double rhyme;
a stanza form having seven lines of iambic pentameter; introduced by Chaucer;
a stanza of eight lines of heroic verse with the rhyme scheme abababcc;
an imperfect rhyme (e.g., loveand move);
a use of language that creates a literary effect (but often without regard for literal significance);
an abrupt change within a sentence from one syntactic structure to another;
the omission of conjunctions where they would normally be used;
the repeated use of the same word or word pattern as a rhetorical device;
repetition of the final words of a sentence or line at the beginning of the next;
repetition after intervening words;
repetition of a group of words in reverse order;
recapitulation of the main ideas of a speech (especially in reverse order);
repetition of the ends of two or more successive sentences, verses, etc.;
the doubling of a word or phrase (as for rhetorical effect);
(rhetoric) repetition to gain special emphasis or extend meaning;
repetition of a word in a different case or inflection in the same sentence; My own heart's heart;
repetition of a word or phrase at the beginning of successive clauses;
using a pronoun or similar word instead of repeating a word used earlier;
repetition of a word or phrase at the beginning and another at the end of successive clauses, i.e., simultaneous use of anaphora and epistrophe;
the reversal of the normal order of words;
the use of a word in a sense opposite to its normal sense (especially in irony);
the juxtaposition of contrasting words or ideas to give a feeling of balance;
substitution of a title for a name;
mentioning something by saying it will not be mentioned;
breaking off in the middle of a sentence (as by writers of realistic conversations);
address to an absent or imaginary person;
strained or paradoxical use of words either in error (as blatantto mean flagrant) or deliberately (as in a mixed metaphor: blind mouths);
inversion in the second of two parallel phrases;
arrangement of clauses in ascending order of forcefulness;
interchange of subject and predicate of a proposition;
(theater) irony that occurs when the meaning of the situation is understood by the audience but not by the characters in the play;
an exclamatory rhetorical device; O tempore! O mores;
special and significant stress by means of position or repetition e.g.;
a substitution of part of speech or gender or number or tense etc. (e.g., editorial wefor I);
immediate rephrasing for intensification or justification; Seems, madam! Nay, it is;
a rhetorical device in which the speaker reproaches the audience in order to incite or convince them;
use of two conjoined nouns instead of a noun and modifier;
reversal of the syntactic relation of two words (as in her beauty's face);
reversal of normal word order (as in cheese I love);
use of a series of subjects with a single predicate;
use of a series of parallel clauses (as in I came, I saw, I conquered);
reversal of normal order of two words or sentences etc. (as in bred and born);
understatement for rhetorical effect (especially when expressing an affirmative by negating its contrary); saying I was not a little upsetwhen you mean I was very upsetis an example of litotes;
using words that imitate the sound they denote;
suggesting by deliberately concise treatment that much of significance is omitted;
juxtaposing words having a common derivation (as in sense and sensibility);
using several conjunctions in close succession, especially where some might be omitted (as in he ran and jumped and laughed for joy);
anticipating and answering objections in advance;
a comparison comprising a well-known quotation followed by a facetious sequel;
language used in a figurative or nonliteral sense;
an elaborate poetic image or a far-fetched comparison of very dissimilar things;
a trope that involves incongruity between what is expected and what occurs;
extravagant exaggeration;
conventional metaphoric name for something, used especially in Old English and Old Norse poetry;
a figure of speech in which an expression is used to refer to something that it does not literally denote in order to suggest a similarity;
a metaphor that has occurred so often that it has become a new meaning of the expression (e.g., he is a snakemay once have been a metaphor but after years of use it has died and become a new sense of the word snake);
a combination of two or more metaphors that together produce a ridiculous effect;
a metaphor that exploits a similarity between experiences in different sense modalities;
substituting the name of an attribute or feature for the name of the thing itself (as in they counted heads);
substituting metonymy of one figurative sense for another;
conjoining contradictory terms (as in deafening silence);
representing an abstract quality or idea as a person or creature;
a figure of speech that expresses a resemblance between things of different kinds (usually formed with likeor as);
substituting a more inclusive term for a less inclusive one or vice versa;
use of a word to govern two or more words though agreeing in number or case etc. with only one;
use of a word to govern two or more words though appropriate to only one; Mr. Pickwick took his hat and his leaveis an example of zeugma;
communication that relies on hearing;
(language) communication by word of mouth; his speech was garbled; he uttered harsh language; he recorded the spoken language of the streets;
the words that are spoken; I listened to his words very closely;
the use of uttered sounds for auditory communication;
the exchange of spoken words; they were perfectly comfortable together without speech;
the sound made by the vibration of vocal folds modified by the resonance of the vocal tract; a singer takes good care of his voice; the giraffe cannot make any vocalizations;
(phonetics) an individual sound unit of speech without concern as to whether or not it is a phoneme of some language;
(linguistics) the phonemes (or strings of phonemes) that constitute the various allomorphs of a morpheme;
(linguistics) one of a small set of speech sounds that are distinguished by the speakers of a particular language;
(linguistics) any of various acoustically different forms of the same phoneme;
a vowel whose quality or length is changed to indicate linguistic distinctions (such as sing sang sung song);
a degree of ablaut;
a vowel sound that starts near the articulatory position for one vowel and moves toward the position for another;
a speech sound made with the vocal tract open;
the system of accentuation used in a particular language;
the system of consonants used in a particular language;
the morphophonemics of a particular language;
the system of phonemes recognized in a language;
the system of phones used in a particular language;
the pattern of syllable formation in a particular language;
a system of tenses used in a particular language;
the system of tones used in a particular language or dialect of a tone language;
the system of vowels used in a particular language;
a neutral middle vowel; occurs in unstressed syllables;
