a noisy mock serenade (made by banging pans and kettles) to a newly married couple;
music written for a ballet;
music to dance to;
music written in the bolero rhythm of the beguine dance;
music written in the rhythm of the bolero dance;
music composed for dancing the carioca;
music composed for dancing the conga;
guitar music composed for dancing the flamenco;
music composed in quadruple time for dancing the gavotte;
music composed in duple time for dancing the habanera;
music for dancing the hornpipe;
music in three-four time for dancing a jig;
music in triple time for dancing the landler;
music composed for dancing the mazurka;
a stately piece of music composed for dancing the minuet; often incorporated into a sonata or suite;
music in march time composed for dancing the paso doble; often played at bull fights;
music composed for dancing the pavane;
music performed for dancing the polka;
music for dancing the quadrille;
music composed for dancing a reel;
syncopated music in duple time for dancing the rumba;
music composed for dancing the samba;
music composed for dancing the saraband;
music performed for dancing the schottische;
20th century music that uses a definite order of notes as a thematic basis for a musical composition;
music (especially dance music) that has a syncopated rhythm;
a type of serial music introduced by Arnold Schoenberg; uses a tone row formed by the twelve semitones of the chromatic scale (and inverted or backward versions of the row);
music written in duple time for dancing the tango;
music composed in six-eight time for dancing the tarantella;
a style of fast heavy electronic dance music usually without vocals;
music composed in triple time for waltzing;
genre of music written for marching; Sousa wrote the best marches;
brisk marching music suitable for troops marching in a military parade;
military march accompanying quick time;
martial music with variations; to be played by bagpipes;
a march to be played for processions;
a slow march to be played for funeral processions;
a march to be played for a wedding procession;
any genre of music having wide appeal (but usually only for a short time);
popular dance music (especially in the late 1970s); melodic with a regular bass beat; intended mainly for dancing at discotheques;
popular dance music of Brazil; derived from the practices of the macumba religious cult;
music of general appeal to teenagers; a bland watered-down version of rock'n'roll with more rhythm and harmony and an emphasis on romantic love;
the traditional and typically anonymous music that is an expression of the life of people in a community;
a simple style of folk music heard mostly in the southern United States; usually played on stringed instruments;
a genre of popular music composed for ballroom dancing;
music with a syncopated melody (usually for the piano);
a style of dance music popular in the 1920s; similar to New Orleans jazz but played by large bands;
a kind of danceable music popular among black South Africans; includes a whistle among its instruments;
folk music consisting of a genre of a cappella music originating with Black slaves in the United States and featuring call and response; influential on the development of other genres of popular music (especially soul);
a genre (usually a cappella) of Black vocal-harmony music of the 1950s that evolved in New York City from gospel singing; characterized by close four-part harmonies; the name derived from some of the nonsense syllables sung by the backup;
a secular form of gospel that was a major Black musical genre in the 1960s and 1970s; soul was politically significant during the Civil Rights movement;
a type of country music played at a rapid tempo on banjos and guitars;
country music originating in mountainous regions of southern United States;
music performed for square dancing;
music of southern Louisiana that combines French dance melodies with Caribbean music and blues;
a genre of popular music that originated in New Orleans around 1900 and developed through increasingly complex styles;
an early form of modern jazz (originating around 1940);
an instrumental version of the blues (especially for piano);
jazz that is restrained and fluid and marked by intricate harmonic structures often lagging slightly behind the beat;
an earthy type of jazz combining it with blues and soul; has a heavy bass line that accentuates the first beat in the bar;
jazz that is emotionally charged and intense and marked by strong rhythms and improvisation;
any of various styles of jazz that appeared after 1940;
genre of African-American music of the 1980s and 1990s in which rhyming lyrics are chanted to a musical accompaniment; several forms of rap have emerged;
a combination of blues and jazz that was developed in the United States by Black musicians; an important precursor of rock 'n' roll;
a fusion of black music and country music that was popular in the 1950s; sometimes described as blues with a country beat;
a genre of popular music originating in the 1950s; a blend of black rhythm-and-blues with white country-and-western ; rock is a generic term for the range of styles that evolved out of rock'n'roll.;
loud and harsh sounding rock music with a strong beat; lyrics usually involve violent or fantastic imagery;
a style of rock music that emerged in the 1970s; associated with attempts to combine rock with jazz and other forms; intended for listening and not dancing;
a musical style that emerged in the 1960s; rock music inspired by or related to drug-induced experience;
rock music with deliberately offensive lyrics expressing anger and social alienation; in part a reaction against progressive rock;
traditional jazz as revived in the 1950s;
a style of jazz played by big bands popular in the 1930s; flowing rhythms but less complex than later styles of jazz;
popular music originating in the West Indies; repetitive bass riffs and regular chords played on the off beat by a guitar;
a style of popular music in the 1950s; based on American folk music and played on guitars and improvised percussion instruments;
a way of expressing something (in language or art or music etc.) that is characteristic of a particular person or group of people or period; all the reporters were expected to adopt the style of the newspaper;
the manner of speaking to another individual; he failed in his manner of address to the captain;
a break or check in the voice (usually a sign of strong emotion);
the use of closed-class words instead of inflections: e.g., the father of the brideinstead of the bride's father;
triteness or triviality of style;
the juxtaposition of morbid and farcical elements (in writing or drama) to give a disturbing effect;
an affected elegance of style that was introduced into Spanish literature by the poet Gongora;
an artistic device or effect; the architect's brilliant conceit was to build the house around the tree;
(music) the section of a composition or movement (especially in sonata form) where the major musical themes are developed and elaborated;
something in an artistic work designed to achieve a particular effect;
medical jargon;
using the technical language of ecology to make the user seem ecologically aware;
powerful and effective language; his eloquence attracted a large congregation; fluency in spoken and written English is essential; his oily smoothness concealed his guilt from the police;
any artificially elegant style of language;
the jargon of European community documents and regulations;
a want of animation or brilliance; the almost self-conscious flatness of Hemingway's style;
the style of expressing yourself; he suggested a better formulation; his manner of expression showed how much he cared;
incomprehensible or pompous jargon of specialists;
high-flown style; excessive use of verbal ornamentation; the grandiosity of his prose; an excessive ornateness of language;
using the abbreviated style of headline writers;
an expression of respect; the Japanese use many honorifics;
specialized technical terminology characteristic of a particular subject;
the style in which newspapers are written;
a style that uses the abstruse technical vocabulary of the law;
your characteristic style or manner of expressing yourself orally; his manner of speaking was quite abrupt; her speech was barren of southernisms; I detected a slight accent in his speech;
an expressive style of music;
