prior to a specified or implied time; she has already graduated;
used as intensifiers; realis sometimes used informally for really; rattlingis informal; she was very gifted; he played very well; a really enjoyable evening; I'm real sorry about it; a rattling good yarn;
exceedingly; extremely; she plays fabulously well;
(Southern regional intensive) very; to a great degree; the baby is mighty cute; he's mighty tired; it is powerful humid; that boy is powerful big now; they have a right nice place; they rejoiced mightily;
completely or thoroughly; when I'm good and ready;
intensifier, very colloquial; what took you so fucking long?;
very; he was much annoyed;
from this time forth; from now on; henceforth she will be known as Mrs. Smith;
following this in time or order or place; after this; hereafter you will no longer receive an allowance;
in a future life or state; hope to win salvation hereafter;
under the terms of this agreement;
only a moment ago; he has just arrived; the sun just now came out;
without any delay; he was killed outright;
to a moderate degree; he was mildly interested;
to a small degree; somewhat; it's a bit warm; felt a little better; a trifle smaller;
(old-fashioned or informal) in a little while; see you anon;
in the near future; the doctor will soon be here; the book will appear shortly; she will arrive presently; we should have news before long;
as soon as possible;
for a short time; he was at the airport shortly before she was expected to arrive;
at a short distance; the hem fell shortly below her knees;
at any moment; she will be with you momently;
side by side and close together; the troops marched shoulder-to-shoulder;
with the least delay; the soonest I can arrive is 3 P.M.;
in a spirited or lively manner; with animation and vivacity;
in a merry sportive manner;
in a stormy or violent manner;
many times at short intervals; we often met over a cup of coffee;
more often or more frequently;
at another time; ever and anon;
not often; we rarely met;
in a manner differing from the usual or expected; had a curiously husky voice; he's behaving rather peculiarly;
to a moderately sufficient extent or degree; pretty big; pretty bad; jolly decent of him; the shoes are priced reasonably; he is fairly clever with computers;
to a degree that exceeds the bounds or reason or moderation; his prices are unreasonably high;
to a small degree or extent; his arguments were somewhat self-contradictory; the children argued because one slice of cake was slightly larger than the other;
in a moving manner; she sang movingly;
in a widespread way; oxidation ponds are extensively used for sewage treatment in the Midwest;
with respect to its inherent nature; this statement is interesting per se;
without question and beyond doubt; it was decidedly too expensive; she told him off in spades; by all odds they should win;
in accordance with truth or fact or reality; she was now truly American; a genuinely open society; they don't really listen to us;
(used as an interjection) an expression of surprise or skepticism or irony etc.; Wants to marry the butler? Indeed!;
in truth (often tends to intensify); they said the car would break down and indeed it did; it is very cold indeed; was indeed grateful; indeed, the rain may still come; he did so do it!;
in a difficult or vulnerable position; he resigned and left me in the lurch;
in fact (used as intensifiers or sentence modifiers); in truth, moral decay hastened the decline of the Roman Empire; really, you shouldn't have done it; a truly awful book;
an archaic word originally meaning in truthbut now usually used to express disbelief;
in the uterus; the child was infected in utero from the mother;
in a vacuum;
in isolation and without reference to anything else;
as might be expected; naturally, the lawyer sent us a huge bill;
in a manner at variance with what is natural or normal; The early Church not unnaturally adopted the position that failure to see the messianic character of his work was really caused by the people's own blindness;
without doubt or question; they were clearly lost; history has clearly shown the folly of that policy;
in a manner that is unclear;
unmistakably (plainis often used informally for plainly); the answer is obviously wrong; she was in bed and evidently in great pain; he was manifestly too important to leave off the guest list; it is all patently nonsense; she has apparently been living here for some time; I thought he owned the property, but apparently not; You are plainly wrong; he is plain stubborn;
from appearances alone; irrigation often produces bumper crops from apparently desert land; the child is seemingly healthy but the doctor is concerned; had been ostensibly frank as to his purpose while really concealing it-Thomas Hardy; on the face of it the problem seems minor;
anew; she tried again; they rehearsed the scene again;
together with this;
without advance planning; they met accidentally;
in a way that was not expected; her brother showed up at the wedding out of the blue;
so as not to obstruct or hinder; put that box out of the way so that no one trips on it;
dealt with; disposed of; I'm so relieved that my midterm is out of the way;
murdered; the mob boss wanted his rival out of the way;
in a remote location or at a distance from the usual route; the restaurant is top-notch, but a little out of the way;
improper; amiss;
extraordinary; unusual; such erratic behavior was out of the way for him;
forming a hindrance, impediment, or obstruction; she might have succeeded in her ambition, had not circumstances been in her way;
in distinction from others; a program specifically for teenagers; he is interested specifically in poisonous snakes;
without distinction of one from others; he is interested in snakes in general;
without specificity; nonspecifically staining substances;
by good fortune; fortunately the weather was good;
in an unexpectedly lucky way; happily he was not injured;
in an unfortunate way; sadly he died before he could see his grandchild;
by bad luck; unfortunately it rained all day; alas, I cannot stay;
(used to introduce a logical conclusion) from that fact or reason or as a result; therefore X must be true; the eggs were fresh and hence satisfactory; we were young and thence optimistic; it is late and thus we must go; the witness is biased and so cannot be trusted;
(used as a sentence connector) therefore or consequently;
from this time; a year hence it will be forgotten;
from this place; get thee hence!;
from that place or from there; proceeded thence directly to college; flew to Helsinki and thence to Moscow; roads that lead therefrom;
from that circumstance or source; atomic formulas and all compounds thence constructible- W.V.Quine; a natural conclusion follows thence; public interest and a policy deriving therefrom; typhus fever results therefrom;
(in formal usage, especially legal usage) for that or for it; ordering goods and enclosing payment therefor; a refund therefor;
affecting the pursuit of a vocation or occupation; vocationally trained;
involving close contact; confronting each other; the boy and the policeman suddenly came face-to-face at the corner; they spoke face to face;
(of two persons) in direct encounter; preferred to settle the matter one-on-one; interviewed her person-to-person;
within each other's presence; she met the president face-to-face;
directly facing each other; the two photographs lay face-to-face on the table; lived all their lives in houses face-to-face across the street; they sat opposite at the table;
face-to-face with; literally face to face; they sat vis-a-vis at the table; I found myself vis-a-vis a burly policeman;
without the intrusion of a third person; in intimate privacy; we talked tete-a-tete;
perhaps; indicating possibility of being more remarkable (greater or better or sooner) than; will yield 10% if not more; pretty if not actually beautiful; let's meet tonight if not sooner;
in addition; agreed to provide essentials but nothing beyond;
farther along in space or time or degree; through the valley and beyond; to the eighth grade but not beyond; will be influential in the 1990s and beyond;
on the farther side from the observer; a pond with a hayfield beyond;
in other respects or ways; he is otherwise normal; the funds are not otherwise available; an otherwise hopeless situation;
in addition, by way of addition; furthermore; he serves additionally as the CEO;
to an extreme degree; extremely cold; extremely unpleasant;
extremely; she was drop-dead gorgeous;
in excess or without limit; amazed beyond measure;
(used as intensives) extremely; she was madly in love; deadly dull; deadly earnest; deucedly clever; insanely jealous;
extremely; she was inordinately smart; it will be an extraordinarily painful step to negotiate;
by a considerable margin; she was by far the smartest student; it was far and away the best meal he had ever eaten;
outstandingly superior to; in intelligence he was head and shoulders above the others in his class;
to a degree exceeding normal or proper limits; too big;
in addition; he has a Mercedes, too;
