according to the constitution; this was constitutionally ruled out;
in an unconstitutional manner; the president acted unconstitutionally;
in a democratic manner; based on democratic principles; it was decided democratically; democratically elected government;
in an undemocratic manner; undemocratically, he made all the important decisions without his colleagues;
in an aloof manner; the local gentry and professional classes had held aloof for the school had accepted their sons readily enough;
in terms of integers; the time was digitally displayed;
by means of the fingers; the exam was carried out digitally;
with respect to economic science; economically this proposal makes no sense;
with respect to the economic system; economically the country is worse off;
in an economical manner;
by electronic means; the door opens electronically;
with respect to ethnicity; the neighborhood is ethnically diverse;
by federal government; it's federally regulated;
by genetic mechanisms; genetically passed down talents;
in a graphic way; he described the event graphically;
in an idiographic manner; it's written ideographically;
in an idyllic manner;
by industrial means; industrially produced;
in an injurious manner;
in an irrevocable manner;
in a legal manner; he acted legally;
by hand; this car shifts manually;
involving medical practice; medically trained nurses; medically correct treatment;
in a medicinal manner;
in name only; nominally he is the boss;
occurring within the predicate phrase; predicatively used adjectives;
in a professorial manner; she behaved very professorially;
by the province; through the province; provincially controlled;
in a realistic manner; the figure was realistically painted;
doing something reprehensible or showing clear evidence of having done something reprehensible; he was caught red-handed;
in a reversible manner; reversibly convertible;
in a rewarding manner;
in a royal manner; they were royally treated;
in a sacrilegious manner;
with respect to stage scenery; scenically stunning;
with respect to scholastic activities; scholastically apt;
in a serial manner; serially composed music;
by or with respect to society; socially accepted norms;
in a social manner; socially unpopular;
by means of symbols; symbolically expressed;
with regard to technical skill and the technology available; a technically brilliant solution;
with regard to technique; technically lagging behind the Japanese; a technically brilliant boxer;
according to the exact meaning; according to the facts; technically, a bank's reserves belong to the stockholders; technically, the term is no longer used by experts;
with regard to temporal order; temporally processed;
at the end; terminally ill;
to a land environment; terrestrially adapted;
with respect to territory; territorially important;
with regard to thematic content; thematically related;
for therapeutic purposes;
by means of heat from the interior of the earth;
by means of heat or with respect to thermal properties;
in a typical manner; Tom was typically hostile;
in a manner that is not typical; she was atypically quiet;
by means of language; verbally expressive;
as a verb; he had a habit of using nouns verbally;
in a vocal manner; she defended herself vocally;
without words; they communicated nonverbally;
throughout the world; this is globally significant;
by electricity; electrically controlled;
with respect to chemistry; chemically different substances; chemically related;
with chemicals; chemically fertilized;
by legislation; legislatively determined;
in a bilingual manner; she grew up bilingually;
in a linear manner; linearly polarized radiation; it grew linearly;
with respect to longitude; longitudinally measured;
in a magical manner; it disappeared magically;
by bacteria; spreads bacterially;
by the theory of relativity; this is relativistically impossible;
with respect to race; racially integrated;
by municipality; municipally funded;
by government; governmentally determined policy;
in a professional manner; professionally trained staff;
with regard to space; spatially limited;
with regard to meaning; semantically empty messages;
in a limited manner;
with respect to language; linguistically impaired children; a lingually diverse population;
with respect to sociolinguistics; sociolinguistically fascinating;
with respect to the science of linguistics; linguistically interesting data;
by comparing languages; she studied the phenomenon cross-linguistically;
in financial matters; fiscally irresponsible;
in an algebraic manner; algebraically determined;
in a polyphonic manner; polyphonically composed;
in a poetic manner; poetically expressed;
by phonetics; phonetically realized;
by phonemics; phonemically transcribed;
as a person; he is personally repulsive;
in the flesh; without involving anyone else; I went there personally; he appeared in person;
concerning the speaker; personally, I find him stupid;
in a philosophic manner; she took it philosophically;
extremely; infernally clever; hellishly dangerous;
with respect to pathology; pathologically interesting results;
with respect to graphic aspects; graphically interesting designs;
with unfortunate consequences; catastrophically complex;
in an optical manner; optically distorted;
with respect to vision; visually distorted;
in the viscera; he is bleeding viscerally;
in the brain; bleeding cerebrally;
in an intellectual manner; cerebrally active;
in a mystical manner; chant mystically;
with respect to biology; biologically related;
