in an unfortunate or deplorable manner; he was sadly neglected; it was woefully inadequate;
with respect to denomination; denominationally diverse audiences;
with respect to the cortex; cortically induced arousal;
in a focal manner; the submucosa was focally infiltrated;
with respect to the hypothalamus; hypothalamically controlled secretions;
into the skin;
in an intramuscular way; administer the drug intramuscularly;
in an entertaining and amusing manner; Hollywood has grown too sophisticated to turn out anything really amusingly bad these days;
on a floor below; the tenants live downstairs;
on a floor above; they lived upstairs;
with respect to the mind; she's a bit weak upstairs;
with the wind; in the direction the wind is blowing; they flew downwind;
in the direction opposite to the direction the wind is blowing; they flew upwind;
away from the wind; they were sailing windward;
toward the wind; they were sailing leeward;
spatially or metaphorically from a higher to a lower level or position; don't fall down; rode the lift up and skied down; prices plunged downward;
away from a more central or a more northerly place; was sent down to work at the regional office; worked down on the farm; came down for the wedding; flew down to Florida;
paid in cash at time of purchase; put ten dollars down on the necklace;
in an inactive or inoperative state; the factory went down during the strike; the computer went down again;
to a lower intensity; he slowly phased down the light until the stage was completely black;
from an earlier time; the story was passed down from father to son;
spatially or metaphorically from a lower to a higher position; look up!; the music surged up; the fragments flew upwards; prices soared upwards; upwardly mobile;
to a later time; they moved the meeting date up; from childhood upward;
to a more central or a more northerly place; was transferred up to headquarters; up to Canada for a vacation;
nearer to the speaker; he walked up and grabbed my lapels;
to a higher intensity; he turned up the volume;
toward the source or against the current;
away from the source or with the current;
toward or in the defending team's end of the playing field; he caught the ball and ran downfield 15 yards;
thoroughgoing; he is outright dishonest;
without reservation or concealment; she asked him outright for a divorce;
without restrictions or stipulations or further payments; buy outright;
at or to or in the direction of one's home or family; He stays home on weekends; after the game the children brought friends home for supper; I'll be home tomorrow; came riding home in style; I hope you will come home for Christmas; I'll take her home; don't forget to write home;
at, to, or toward the place where you reside; he worked at home;
on the home team's field; they played at home last night;
to the fullest extent; to the heart; drove the nail home; drove his point home; his comments hit home;
on or to the point aimed at; the arrow struck home;
toward home; fought his way homeward through the deep snow;
on the contrary; rather than disappoint the children, he did two quick tricks before he left; he didn't call; rather (or instead), he wrote her a letter; used English terms instead of Latin ones;
to the degree or extent that; insofar as it can be ascertained, the horse lung is comparable to that of man; so far as it is reasonably practical he should practice restraint;
in a mordacious manner; she taunted him mordaciously;
used to form the comparative of some adjectives and adverbs; more interesting; more beautiful; more quickly;
used to form the comparative of some adjectives and adverbs; less interesting; less expensive; less quickly;
comparative of much; to a greater degree or extent; he works more now; they eat more than they should;
comparative of little; she walks less than she should; he works less these days;
not much; he talked little about his family;
before the usual time or the time expected; she graduated early; the house was completed ahead of time;
later than usual or than expected; the train arrived late; we awoke late; the children came late to school; notice came so tardily that we almost missed the deadline; I belatedly wished her a happy birthday;
in good time; he awoke betimes that morning;
during an early stage; early on in her career;
as far as that is concerned; for that matter I don't care either;
(old-fashioned) at or from or to a great distance; far; we traveled afar; we could see the ship afar off; the Magi came from afar;
at or to or from a great distance in space; he traveled far; strayed far from home; sat far away from each other;
remote in time; if we could see far into the future; all that happened far in the past;
to a considerable degree; very much; a far far better thing that I do; felt far worse than yesterday; eyes far too close together;
at or to a certain point or degree; I can only go so far before I have to give up; how far can we get with this kind of argument?;
to an advanced stage or point; a young man who will go very far;
to a great degree or by a great distance; very much (right smartis regional in the United States); way over budget; way off base; the other side of the hill is right smart steeper than the side we are on;
over great areas or distances; everywhere; he traveled far and wide; the news spread far and wide; people came from far and near; searched for the child far and near;
in a fictional manner (created by the imagination);
in a false manner intended to mislead;
in a delicate manner; finely shaped features; her fine drawn body;
in an elegant manner; finely costumed actors;
before anything else; first we must consider the garter snake;
in the second place; second, we must consider the economy;
in the third place; third we must consider unemployment;
from first to last; the play was excellent end-to-end;
at the beginning; at first he didn't notice anything strange;
immediately; it was love at first sight;
as a first impression; at first blush the offer seemed attractive;
the initial time; when Felix first saw a garter snake;
continuing in the same way;
out into view; came forth from the crowd; put my ideas forth;
forward in time or order or degree; from that time forth; from the sixth century onward;
to or in a foreign country; they had never travelled abroad;
in reality; she is very kind at heart;
in a general fashion; he talked at large about his plans;
not less than; at least two hours studying the manual; a tumor at least as big as an orange;
not more than; spend at most $20 on the lunch;
if nothing else (leastwiseis informal and leastwaysis colloquial); at least he survived; they felt--at any rate Jim felt--relieved though still wary; the influence of economists--or at any rate of economics--is far-reaching ;
in an unhurried way or at one's convenience; read the manual at your leisure; he traveled leisurely;
immediately; she called right after dinner;
at a particular time in the past; just then the bugle sounded;
in a punctual manner; he did his homework promptly;
at once (usually modifies an undesirable occurrence); he promptly forgot the address;
with little or no delay; the rescue squad arrived promptly; come here, quick!;
under the best of conditions; at best we'll lose only the money;
under the worst of conditions; at worst we'll go to jail;
in a very agitated manner; as if possessed by an evil spirit;
in a furtive manner; the soldiers were furtively crawling through the night;
of one mind; without dissent; the Senate unanimously approved the bill; we voted unanimously;
in a responsible manner; we must act responsibly;
in an irresponsible manner; he acted irresponsibly;
without favoring one party, in a fair evenhanded manner; deal fairly with one another;
under normal conditions; usually she was late;
in the usual manner; as usual, she arrived late;
to a remarkable degree or extent; she was unusually tall;
in the recent past; he was in Paris recently; lately the rules have been enforced; as late as yesterday she was fine; feeling better of late; the spelling was first affected, but latterly the meaning also;
in an erratic unpredictable manner; economic changes are proceeding erratically;
like a girl; she was girlishly shy;
