(Greek mythology) a mountain in central Greece where (according to Greek mythology) the Muses lived; known as the mythological home of music and poetry; Liakoura is the modern name of Mount Parnassus;
a portion of a natural object; they analyzed the river into three parts; he needed a piece of granite;
a body having finite mass and internal structure but negligible dimensions;
the location in a range of mountains of a geological formation that is lower than the surrounding peaks; we got through the pass before it started to snow;
a line or route along which something travels or moves; the hurricane demolished houses in its path; the track of an animal; the course of the river;
a major waterfall in northeastern Brazil;
a small constellation near the South Pole between Tucana and Ara;
a river in Mississippi that flows southward to the Gulf of Mexico;
a small smooth rounded rock;
a tributary of the Rio Grande that flows southeastward from New Mexico through western Texas;
a river that flows through central North Carolina and northeastern South Carolina to the Atlantic Ocean;
a constellation in the northern hemisphere near Andromeda and Pisces;
a more or less level land surface representing an advanced stage of erosion undisturbed by crustal movements;
a large mass of land projecting into a body of water;
a river in central Maine flowing into Penobscot Bay;
an inlet of the Atlantic in eastern Maine;
a hole made in something; a perforation of the eardrum;
a small uninhabited Mediterranean islet claimed by both Morocco and Spain;
ground that is permanently frozen;
a conspicuous constellation in the northern hemisphere; between Auriga and Cassiopeia and crossed by the Milky Way;
a shallow arm of the Arabian Sea between Iran and the Arabian peninsula; the Persian Gulf oil fields are among the most productive in the world;
a rock created by petrifaction; an organic object infiltrated with mineral matter and preserved in its original form;
the larger of the two satellites of Mars;
a constellation in the southern hemisphere near Tucana and Sculptor;
an electron that is emitted from an atom or molecule by an incident photon;
a quantum of electromagnetic radiation; an elementary particle that is its own antiparticle;
the intensely luminous surface of a star (especially the sun);
a constellation in the southern hemisphere near Dorado and Columba;
a gentle slope leading from the base of a mountain to a region of flat land;
a type of glaciation characteristic of Alaska; large valley glaciers meet to form an almost stagnant sheet of ice;
a mountain peak in the Rockies in central Colorado (14,109 feet high);
the two promontories at the eastern end of the Strait of Gibraltar; according to legend they were formed by Hercules;
an area planted with pine trees or related conifers;
a river in western Thailand; a major tributary of the Chao Phraya;
a meson involved in holding the nucleus together; produced as the result of high-energy particle collision;
a large faint zodiacal constellation; between Aquarius and Aries;
a mountain in the Andes in Argentina (22,241 feet high);
a sizeable hole (usually in the ground); they dug a pit to bury the body;
an alluvial deposit that contains particles of some valuable mineral;
the beach at a seaside resort;
extensive tract of level open land; they emerged from the woods onto a vast open plain; he longed for the fields of his youth;
(astronomy) any of the nine large celestial bodies in the solar system that revolve around the sun and shine by reflected light; Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, and Pluto in order of their proximity to the sun; viewed from the constellation Hercules, all the planets rotate around the sun in a counterclockwise direction;
any celestial body (other than comets or satellites) that revolves around a star;
a nebula that was once thought to be a star with its planets but is now thought to be a very hot star surrounded by an expanding envelope of ionized gases that emit a fluorescent glow because of intense radiation from the star;
one of many small solid celestial bodies thought to have existed at an early stage in the development of the solar system;
a small cellular inclusion consisting of a ring of DNA that is not in a chromosome but is capable of autonomous replication;
a rigid layer of the Earth's crust that is believed to drift slowly;
a river in Nebraska that flows eastward to become a tributary of the Missouri River;
a star cluster in the constellation Taurus;
a small planet and the farthest known planet from the sun; it has the most elliptical orbit of all the planets; Pluto was discovered by Clyde Tombaugh in 1930;
a European river; flows into the Adriatic Sea;
a mountain peak in the Tien Shan mountains in northern India (24,406 feet high);
a promontory extending out into a large body of water; they sailed south around the point;
a glacier near the Arctic or Antarctic poles;
the brightest star in Ursa Minor; at the end of the handle of the Little Dipper; the northern axis of the earth points toward it;
low-lying land that has been reclaimed and is protected by dikes (especially in the Netherlands);
the brightest star in Gemini; close to Castor;
a stretch of open water surrounded by ice (especially in Arctic seas);
a small lake; the pond was too small for sailing;
a small body of standing water (rainwater) or other liquid; there were puddles of muddy water in the road after the rain; the body lay in a pool of blood;
an elementary particle with positive charge; interaction of a positron and an electron results in annihilation;
a pit or hole produced by wear or weathering (especially in a road surface);
a river in the east central United States; rises in West Virginia in the Appalachian Mountains and flows eastward, forming the boundary between Maryland and Virginia, to the Chesapeake Bay;
a lake in central China that is connected to the Chang Jiang by a canal;
a very steep cliff;
(astronomy) a celestial body (especially a star) relative to other objects in orbit around it;
(microbiology) an infectious protein particle similar to a virus but lacking nucleic acid; thought to be the agent responsible for scrapie and other degenerative diseases of the nervous system;
(microbiology) a hypothetical infectious particle thought to be the cause of scrapie and other degenerative diseases of the central nervous system; consists of nucleic acid in a protective coat of host cell proteins;
the brightest star in Canis Minor;
a natural elevation (especially a rocky one that juts out into the sea);
any large molecule containing chains of amino acids linked by peptide bonds;
a stable particle with positive charge equal to the negative charge of an electron;
the nearest star to the sun; distance: 4.3 light years;
a bay on the northern coast of Alaska where oil was discovered in 1968;
something that has been pruned off of a plant;
calculus in a salivary gland;
an inlet of the North Pacific in northwestern Washington State;
any soft or soggy mass; he pounded it to a pulp;
a degenerate neutron star; small and extremely dense; rotates very fast and emits regular pulses of polarized radiation;
a constellation in the southern hemisphere between Vela and Canis Major that shaped like the stern of a boat;
a Brazilian river; tributary of the Amazon River;
a chain of mountains between France and Spain;
a constellation in the southern hemisphere near Puppis and Antlia;
a planetoid discovered in 2002;
(physics) hypothetical truly fundamental particle in mesons and baryons; there are supposed to be six flavors of quarks (and their antiquarks), which come in pairs; each has an electric charge of +2/3 or -1/3; quarks have not been observed directly but theoretical predictions based on their existence have been confirmed experimentally;
a starlike object that may send out radio waves and other forms of energy; many have large red shifts;
an inlet of the Pacific Ocean off the coast of British Columbia;
an agent that gives or restores life or vigor; the soul is the quickener of the body;
a pit filled with loose wet sand into which objects are sucked down;
a hole in the ground as a nest made by wild rabbits;
any object that radiates energy;
an object that radiates radio waves;
an arc of colored light in the sky caused by refraction of the sun's rays by rain;
a mountain peak in the Karakoram Range in northern Kashmir (25,560 feet high);
a series of hills or mountains; the valley was between two ranges of hills; the plains lay just beyond the mountain range;
land suitable for grazing livestock;
a mountain peak in central Washington; highest peak in the Cascade Range;(14,410feethigh);
a part of a river where the current is very fast;
a river that flows across eastern Virginia into the Tidewater region;
a hole (as in the wall of a building) made by rats;
