any of numerous trees of north temperate regions having light soft wood and flowers borne in catkins;
soft light-colored non-durable wood of the poplar;
poplar of northeastern North America with broad heart-shaped leaves;
a poplar that is widely cultivated in the United States; has white bark and leaves with whitish undersurfaces;
large rapidly growing poplar with faintly lobed dentate leaves grey on the lower surface; native to Europe but introduced and naturalized elsewhere;
large European poplar;
distinguished by its columnar fastigiate shape and erect branches;
any of several North American trees of the genus Populus having a tuft of cottony hairs on the seed;
a common poplar of eastern and central United States; cultivated in United States for its rapid growth and luxuriant foliage and in Europe for timber;
cottonwood of western North America with dark green leaves shining above and rusty or silvery beneath;
North American poplar with large rounded scalloped leaves and brownish bark and wood;
any of several trees of the genus Populus having leaves on flattened stalks so that they flutter in the lightest wind;
Old World aspen with a broad much-branched crown; northwestern Europe and Siberia to North Africa;
slender aspen native to North America;
aspen with a narrow crown; eastern North America;
order of plants distinguished by having a one-celled inferior ovary; many are parasitic or partly parasitic usually on roots;
chiefly tropical herbs or shrubs or trees bearing nuts or one-seeded fruit;
parasitic trees of Indonesia and Malaysia;
parasitic tree of Indonesia and Malaysia having fragrant close-grained yellowish heartwood with insect repelling properties and used, e.g., for making chests;
close-grained fragrant yellowish heartwood of the true sandalwood; has insect repelling properties and is used for carving and cabinetwork;
small genus of Asiatic and American parasitic shrubs;
parasitic shrub of the eastern United States having opposite leaves and insignificant greenish flowers followed by oily dull green olivelike fruits;
small genus of chiefly North American parasitic plants;
woody creeping parasite of western North America having numerous thick powdery leaves and panicles of small dull-white flowers;
quandong trees;
Australian tree with edible flesh and edible nutlike seed;
small genus of chiefly Asiatic parasitic shrubs;
shrub of southeastern United States parasitic on roots of hemlocks having sparse spikes of greenish flowers and pulpy drupes;
oily drupaceous fruit of rabbitwood;
in some classification includes Viscaceae: parasitic or hemiparasitic shrublets or shrubs or small trees of tropical and temperate regions; attach to hosts by haustoria;
type genus of the Loranthaceae: 1 species;
shrub of central and southeastern Europe; partially parasitic on beeches, chestnuts and oaks;
genus of chiefly American plants parasitic on conifers;
small herb with scalelike leaves on reddish-brown stems and berrylike fruits; parasitic on spruce and larch trees;
one species;
a terrestrial evergreen shrub or small tree of western Australia having brilliant yellow-orange flowers; parasitic on roots of grasses;
in some classifications considered a subfamily of Loranthaceae;
type genus of the Viscaceae: Old World evergreen shrubs parasitic on many trees including oaks but especially apple trees, poplars, aspens and cottonwoods;
Old World parasitic shrub having branching greenish stems with leathery leaves and waxy white glutinous berries; the traditional mistletoe of Christmas;
any of various American parasitic plants similar to Old World mistletoe: false mistletoe;
American plants closely resembling Old World mistletoe;
the traditional mistletoe of Christmas in America: grows on deciduous trees and can severely weaken the host plant;
an order of dicotyledonous plants;
chiefly tropical New and Old World deciduous and evergreen trees and shrubs bearing leathery drupes with yellow translucent flesh; most plants produce toxic saponins;
a small Hawaiian tree with hard dark wood;
a genus of tropical shrub or tree;
a tree of the genus Sapindus whose fruit is rich in saponin;
type genus of the Sapindaceae;
deciduous tree of southwestern United States having pulpy fruit containing saponin;
evergreen of tropical America having pulpy fruit containing saponin which was used as soap by Native Americans;
small genus of western African evergreen trees and shrubs bearing fleshy capsular three-seeded fruits edible when neither unripe nor overripe;
widely cultivated in tropical and subtropical regions for its fragrant flowers and colorful fruits; introduced in Jamaica by William Bligh;
tendril-climbing herbs or shrubs whose seeds have a white heart-shaped spot;
tendril-climbing vine;
herbaceous vine of tropical America and Africa;
woody perennial climbing plant with large ornamental seed pods that resemble balloons; tropical India and Africa and America;
longan;
tree of southeastern Asia to Australia grown primarily for its sweet edible fruit resembling litchi nuts; sometimes placed in genera Euphorbia or Nephelium;
genus of tropical Asiatic and African trees;
any of various tree of the genus Harpullia;
fast-growing tree of India and East Indies yielding a wood used especially for building;
Australian tree yielding a variegated tulipwood;
Chinese trees;
Chinese tree cultivated especially in Philippines and India for its edible fruit; sometimes placed in genus Nephelium;
tropical American trees and shrubs bearing berries;
tropical American tree bearing a small edible fruit with green leathery skin and sweet juicy translucent pulp;
a genus of dicotyledonous trees of the family Sapindaceae that are native to Asia and Australia;
Malayan tree bearing spiny red fruit;
East Indian fruit tree bearing fruit similar to but sweeter than that of the rambutan;
widely distributed evergreen shrubs and trees;
type genus of the Buxaceae;
evergreen shrubs or small trees;
large slow-growing evergreen shrub or small tree with multiple stems; extensively used for hedges or borders and topiary figures;
very hard tough close-grained light yellow wood of the box (particularly the common box); used in delicate woodwork: musical instruments and inlays and engraving blocks;
evergreen perennial procumbent subshrubs or herbs;
any plant of the genus Pachysandra; low-growing evergreen herbs or subshrubs having dentate leaves and used as ground cover;
low semi-evergreen perennial herb having small spikes of white or pinkish flowers; native to southern United States but grown elsewhere;
slow-growing Japanese evergreen subshrub having terminal spikes of white flowers; grown as a ground cover;
trees and shrubs and woody vines usually having bright-colored fruits;
any small tree or twining shrub of the genus Celastrus;
genus of woody vines and erect shrubs (type genus of the Celastraceae) that is native chiefly to Asia and Australia: includes bittersweet;
twining shrub of North America having yellow capsules enclosing scarlet seeds;
ornamental Asiatic vine with showy orange-yellow fruit with a scarlet aril; naturalized in North America;
widely distributed chiefly evergreen shrubs or small trees or vines;
any shrubby trees or woody vines of the genus Euonymus having showy usually reddish berries;
small erect deciduous shrub having tough white wood and cathartic bark and fruit;
bushy deciduous shrub with branches having thin wide corky longitudinal wings; brilliant red in autumn; northeastern Asia to central China;
deciduous shrub having purple capsules enclosing scarlet seeds;
upright deciduous plant with crimson pods and seeds; the eastern United States from New York to Florida and Texas;
broad and bushy Asiatic twining shrub with pinkish fruit; many subspecies or varieties;
shrubs and trees with leathery leaves and small white flowers in racemes: genera Cyrilla and Cliftonia;
one species: trees and shrubs having flowers with acute or twisted petals and wingless fruit;
shrub or small tree of southeastern United States to West Indies and Brazil; grown for the slender racemes of white flowers and orange and crimson foliage;
one species: titi;
tree of low-lying coastal areas of southeastern United States having glossy leaves and racemes of fragrant white flowers;
heathlike shrubs;
crowberries;
a low evergreen shrub with small purple flowers and black berrylike fruit;
a family of trees and shrubs of order Sapindales including the maples;
type genus of the Aceraceae; trees or shrubs having winged fruit;
