someone who sends a telegram;
an upstart who makes conceited, sardonic, insolent comments;
term of address for a disrespectful and annoying male; look here, junior, it's none of your business;
a small person; a mere wisp of a girl;
someone who is believed to heal through magical powers;
someone who identifies and punishes people for their opinions;
a depositor who withdraws funds previously deposited;
a student who withdraws from the educational institution in which he or she was enrolled;
a contestant who withdraws from competition;
a drug addict who is discontinuing the use of narcotics;
an individualist who withdraws from social interaction;
an authority who withdraws permission;
a person who restrains or checks or holds back;
a person who refrains from granting; a withholder of payments;
an opponent who resists with force or resolution; obstinate withstanders of innovation;
someone who sees an event and reports what happened;
(law) a person who attests to the genuineness of a document or signature by adding their own signature;
(law) a person who testifies under oath in a court of law;
an archaic term for a cuckold who knows about his wife's infidelity but tolerates it;
a member of the Industrial Workers of the World;
(offensive British slang) term used by the British to refer to people of color from Africa or Asia;
a man who is aggressive in making amorous advances to women;
a male person assumed to have been raised by wolves;
an adult female person (as opposed to a man); the woman kept house while the man hunted;
a female person who plays a significant role (wife or mistress or girlfriend) in the life of a particular man; he was faithful to his woman;
a man who likes many women and has short sexual relationships with them;
a man who is unusually successful at an early age;
someone filled with admiration and awe; someone who wonders at something;
someone who is curious about something;
a woman who can be a successful wife and have a professional career at the same time;
makes decorative wooden panels;
cuts down trees and chops wood as a job;
makes things out of wood;
someone who lives in the woods;
a person who sorts wool into different grades;
a dealer in wool;
a writer who uses language carelessly or pretentiously with little regard for meaning;
a writer of vivid or graphic descriptive power;
a fluent and prolific writer;
person with a compulsive need to work;
a young woman who is employed;
an employee who performs manual or industrial labor;
a fellow worker;
a person absorbed by the concerns and interests and pleasures of the present world;
a person who has a nasty or unethical character undeserving of respect;
thinks about unfortunate things that might happen;
someone who admires too much to recognize faults;
an important, honorable person (word is often used humorously); he told his story to some conservative worthies; local worthies rarely challenged the chief constable;
someone who argues noisily or angrily;
someone who demolishes or dismantles buildings as a job;
someone who obtains something by pulling it violently with twisting movements;
combatant who tries to throw opponent to the ground;
performs some wicked deed;
someone who makes or repairs something(usuallyusedincombination);
a candidate for public office whose name does not appear on the ballot and so must be written on the ballot by the voters;
writes (books or stories or articles or the like) professionally (for pay);
a person who is able to write and has written something;
a student enrolled in (or graduated from) Winchester College;
someone who plays a xylophone;
a Japanese gangster;
one of a race of brutes resembling men but subject to the Houyhnhnms in a novel by Jonathan Swift;
a person who owns or sails a yacht;
someone who gives a strong sudden pull;
an American who lives in the North (especially during the American Civil War);
a military recruit who is assigned menial tasks;
member of an international gang of Jamaican criminals who sell drugs and violence; A much publicized raid on a yardie stronghold had first been simulated at Riot City;
a laborer hired to do outdoor work (such as mowing lawns);
worker in a railway yard;
a railroad employer who is in charge of a railway yard;
a person who yawns;
(Yiddish) a woman who talks too much; a gossip unable to keep a secret; a woman who spreads rumors and scandal;
(Yiddish) a vulgar shrew; a shallow coarse termagant;
in former times was free and cultivated his own land;
officer in the (ceremonial) bodyguard of the British monarch;
a singer who changes register rapidly (popular is Swiss folk songs);
one who practices yoga and has achieved a high level of spiritual insight;
a person who is not very intelligent or interested in culture;
a teenager or a young adult male;
a young person (especially a young man or boy);
a young radical who agitates for reform;
a member of one or more of the insurgent groups in Turkey in the late 19th century who rebelled against the absolutism of Ottoman rule;
a young upwardly mobile professional individual; a well-paid middle-class professional who works in a city and has a luxurious life style;
a buffoon in one of the old comedies; imitates others for ludicrous effect;
a member of an ancient Jewish sect in Judea in the first century who fought to the death against the Romans and who killed or persecuted Jews who collaborated with the Romans;
a Jewish supporter of Zionism;
a dead body that has been brought back to life by a supernatural force;
a god of voodoo cults of African origin worshipped especially in West Indies;
(voodooism) a spirit or supernatural force that reanimates a dead body;
the chief person responsible for a zoological garden;
a specialist in the branch of biology dealing with animals;
the Zoroastrian god of time;
Finnish architect and designer of furniture (1898-1976 );
(Old Testament) elder brother of Moses and first high priest of the Israelites; created the golden calf;
United States professional baseball player who hit more home runs than Babe Ruth (born in 1934);
Norwegian mathematician (1802-1829 );
French philosopher and theologian; lover of Heloise (1079-1142 );
the first of the Old Testament patriarchs and the father of Isaac; according to Genesis, God promised to give Abraham's family (the Hebrews) the land of Canaan (the Promised Land); God tested Abraham by asking him to sacrifice his son; Judaism, Christianity, and Islam each has a special claim on Abraham;
United States statesman who promoted the Marshall Plan and helped establish NATO (1893-1971 );
Scottish architect who designed many public buildings in England and Scotland (1728-1792 );
2nd President of the United States (1735-1826 );
