an uninhabited wilderness that is worthless for cultivation; the barrens of central Africa; the trackless wastes of the desert;
a tract of level wasteland; uncultivated land with sandy soil and scrubby vegetation;
a large wilderness area;
the bush country of the interior of Australia;
the remote outback of Australia; unpopulated desert country;
a wilderness at the edge of a settled area of a country; the individualism of the frontier in Andrew Jackson's day;
arid land with little or no vegetation;
a region much like a desert but usually located between a desert and the surrounding regions;
a fertile tract in a desert (where the water table approaches the surface);
a region where a battle is being (or has been) fought; they made a tour of Civil War battlefields;
(New Testament) the scene of the final battle between the kings of the Earth at the end of the world;
(Arthurian legend) the battlefield where King Arthur was mortally wounded;
a region in which explosives mines have been placed;
a regular route for a sentry or policeman; in the old days a policeman walked a beat and knew all his people by name;
the place where something begins, where it springs into being; the Italian beginning of the Renaissance; Jupiter was the origin of the radiation; Pittsburgh is the source of the Ohio River; communism's Russian root;
the source or origin from which something derives (i.e. comes or issues); he prefers shoes of Italian derivation; music of Turkish derivation;
a point at which water issues forth;
the source of water from which a stream arises; they tracked him back toward the head of the stream;
the source of a river; the headwaters of the Nile;
the source of water for a well;
a place from which an enterprise or expedition is launched; one day when I was at a suitable jumping-off place I decided to see if I could find him; my point of departure was San Francisco;
a location marked by an intense competition and struggle for survival;
an area in a city with large modern buildings that is perceived as dangerous and unpleasant;
an area or region distinguished from adjacent parts by a distinctive feature or characteristic;
an elongated region where a specific condition or characteristic is found; a belt of high pressure;
southern and midwestern United States where Protestant fundamentalism is dominant;
the country where you were born;
the place where someone was born;
where something originated or was nurtured in its early existence; the birthplace of civilization;
a surface forming part of the outside of an object; he examined all sides of the crystal; dew dripped from the face of the leaf;
(nautical) at the ends of the transverse deck beams of a vessel; on her beam-endsmeans heeled over on the side so that the deck is almost vertical;
the lower side of anything;
lower side; the underbellies of clouds;
the lower part of anything; curled up on the foot of the bed; the foot of the page; the foot of the list; the foot of the mountain;
(anatomy) the part of an organ nearest its point of attachment; the base of the skull;
the lowest part of anything; they started at the bottom of the hill;
the absolute bottom;
the line or plane indicating the limit or extent of something;
a line that indicates a boundary;
an archaic term for a boundary;
district consisting of the area on either side of a border or boundary of a country or an area; the Welsh marches between England and Wales;
an area that has been taken over and is controlled and corrupted by drug cartels and where law enforcement is effectively nonexistent; this Mexican town has become a narco-state that ships 100 pounds of cocaine to the United States every day;
any area set aside for a particular purpose; who owns this place?; the president was concerned about the property across from the White House;
a place where some particular activity is concentrated; they received messages from several centers;
a place where a group of people with the same interest or occupation are concentrated; a nudist colony; an artists' colony;
a center that provides information and control; the nerve center of the diamond industry is in Amsterdam;
the boundary line encompassing an area or object; he had walked the full circumference of his land; a danger to all races over the whole circumference of the globe;
a boundary line created by a fence;
the border marking the boundaries of the land that Israel won in its 1948 war of independence;
a 450-mile line that is supposed to indicate the boundary between the part of Kashmir controlled by India and the part controlled by Pakistan;
the boundary line between two pieces of property;
the boundary between two states;
the boundary between Maryland and Pennsylvania; symbolic dividing line between North and South before the American Civil War;
the boundary between two districts;
the boundary between two counties;
the boundary of a city;
the area on a billiard table behind the balkline; a player with ball in hand must play from the balk;
line across a billiard table behind which the cue balls are placed at the start of a game;
an area in a town that has been devastated by bombs; they opened a parking lot on the bomb site;
the center of the Earth;
a field of closely mowed turf for playing bowls;
a geographic region serving as the principal source of grain;
a place where animals breed;
a defensive post at the end of a bridge nearest to the enemy;
the edge of a steep place;
the area over which a radio or tv transmission can be received;
a small neutral state between two rival powers;
the center of a target;
the route regularly followed by a passenger bus;
a place on a bus route where buses stop to discharge and take on passengers;
a place (as at a frontier) where travellers are stopped for inspection and clearance;
a place where taxis park while awaiting customers; in England the place where taxis wait to be hired is called a taxi rank;
a site where people on holiday can pitch a tent;
a field on which the buildings of a university are situated;
a seat of government;
a center that is associated more than any other with some activity or product; the crime capital of Italy; the drug capital of Columbia;
the entire geographical area drained by a river and its tributaries; an area characterized by all runoff being conveyed to the same outlet; flood control in the Missouri basin;
a storage site (such as a small reservoir) that delays the flow of water downstream;
a storage site similar to a detention basin but the water in storage is permanently obstructed from flowing downstream;
a large region between the Black and Caspian seas that contains the Caucasus Mountains; oil is its major resource;
a geographical region to the south of the Caucasus Mountains and to the north of Turkey that comprises Georgia and Armenia and Azerbaijan;
the great circle on the celestial sphere midway between the celestial poles;
a point in the heavens (on the celestial sphere);
(astronomy) either of the two celestial points at which the celestial equator intersects the ecliptic;
(astronomy) the equinoctial point that lies in the constellation of Pisces;
(astronomy) the equinoctial point that lies in the constellation of Virgo;
the apparent surface of the imaginary sphere on which celestial bodies appear to be projected;
a tract of land used for burials;
a point equidistant from the ends of a line or the extremities of a figure;
(physics) the center of mass of the immersed part of ship or other floating object;
the point within something at which gravity can be considered to act; in uniform gravity it is equal to the center of mass;
the center of gravity of a floating object;
point representing the mean position of the matter in a body;
(astronomy) the common center of mass around which two or more bodies revolve;
the center of mass of an object of uniform density;
point where the hairline meets the midpoint of the forehead;
an area that is approximately central within some larger region; it is in the center of town; they ran forward into the heart of the struggle; they were in the eye of the storm;
the central area on a theater stage;
the central part of a city;
the center of an object; the ball has a titanium core;
