a trivalent metallic element of the rare earth group; occurs together with yttrium; forms highly magnetic compounds;
a nonmetallic univalent element that is normally a colorless and odorless highly flammable diatomic gas; the simplest and lightest and most abundant element in the universe;
an atom of hydrogen;
a hydrogen atom in an acid that forms a positive ion when the acid dissociates;
an isotope of hydrogen which has one neutron (as opposed to zero neutrons in hydrogen);
a rare soft silvery metallic element; occurs in small quantities in sphalerite;
a nonmetallic element belonging to the halogens; used especially in medicine and photography and in dyes; occurs naturally only in combination in small quantities (as in sea water or rocks);
heavy radioactive isotope of iodine with a half-life of 8 days; used in a sodium salt to diagnose thyroid disease and to treat goiter;
light radioactive isotope of iodine with a half-life of 60 days; used as a tracer in thyroid studies and as a treatment for hyperthyroidism;
a heavy brittle metallic element of the platinum group; used in alloys; occurs in natural alloys with platinum or osmium;
a heavy ductile magnetic metallic element; is silver-white in pure form but readily rusts; used in construction and tools and armament; plays a role in the transport of oxygen by the blood;
a colorless element that is one of the six inert gasses; occurs in trace amounts in air;
a white soft metallic element that tarnishes readily; occurs in rare earth minerals and is usually classified as a rare earth;
a radioactive transuranic element synthesized from californium;
a soft heavy toxic malleable metallic element; bluish white when freshly cut but tarnishes readily to dull grey; the children were playing with lead soldiers;
a soft silver-white univalent element of the alkali metal group; the lightest metal known; occurs in several minerals;
a trivalent metallic element of the rare earth group; usually occurs in association with yttrium;
a light silver-white ductile bivalent metallic element; in pure form it burns with brilliant white flame; occurs naturally only in combination (as in magnesite and dolomite and carnallite and spinel and olivine);
a hard brittle grey polyvalent metallic element that resembles iron but is not magnetic; used in making steel; occurs in many minerals;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a radioactive transuranic element synthesized by bombarding einsteinium with alpha particles (Md is the current symbol for mendelevium but Mv was formerly the symbol);
a heavy silvery toxic univalent and bivalent metallic element; the only metal that is liquid at ordinary temperatures;
a polyvalent metallic element that resembles chromium and tungsten in its properties; used to strengthen and harden steel;
a yellow trivalent metallic element of the rare earth group; occurs in monazite and bastnasite in association with cerium and lanthanum and praseodymium;
a colorless odorless gaseous element that give a red glow in a vacuum tube; one of the six inert gasses; occurs in the air in small amounts;
a radioactive transuranic metallic element; found in trace amounts in uranium ores; a by-product of the production of plutonium;
a hard malleable ductile silvery metallic element that is resistant to corrosion; used in alloys; occurs in pentlandite and smaltite and garnierite and millerite;
a soft grey ductile metallic element used in alloys; occurs in niobite; formerly called columbium;
a former name for niobium;
a common nonmetallic element that is normally a colorless odorless tasteless inert diatomic gas; constitutes 78 percent of the atmosphere by volume; a constituent of all living tissues;
an obsolete name for nitrogen;
a radioactive transuranic element synthesized by bombarding curium with carbon ions; 7 isotopes are known;
a hard brittle blue-grey or blue-black metallic element that is one of the platinum metals; the heaviest metal known;
a nonmetallic bivalent element that is normally a colorless odorless tasteless nonflammable diatomic gas; constitutes 21 percent of the atmosphere by volume; the most abundant element in the earth's crust;
a bluish translucent magnetic liquid obtained by compressing gaseous oxygen and then cooling it below its boiling point; used as an oxidizer in rocket propellants;
a silver-white metallic element of the platinum group that resembles platinum; occurs in some copper and nickel ores; does not tarnish at ordinary temperatures and is used (alloyed with gold) in jewelry;
a synthetic substance that is fluorescent or phosphorescent; used to coat the screens of cathode ray tubes;
a multivalent nonmetallic element of the nitrogen family that occurs commonly in inorganic phosphate rocks and as organic phosphates in all living cells; is highly reactive and occurs in several allotropic forms;
a heavy precious metallic element; grey-white and resistant to corroding; occurs in some nickel and copper ores and is also found native in some deposits;
a solid silvery grey radioactive transuranic element whose atoms can be split when bombarded with neutrons; found in minute quantities in uranium ores but is usually synthesized in nuclear reactors; 13 isotopes are known with the most important being plutonium 239;
a highly fissionable isotope of plutonium that is used in atomic weapons and as a reactor fuel; produced by irradiating uranium 238 with slow electrons;
plutonium 239 that is recovered when nuclear weapons are disassembled; it is stored in plutonium pits;
a radioactive metallic element that is similar to tellurium and bismuth; occurs in uranium ores but can be produced by bombarding bismuth with neutrons in a nuclear reactor;
a light soft silver-white metallic element of the alkali metal group; oxidizes rapidly in air and reacts violently with water; is abundant in nature in combined forms occurring in sea water and in carnallite and kainite and sylvite;
a soft yellowish-white trivalent metallic element of the rare earth group; can be recovered from bastnasite or monazite by an ion-exchange process;
a soft silvery metallic element of the rare earth group having no stable isotope; was discovered in radioactive form as a fission product of uranium;
a short-lived radioactive metallic element formed from uranium and disintegrating into actinium and then into lead;
an intensely radioactive metallic element that occurs in minute amounts in uranium ores;
a radioactive gaseous element formed by the disintegration of radium; the heaviest of the inert gasses; occurs naturally (especially in areas over granite) and is considered a hazard to health;
a rare heavy polyvalent metallic element that resembles manganese chemically and is used in some alloys; is obtained as a by-product in refining molybdenum;
a white hard metallic element that is one of the platinum group and is found in platinum ores; used in alloys with platinum;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a soft silvery metallic element of the alkali metal group; burns in air and reacts violently in water; occurs in carnallite and lepidolite and pollucite;
a rare polyvalent metallic element of the platinum group; it is found associated with platinum;
a radioactive transuranic element which has been synthesized;
a grey lustrous metallic element of the rare earth group; is used in special alloys; occurs in monazite and bastnasite;
a white trivalent metallic element; sometimes classified in the rare earth group; occurs in the Scandinavian mineral thortveitite;
a transuranic element;
a toxic nonmetallic element related to sulfur and tellurium; occurs in several allotropic forms; a stable grey metallike allotrope conducts electricity better in the light than in the dark and is used in photocells; occurs in sulfide ores (as pyrite);
a tetravalent nonmetallic element; next to oxygen it is the most abundant element in the earth's crust; occurs in clay and feldspar and granite and quartz and sand; used as a semiconductor in transistors;
a soft white precious univalent metallic element having the highest electrical and thermal conductivity of any metal; occurs in argentite and in free form; used in coins and jewelry and tableware and photography;
a silvery soft waxy metallic element of the alkali metal group; occurs abundantly in natural compounds (especially in salt water); burns with a yellow flame and reacts violently in water; occurs in sea water and in the mineral halite (rock salt);
a soft silver-white or yellowish metallic element of the alkali metal group; turns yellow in air; occurs in celestite and strontianite;
a radioactive isotope of strontium (with the mass number 90) that is present in the fallout from nuclear explosions; can be assimilated like calcium into bones;
an abundant tasteless odorless multivalent nonmetallic element; best known in yellow crystals; occurs in many sulphide and sulphate minerals and even in native form (especially in volcanic regions);
a hard grey lustrous metallic element that is highly resistant to corrosion; occurs in niobite and fergusonite and tantalite;
a colorless crystalline substance obtained from the bile of mammals;
a crystalline metallic element not found in nature; occurs as one of the fission products of uranium;
a brittle silver-white metalloid element that is related to selenium and sulfur; it is used in alloys and as a semiconductor; occurs mainly as tellurides in ores of copper and nickel and silver and gold;
a metallic element of the rare earth group; used in lasers; occurs in apatite and monazite and xenotime and ytterbite;
a soft grey malleable metallic element that resembles tin but discolors on exposure to air; it is highly toxic and is used in rodent and insect poisons; occurs in zinc blende and some iron ores;
a soft silvery-white tetravalent radioactive metallic element; isotope 232 is used as a power source in nuclear reactors; occurs in thorite and in monazite sands;
radioactive isotope of thorium with mass number 228;
a soft silvery metallic element of the rare earth group; isotope 170 emits X-rays and is used in small portable X-ray machines; it occurs in monazite and apatite and xenotime;
a silvery malleable metallic element that resists corrosion; used in many alloys and to coat other metals to prevent corrosion; obtained chiefly from cassiterite where it occurs as tin oxide;
a light strong grey lustrous corrosion-resistant metallic element used in strong lightweight alloys (as for airplane parts); the main sources are rutile and ilmenite;
a heavy grey-white metallic element; the pure form is used mainly in electrical applications; it is found in several ores including wolframite and scheelite;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a radioactive transuranic element;
a heavy toxic silvery-white radioactive metallic element; occurs in many isotopes; used for nuclear fuels and nuclear weapons;
a uranium isotope with mass number 235; capable of sustaining chain reactions;
the commonest isotope of uranium; it is not fissionable but when irradiated with neutrons it produces fissionable plutonium 239;
a soft silvery white toxic metallic element used in steel alloys; it occurs in several complex minerals including carnotite and vanadinite;
a colorless odorless inert gaseous element occurring in the earth's atmosphere in trace amounts;
a soft silvery metallic element; a rare earth of the lanthanide series; it occurs in gadolinite and monazite and xenotime;
a silvery metallic element that is common in rare-earth minerals; used in magnesium and aluminum alloys;
a bluish-white lustrous metallic element; brittle at ordinary temperatures but malleable when heated; used in a wide variety of alloys and in galvanizing iron; it occurs naturally as zinc sulphide in zinc blende;
a lustrous grey strong metallic element resembling titanium; it is used in nuclear reactors as a neutron absorber; it occurs in baddeleyite but is obtained chiefly from zircon;
solid homogeneous inorganic substances occurring in nature having a definite chemical composition;
a waxy mineral that is a mixture of hydrocarbons and occurs in association with petroleum; some varieties are used in making ceresin and candles;
a compact fine-textured, usually white gypsum used for carving;
a hard compact kind of calcite;
a white or grey mineral consisting of lithium aluminum phosphate; a source of lithium;
a mineral or mineral variety belonging to the amphibole group;
a group of minerals with similar crystal structures containing a silicate chain and combinations of chiefly sodium and calcium and magnesium and iron and aluminum;
a metamorphic rock composed chiefly of amphibole and plagioclase;
a common complex mineral consisting of calcium fluoride phosphate or calcium chloride phosphate; a source of phosphorus;
