an enzyme that makes prostaglandins that cause inflammation and pain and fever; the beneficial effects of NSAIDs result from their ability to block Cox-2;
an amylase secreted in saliva;
a substance that curdles milk in making cheese and junket;
a substance capable of bringing about fermentation;
the substance that is acted upon by an enzyme or ferment;
a compound derived from ammonia by replacing hydrogen atoms by univalent hydrocarbon radicals;
insecticide;
an organic acid characterized by one or more carboxyl groups;
a white dicarboxylic acid formed from oxidation of sugar or starch;
a dicarboxylic acid used to make resins;
a white crystalline carboxylic acid used as a preservative;
a clear liquid carboxylic acid used in perfumes and drugs;
any of a class of aliphatic monocarboxylic acids that form part of a lipid molecule and can be derived from fat by hydrolysis; fatty acids are simple molecules built around a series of carbon atoms linked together in a chain of 12 to 22 carbon atoms;
a fatty acid whose carbon chain cannot absorb any more hydrogen atoms; found chiefly in animal fats;
a fatty acid whose carbon chain can absorb additional hydrogen atoms;
a fatty acid that has been produced by hydrogenating an unsaturated fatty acid (and so changing its shape); found in processed foods such as margarine and fried foods and puddings and commercially baked goods and partially hydrogenated vegetable oils;
an unsaturated fatty acid whose carbon chain has one double or triple valence bond per molecule; found chiefly in olive oil and chicken and almonds;
an unsaturated fatty acid whose carbon chain has more than one double or triple valence bond per molecule; found chiefly in fish and corn and soybean oil and safflower oil;
a polyunsaturated fatty acid whose carbon chain has its first double valence bond three carbons from the beginning;
a polyunsaturated fatty acid whose carbon chain has its first double valence bond six carbons from the beginning;
a colorless crystalline synthetic fatty acid;
an oily fatty acid found in castor oil and used in soap;
peptide released from the amino end of fibrinogen by the action of thrombin to form fibrin during clotting of the blood;
a peptide containing 10 to more than 100 amino acids;
amide combining the amino group of one amino acid with the carboxyl group of another; usually obtained by partial hydrolysis of protein;
a derivative of benzoic acid;
a plastic (synthetic resin) made from amino compounds; used as an adhesive and as a coating for paper and textiles;
a pungent gas compounded of nitrogen and hydrogen (NH3);
a complex inorganic compound that contains ammonia molecules;
a water solution of ammonia;
the aromatic gum of the ammoniac plant;
the ion NH4 derived from ammonia; behaves in many respects like an alkali metal ion;
a salt of carbamic acid that is used as a nitrogen fertilizer;
a carbonate of ammonium; used in the manufacture of smelling salts and baking powder and ammonium compounds;
a white salt used in dry cells;
a mixture of 2 or more isomeric alcohols; used as a solvent and in organic synthesis;
(botany) a plant product that acts like a hormone;
a plant hormone that promotes root formation and bud growth;
a plant hormone isolated from a fungus; used in promoting plant growth;
a crystalline acid associated with gibberellin;
any of a class of plant hormones that promote cell division and delay the senescence of leaves;
any hormone affecting the development and growth of sex organs;
secreted by the adrenal cortex; involved in regulating water and electrolyte balance in the body;
a steroid hormone (trade name Lipo-Lutin) produced in the ovary; prepares and maintains the uterus for pregnancy;
a synthetic progestational compound used to treat endometrial carcinoma;
a synthetic progestational hormone (trade name Norlutin) used in oral contraceptives and to treat endometriosis;
a progesterone derivative used in oral contraceptives and in the control of menstruation and the treatment of abnormal uterine bleeding;
synthetic progestin used in oral contraceptives;
a progestin compound (trade name Provera) used to treat menstrual disorders;
any of a group of steroid hormones that have the effect of progesterone;
male sex hormone that is produced in the testes and responsible for typical male sexual characteristics;
a steroid having androgenic activity; obtained from the cortex of the adrenal gland;
an androgenic hormone that is less active than testosterone;
an androgenic compound contained in drugs that are used to treat testosterone deficiency and female breast cancer and to stimulate growth and weight gain;
an androgen (trade names Durabolin or Kabolin) that is used to treat testosterone deficiency or breast cancer or osteoporosis;
a potent androgenic hormone produced chiefly by the testes; responsible for the development of male secondary sex characteristics;
a gonadotropic hormone that is secreted by the anterior pituitary and stimulates growth of Graafian follicles in female mammals, and activates the cells in male mammals that form sperm;
hormone produced early in pregnancy by the placenta; detection in the urine and serum is the basis for one kind of pregnancy test;
a gonadotropic hormone that is secreted by the anterior pituitary; stimulates ovulation in female mammals and stimulates androgen release in male mammals;
gonadotropic hormone secreted by the anterior pituitary; in females it stimulates growth of the mammary glands and lactation after parturition;
a general term for female steroid sex hormones that are secreted by the ovary and responsible for typical female sexual characteristics;
a potent estrogen used in medicine and in feed for livestock and poultry;
the most powerful female hormone that occurs naturally; synthesized and used to treat estrogen deficiency and breast cancer;
a naturally occurring estrogenic hormone; a synthetic form is used to treat estrogen deficiency;
a naturally occurring weak estrogenic hormone secreted by the mammalian ovary; synthesized (trade name Estronol) and used to treat estrogen deficiency;
estrogen compound used to treat menstrual irregularities and menopausal symptoms and to prevent pregnancy;
a synthetic form of estrogen used in combination with a progestin in oral contraceptives;
a steroid hormone produced by the adrenal cortex or synthesized; administered as drugs they reduce swelling and decrease the body's immune response; adrenal cortical steroids are used to treat many different conditions;
hormone that is one of the steroids of the adrenal cortex that influences the metabolism of sodium and potassium;
a steroid hormone that is produced by the adrenal cortex of animals; affects functioning of gonads and has anti-inflammatory activity;
an amino derivative of glucose that is a component of many polysaccharides;
a corticosteroid hormone that is secreted by the cortex of the adrenal gland; regulates salt (sodium and potassium) and water balance;
an adrenal-cortex hormone (trade names Hydrocortone or Cortef) that is active in carbohydrate and protein metabolism;
a corticosteroid hormone (trade name Cortone Acetate) normally produced by the adrenal cortex; is converted to hydrocortisone;
a glucocorticoid (trade names Pediapred or Prelone) used to treat inflammatory conditions;
a dehydrogenated analogue of cortisol (trade names Orasone or Deltasone or Liquid Pred or Meticorten); used as an anti-inflammatory drug in the treatment of arthritis and as an immunosuppressant;
a corticosteroid drug (trade names Decadron or Dexamethasone Intensol or Dexone or Hexadrol or Oradexon) used to treat allergies or inflammation;
a synthetic corticosteroid (trade name Aldactone) used to treat hypertension;
dye in which the chromophore is part of a negative ion;
oily poisonous liquid amine obtained from nitrobenzene and used to make dyes and plastics and medicines;
any of various yellow dyes; not related chemically to alizarin but applied in the same manner;
a blue dye obtained from plants or made synthetically;
any of many dyes made from aniline;
any oil obtained from animal substances;
an oil that hardens in air due to oxidation and is often used as a paint or varnish base;
material derived from animals;
pigment occurring in animals;
a poisonous colorless flammable gas used in organic synthesis and to dope transistors and as a poison gas in warfare;
an orange-yellow pigment in the bile that forms as a product of hemoglobin; excess amounts in the blood produce the yellow appearance observed in jaundice;
brown bile pigment formed from urobilinogens and found in feces and in small amounts in urine;
a chromogen formed in the intestine from the breakdown of bilirubin; yields urobilins on oxidation; some is excreted in the feces and some is resorbed and excreted in bile or urine;
pigment occurring in luminescent organisms (as fireflies); emits heatless light when undergoing oxidation;
insoluble pigments that account for the color of e.g. skin and scales and feathers;
a calcareous material harder and denser than bone that comprises the bulk of a tooth;
a hard smooth ivory colored dentine that makes up most of the tusks of elephants and walruses;
any light downy material;
the porous calcified substance from which bones are made;
the material (mostly keratin) that covers the horns of ungulates and forms hooves and claws and nails;
a horny material from the upper jaws of certain whales; used as the ribs of fans or as stays in corsets;
the mottled horny substance of the shell of some turtles;
