blockage or closure (as of a wound or body cavity) by (or as if by) a tampon (especially to stop bleeding);
mechanical compression of the heart resulting from large amounts of fluid collecting in the pericardial space and limiting the heart's normal range of motion;
a form of infantilism characterized by physical underdevelopment but normal intelligence;
an abnormally large head; differs from hydrocephalus because there is no increased intracranial pressure and the overgrowth is symmetrical;
abnormally small arms;
an abnormally small head and underdeveloped brain;
an abnormal thickness of the lips;
an abnormal tightness of the foreskin preventing retraction over the glans;
the physiological state produced by a poison or other toxic substance;
poisoning resulting from the ingestion of an alkali compound (as lye or ammonia);
poisoning resulting from excessive intake of caffeine containing products;
a toxic condition that results from inhaling and absorbing carbon monoxide gas; carbon monoxide combines with hemoglobin and displaces oxygen in the blood;
poisoning due to ingesting or inhaling cyanide; common in smoke from fires and in industrial chemicals;
a toxic condition caused by inhaling or ingesting the insecticide Malathion;
poisoning by ingestion of ergot-infected grain products; characterized by thirst and diarrhea and nausea and cramping and vomiting and abnormal cardiac rhythms; in severe cases it can cause seizures and gangrene of the limbs;
a toxic condition caused by ingesting or inhaling mercury; acute mercury poisoning causes a metallic taste and vomiting and diarrhea and kidney problems that may lead to death;
a form of mercury poisoning among people who ate fish from mercury-contaminated waters of Minamata Bay off Japan in the 1950s; characterized by severe neurological degeneration;
toxic condition resulting from inhaling or ingesting naphthalene;
toxic condition caused by the ingestion or inhalation of large amounts of nicotine;
poisoning by snake venom;
poisoning caused by ingestion of paraquat; characterized by progressive damage to the esophagus and liver and kidneys;
a toxic condition resulting from inhalation or ingestion of the insecticide parathion; characterized by nausea and abdominal pains and headache and convulsions and sweating;
toxic condition resulting from ingesting or inhaling a pesticide;
poisoning caused by the excessive ingestion of salicylates (usually aspirin);
the set of facts or circumstances that surround a situation or event; the historical context;
the environment as it relates to living organisms; it changed the ecology of the island;
the state of the environment in which a situation exists; you can't do that in a university setting;
the setting for a narrative or fictional or dramatic account; the crowded canvas of history; the movie demanded a dramatic canvas of sound;
an environment offering affection and security; home is where the heart is; he grew up in a good Christian home; there's no place like home;
the environmental condition;
a particular environment or walk of life; his social sphere is limited; it was a closed area of employment; he's out of my orbit;
the sphere of work by women;
a sphere of activity involving effort; the Japanese were active last week on the diplomatic front; they advertise on many different fronts;
an idyllic realm of contentment and self-indulgence;
a domain in which something is dominant; the untroubled kingdom of reason; a land of make-believe; the rise of the realm of cotton in the south;
an area of control or responsibility; the job fell right in my lap;
beyond human control or responsibility; there is nothing more I can do; it's in the lap of the gods now;
a sphere of intense political activity;
a domain that seems to be specially reserved for someone; medicine is no longer a male preserve;
the proper sphere or extent of your activities; it was his province to take care of himself;
the district within the jurisdiction of an archbishop or a metropolitan or one of the territorial divisions of an ecclesiastical order; the general of the Jesuits has several provinces under him;
a setting in which something can be displayed to best effect; it was a showcase for democracy in Africa;
the streets of a city viewed as a depressed environment in which there is poverty and crime and prostitution and dereliction; she tried to keep her children off the street;
the state of the environment;
undesirable state of the natural environment being contaminated with harmful substances as a consequence of human activities;
pollution that is rendered harmless by natural processes and so causes no permanent harm;
pollution that accumulates in the environment and may appear in the food chain;
pollution of the atmosphere; air pollution reduced the visibility;
rain containing acids that form in the atmosphere when industrial gas emissions (especially sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides) combine with water;
pollution resulting from an industrial plant discharging pollutants into the atmosphere;
unhealthy vapors rising from the ground or other sources; the miasma of the marshes; a miasma of cigar smoke;
air pollution caused by fine particles of soot (as from power plants or diesel engines);
air pollution by a mixture of smoke and fog;
annoying and potentially harmful environmental noise;
harm to lakes and rivers resulting from the release of excessive waste heat into them;
pollution of the water in rivers and lakes;
condition in which the earth's surface is worn away by the action of water and wind;
the state of being clear of trees;
the condition of having reduced numbers of inhabitants (or no inhabitants at all);
the weather in some location averaged over some long period of time; the dank climate of southern Wales; plants from a cold clime travel best in winter;
the condition of being covered with glaciers or masses of ice; the result of glacial action; Agassiz recognized marks of glaciation all over northern Europe;
the environmental condition in a region that lacks a favorable climate or terrain for life or growth;
the prevailing environmental conditions as they influence the prediction of weather;
the weather or climate at some place; the atmosphere was thick with fog;
a large body of air with uniform characteristics horizontally;
an air mass of higher than normal pressure; the east coast benefits from a Bermuda high;
an air mass of lower pressure; often brings precipitation; a low moved in over night bringing sleet and snow;
(meteorology) winds spiraling outward from a high pressure center; circling clockwise in the northern hemisphere and counterclockwise in the southern;
(meteorology) rapid inward circulation of air masses about a low pressure center; circling counterclockwise in the northern hemisphere and clockwise in the southern;
an atmosphere in which visibility is reduced because of a cloud of some substance;
(British informal) an airless smoky smelly atmosphere;
weather suitable for outdoor activities;
an absence of strong winds or rain;
good weather with comfortable temperatures;
the quality of weather that is deliciously mild and soothing; the day's heat faded into balminess; the climate had the softness of the south of France;
calmness without winds;
a period of calm weather; there was a lull in the storm;
weather unsuitable for outdoor activities;
unpleasantly cold and damp weather;
the state of being stormy; he dreaded the storminess of the North Atlantic in winter;
a turbulent and stormy state of the sea;
a mildly windy state of the air;
a state of wild storminess;
used of the sea during inclement or stormy weather;
the state of the sky when it is covered by clouds;
instability in the atmosphere;
strong turbulence in an otherwise cloudless region that subjects aircraft to violent updrafts or downdrafts;
the prevailing psychological state; the climate of opinion; the national mood had changed radically since the last election;
a particular environment or surrounding influence; there was an atmosphere of excitement;
a cause of worry or gloom or trouble; the only cloud on the horizon was the possibility of dissent by the French;
the special atmosphere of a place;
an atmosphere of depression and melancholy; gloom pervaded the office;
a bleak and desolate atmosphere; the nakedness of the landscape;
a flashy vulgar tone or atmosphere believed to be characteristic of the American film industry; some people in publishing think of theirs as a glamorous medium so they copy the glitter of Hollywood;
an unwholesome atmosphere; the novel spun a miasma of death and decay;
the general atmosphere of a place or situation and the effect that it has on people; the feel of the city excited him; a clergyman improved the tone of the meeting; it had the smell of treason;
the spirit of the time; the spirit characteristic of an age or generation;
the state of not being susceptible; unsusceptibility to rust;
the capacity of an organism to defend itself against harmful environmental agents; these trees are widely planted because of their resistance to salt and smog;
(medicine) the condition in which an organism can resist disease;
