acceptance as true or valid;
the state of being contented with your situation in life; he relaxed in sleepy contentedness; they could read to their heart's content;
acceptance without protest;
the state of being welcome; don't outstay your welcome;
the state of having rejected your religious beliefs or your political party or a cause (often in favor of opposing beliefs or causes);
the state of being out of favor; he is in disfavor with the king;
(politics) a state of disfavor; he led the Democratic party back from the wilderness;
the state of being excommunicated;
rejection by God; the state of being condemned to eternal misery in Hell;
the state of lacking unity;
the state of being several and distinct;
a state of separation between persons or groups;
the state or situation of being alone;
a state of social isolation;
the state of being alone in solitary isolation;
enforced isolation of patients suffering from a contagious disease in order to prevent the spread of disease;
the state of being isolated or detached; the insulation of England was preserved by the English Channel;
separation resulting from hostility;
personal state of isolation and anxiety resulting from a lack of social control and regulation;
the condition of being concealed or hidden;
the state of being covert and hidden;
the chest considered as the place where secret thoughts are kept; his bosom was bursting with the secret;
the state of being secret; you must respect the confidentiality of your client's communications;
a state in which some integrated part of a person's life becomes separated from the rest of the personality and functions independently;
a mild state of dissociation;
dissociation so severe that the usually integrated functions of consciousness and perception of self break down;
lack of connection or continuity;
state of being disconnected;
the capability of being separated;
lack of cohesion or clarity or organization;
lacking order or coherence;
the state of being joined or united or linked; there is strength in union;
the state of being combined into one body;
the state of being allied or confederated;
the state of being under federal control; the federalization of postal service;
the state of being connected; the connection between church and state is inescapable;
the state or condition of touching or of being in immediate proximity; litmus paper turns red on contact with an acid;
the state of being linked together as in a chain; union in a linked series;
(mathematics) a contact of two curves (or two surfaces) at which they have a common tangent;
the state of being tangent; having contact at a single point or along a line without crossing;
a state of being connected reciprocally; an interconnection between the two buildings;
the state of cohering or sticking together;
logical coherence and accordance with the facts; a rambling argument that lacked any consistency;
the state of being joined together;
the state of being connected together as in memory or imagination; his association of his father with being beaten was too strong to break;
the state of being unconnected in memory or imagination; I could not think of him in disassociation from his wife;
a close and intimate union; the marriage of music and dance; a marriage of ideas;
the union (or attempted fusion) of different systems of thought or belief (especially in religion or philosophy); a syncretism of material and immaterial theories;
uninterrupted connection or union;
a condition superior to an earlier condition; the new school represents a great improvement;
a condition inferior to an earlier condition; a gradual falling off from a better state;
an improvement that adds to the value of a property or facility;
a state in which things are improving; the result of developing (as in the early part of a game of chess); after he saw the latest development he changed his mind and became a supporter; in chess your should take care of your development before moving your queen;
state of inadequate development; much poverty can be traced to the underdevelopment of industry;
the state of something that has been unused and neglected; the house was in a terrible state of neglect;
something that has been omitted; she searched the table for omissions;
a condition of decline following successes; in the twilight of the empire;
something or someone that has suffered ruin or dilapidation; the house was a wreck when they bought it; thanks to that quack I am a human wreck;
improvement (or an intended improvement) in the existing form or condition of institutions or practices etc.; intended to make a striking change for the better in social or political or religious affairs;
a reformation intended to counter the results of a prior reformation;
the state of being restored to its former good condition; the inn was a renovation of a Colonial house;
state of being mature; full development;
the state (and responsibilities) of a person who has attained maturity;
the state of being a man; manly qualities;
the state of being a parent; to everyone's surprise, parenthood reformed the man;
the state of being ripe;
the state of being an adult woman;
early maturity; the state of being young or immature or inexperienced;
not having reached maturity;
the state in which women have stopped ovulating;
the state of not being ripe;
lacking and evidencing lack of experience of life;
the state of being premature;
in the state that someone is in between puberty and adulthood;
the state of a child between infancy and adolescence;
the earliest state of immaturity;
the state of taking in or encircling; an island in the embrace of the sea;
including entirely;
the state of being banished or ostracized (excluded from society by general consent); the association should get rid of its elderly members--not by euthanasia, of course, but by Coventry;
the state of being debarred (excluded from enjoying certain possessions or rights or practices);
a relative position or degree of value in a graded group; lumber of the highest grade;
the level of safety from exposure to infectious agents; depends on work practices and safety equipment and facilities;
exposure only to infectious agents that do not ordinarily cause human disease;
exposure to infectious agents that can cause disease in humans but whose potential for transmission is limited;
exposure to infectious agents that can be transmitted by the respiratory route and which can cause serious infection;
exposure to exotic infectious agents that pose a high risk of life-threatening disease and can be transmitted as an aerosol and for which there is no vaccine or therapy;
standing or position on a scale;
position on a scale in relation to others in a sport;
relative position in a graded series; always a step behind; subtle gradations in color; keep in step with the fashions;
a step on some scale; he is a cut above the rest;
relative status; his salary was determined by his rank and seniority;
not the highest rank in a classification;
the advanced level of a subject taken in school (usually two years after O level);
the basic level of a subject taken in school;
the level of education that college students are assumed to have attained;
rank in a military organization;
the rank of a flag officer;
social status or position conferred by a system based on class; lose caste by doing work beneath one's station;
high office or rank or station; he respected the dignity of the emissaries;
the state of being of noble birth;
