capital of Pennsylvania; located in southern part of state;
an industrial town to the east of Harrisburg;
a city of southeastern Pennsylvania on the Delaware river (an industrial suburb of Philadelphia);
the largest city in Pennsylvania; located in the southeastern part of the state on the Delaware river; site of Independence Hall where the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution were signed; site of the University of Pennsylvania;
a city in southwestern Pennsylvania where the confluence of the Allegheny River and Monongahela River forms the Ohio River; long an important urban industrial area; site of Carnegie Mellon University and the University of Pittsburgh;
an industrial city of northeastern Pennsylvania;
a state in New England; one of the original 13 colonies; the smallest state;
one of the British colonies that formed the United States;
the capital and largest city of Rhode Island; located in northeastern Rhode Island on Narragansett Bay; site of Brown University;
a resort city in southeastern Rhode Island; known for the summer homes of millionaires; important yachting center;
a state in the Deep South; one of the original 13 colonies;
one of the British colonies that formed the United States;
capital and largest city in South Carolina; located in central South Carolina;
a port city in southeastern South Carolina;
a town in northeast South Carolina; transportation center;
a town in northwest South Carolina in the Piedmont;
a state in north central United States;
a town in northeastern South Dakota;
capital of the state of South Dakota; located in central South Dakota on the Missouri river;
a town in southwestern South Dakota in the eastern part of the Black Hills;
largest city in South Dakota; located in southeastern South Dakota;
mountains in western South Dakota and northeastern Wyoming;
a state in east central United States;
a city in eastern Tennessee;
a town in west central Tennessee;
a town in western Tennessee;
a town in northeastern Tennessee;
a city in eastern Tennessee on the Tennessee River;
largest city of Tennessee; located in southwestern Tennessee on bluffs overlooking the Mississippi River;
capital of the state of Tennessee; located in the north central part of the state on the Cumberland River; known for country music;
the second largest state; located in southwestern United States on the Gulf of Mexico;
a city in central Texas;
a city in the northern panhandle of Texas;
a city in northern Texas between Dallas and Fort Worth;
state capital of Texas on the Colorado River; site of the University of Texas;
a city of southeastern Texas near Houston;
a city in southern Texas on the Rio Grande near its mouth into the Gulf of Mexico; has a channel that accommodates oceangoing ships;
a town of east central Texas;
a city in southern Texas on an arm of the Gulf of Mexico;
a large commercial and industrial city in northeastern Texas located in the heart of the northern Texas oil fields;
a town in southwest Texas on the Rio Grande to the west of San Antonio;
a city in western Texas on the Mexican border; located on the northern bank of the Rio Grande across from the Mexican city of Juarez;
a city in northeastern Texas (just to the west of Dallas); a major industrial center;
a town in southeast Texas on Galveston Island;
an island at the entrance of Galveston Bay;
a city in northeastern Texas (suburb of Dallas);
the largest city in Texas; located in southeastern Texas near the Gulf of Mexico; site of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;
a city in southern Texas on the Rio Grande;
a city in northwest Texas to the south of Amarillo;
a town in eastern Texas;
a town in southern Texas on the Rio Grande;
a town in west central Texas;
a city in western Texas;
a town in northeastern Texas;
a city in northeastern Texas (suburb of Dallas);
a town in west central Texas; formerly a notorious frontier town;
a city of south central Texas; site of the Alamo; site of several military bases and a popular haven for vacationers;
a town in northeastern Texas near the Oklahoma border;
a town in northeast Texas adjacent to Texarkana, Arkansas;
a town in northeast Texas;
a town in southeast Texas to the southeast of San Antonio;
a city in east central Texas;
a city in north central Texas near the Oklahoma border;
a state in the western United States; settled in 1847 by Mormons led by Brigham Young;
a town in northern Utah settled by Mormons;
a city in north central Utah settled by Mormons;
the capital and largest city of Utah; located near the Great Salt Lake in north central Utah; world capital of the Mormon Church;
a state in New England;
capital of the state of Vermont; located in north central Vermont;
a town in southwestern Vermont;
a town in southeastern Vermont on the Connecticut River;
the largest city in Vermont; located in northwestern Vermont on Lake Champlain; site of the University of Vermont;
a town in central Vermont;
a state in the eastern United States; one of the original 13 colonies; one of the Confederate States in the American Civil War;
one of the British colonies that formed the United States;
capital of the state of Virginia located in the east central part of the state; was capital of the Confederacy during the American Civil War;
a university town in southwestern Virginia (west of Roanoke) in the Allegheny Mountains;
a former village on the James River in Virginia to the north of Norfolk; site of the first permanent English settlement in America in 1607;
a port city in southeastern Virginia at the mouth of the James River off Hampton Roads; large shipyards;
port city located in southeastern Virginia on the Elizabeth River at the mouth of Chesapeake Bay; headquarters of the Atlantic fleet of the United States Navy;
a city in central Virginia;
a port city in southeastern Virginia on the Elizabeth River opposite Norfolk; naval base; shipyards;
a city in southwestern Virginia;
the largest city in Virginia; long overshadowed by Norfolk but growing rapidly since 1970; with 28 miles of public beaches tourism is a major factor in the economy; site of three United States Navy bases;
a creek in northeastern Virginia where two battles were fought in the American Civil War;
a village in northeastern Virginia;
a town in northeastern Virginia on the Rappahannock River;
a town in southeastern Virginia (south of Richmond); scene of heavy fighting during the American Civil War;
a village in northeastern Virginia where battles were fought during the American Civil War;
a historic village in southeastern Virginia to the north of Newport News; site of the last battle of the American Revolution;
the former residence of George Washington in northeastern Virginia overlooking the Potomac river;
a state in northwestern United States on the Pacific;
a town in western Washington;
a town in northwestern Washington on a bay near the Canadian border;
a town in southern Washington on the Columbia River;
capital of the state of Washington; located in western Washington on Puget Sound;
a major port of entry and the largest city in Washington; located in west central Washington on the protected waters of Puget Sound with the snow-capped peaks of the Cascade Range and Mount Ranier visible to the south and east; an aerospace and computer center; site of the University of Washington;
a city in eastern Washington near the Idaho border;
a city in west central Washington on an arm of Puget Sound to the south of Seattle;
a town in southwestern Washington on the Columbia River across from Portland, Oregon;
