a fried ball or patty of flaked fish and mashed potatoes;
a small cake with a hard surface said to resemble a rock;
a cake consisting of two layers of sponge cake with a jelly filling in between;
a long fillet of fish breaded and fried;
fruit preserved by cooking with sugar;
thick dark spicy puree of apples;
a Chinese preserve of mixed fruits and ginger;
preserve of crushed fruit;
a conserve with a thick consistency; made with lemons and butter and eggs and sugar;
made with strawberries;
a preserve made of the jelled juice of fruit;
jelly made from apple juice;
a tart apple jelly made from crab apples;
jelly made from grape juice;
a preserve made of the pulp and rind of citrus fruits;
marmalade made from oranges;
an edible jelly (sweet or pungent) made with gelatin and used as a dessert or salad base or a coating for foods;
jellied dessert made with gelatin and fruit juice or water;
the flesh of a bird or fowl (wild or domestic) used as food;
flesh of chickens or turkeys or ducks or geese raised for food;
the flesh of a chicken used for food;
flesh of a small young chicken not over 2 1/2 lb suitable for broiling;
flesh of a castrated male chicken;
flesh of a medium-sized young chicken suitable for frying;
flesh of a large young chicken over 3 1/2 lb suitable for roasting;
a brand name for a roasting chicken;
flesh of a chicken (or game bird) split down the back and grilled (usually immediately after being killed);
flesh of an older chicken suitable for stewing;
flesh of a small fowl bred for roasting;
flesh of a guinea fowl (especially of hens);
flesh of a pigeon suitable for roasting or braising; flesh of a dove (young squab) may be broiled;
flesh of a duck (domestic or wild);
flesh of a young domestic duck;
flesh of a goose (domestic or wild);
flesh of any of a number of wild game birds suitable for food;
flesh of any of various grouse of the family Tetraonidae; usually roasted; flesh too dry to broil;
flesh of quail; suitable for roasting or broiling if young; otherwise must be braised;
flesh of either quail or grouse;
flesh of a pheasant; usually braised;
flesh of large domesticated fowl usually roasted;
the lower joint of the leg of a fowl;
the lower joint of the leg of a turkey;
the lower joint of the leg of a chicken;
the upper joint of the leg of a fowl;
meat carved from the breast of a fowl;
the wing of a fowl; he preferred the drumsticks to the wings;
the wing of a turkey;
the wing of a chicken;
crisp spicy chicken wings;
chicken wings cooked in barbecue sauce;
edible viscera of a fowl;
a circular helping of food (especially a boneless cut of meat); medallions of veal;
a small muscle on each side of the back of a fowl;
the tail of a dressed fowl;
a quantity of food (other than bread) formed in a particular shape; meat loaf; sugar loaf; a loaf of cheese;
the flesh of animals (including fishes and birds and snails) used as food;
the flesh of wild animals that is used for food;
the flesh of the legs of fowl used as food;
soft semiliquid food; a mess of porridge;
food chopped into small bits; a mince of mushrooms;
food prepared by cooking and straining or processed in a blender;
uncooked meat;
a lump or chunk of raw meat;
meat that is dark in color before cooking (as beef, venison, lamb, mutton);
edible viscera of a butchered animal;
viscera and trimmings of a butchered animal often considered inedible by humans;
a firm rather dry variety meat (usually beef or veal); a five-pound beef heart will serve six;
liver of an animal used as meat;
liver of a calf used as meat;
liver of a chicken used as meat;
liver of a goose used as meat;
edible glands of an animal;
the brain of certain animals used as meat;
the brain of a calf eaten as meat;
edible pancreas of an animal;
edible thymus gland of an animal;
the tongue of certain animals used as meat;
the tongue of a cow eaten as meat;
the tongue of a calf eaten as meat;
meat from a deer used as food;
a piece of meat that has been cut from an animal carcass;
a small cut of meat including part of a rib;
meat that has been barbecued or grilled in a highly seasoned sauce;
an Indian dish made with highly seasoned rice and meat or fish or vegetables;
sliced assorted cold meats;
cut of meat or fish including at least part of the backbone;
a serving that has been cut from a larger portion; a piece of pie; a slice of bread;
thin slice of meat (especially veal) usually fried or broiled;
lightly sauteed veal cutlets spread with a Soubise sauce and liver paste then sprinkled with grated Parmesan and baked briefly;
a dish of sauteed food;
a longitudinal slice or boned side of a fish;
the limb of an animal used for food;
a lengthwise dressed half of an animal's carcass used for food;
dressed half of a beef carcass;
the front half of a side of meat;
the back half of a side of meat;
cut of meat from beef cattle;
the part of a forequarter from the neck to the ribs and including the shoulder blade;
between the chuck and the brisket;
cut of meat including one or more ribs;
