an animal order including lemurs and tarsiers and monkeys and apes and human beings;
any placental mammal of the order Primates; has good eyesight and flexible hands and feet;
an ape or monkey;
any of various primates with short tails or no tail at all;
monkeys; apes; hominids;
any member of the suborder Anthropoidea including monkeys and apes and hominids;
any tailless ape of the families Pongidae and Hylobatidae;
anthropoid apes and human beings;
a primate of the superfamily Hominoidea;
modern man and extinct immediate ancestors of man;
a primate of the family Hominidae;
type genus of the family Hominidae;
any living or extinct member of the family Hominidae characterized by superior intelligence, articulate speech, and erect carriage;
all of the living human inhabitants of the earth; all the world loves a lover; she always used humankindbecause mankindseemed to slight the women;
extinct species of primitive hominid with upright stature but small brain; Homo erectus was formerly called Pithecanthropus erectus;
former genus of primitive apelike men now Homo erectus;
fossil remains found in Java; formerly called Pithecanthropus erectus;
fossils found near Beijing, China; they were lost during World War II;
genus to which Peking man was formerly assigned;
extinct primitive hominid of late Pleistocene; Java; formerly Javanthropus;
former genus of primitive man; now Homo soloensis: comprises Solo man;
early man of late Pleistocene; skull resembles that of Neanderthal man but with smaller cranial capacity; found in Java;
extinct species of upright East African hominid having some advanced humanlike characteristics;
the only surviving hominid; species to which modern man belongs; bipedal primate having language and ability to make and use complex tools; brain volume at least 1400 cc;
extinct robust human of Middle Paleolithic in Europe and western Asia;
extinct human of Upper Paleolithic in Europe;
possible early Homo sapiens represented by a cranium found in the Transvaal; formerly considered a separate species;
subspecies of Homo sapiens; includes all modern races;
extinct genus of African hominid;
former name for the genus Australopithecus;
any of several extinct humanlike bipedal primates with relatively small brains of the genus Australopithecus; from 1 to 4 million years ago;
fossils found in Ethiopia; from 3.5 to 4 million years ago;
incomplete skeleton of female found in eastern Ethiopia in 1974;
gracile hominid of southern Africa; from about 3 million years ago;
large-toothed hominid of eastern Africa; from 1 to 2 million years ago;
genus to which Australopithecus boisei was formerly assigned;
large-toothed hominid of southern Africa; from 1.5 to 2 million years ago; formerly Paranthropus;
former classification for Australopithecus robustus;
extinct primates; lower Pliocene;
fossil primates found in India;
genus of Old World hominoids; Miocene and Pliocene;
considered a possible ancestor to both anthropoid apes and humans;
fossil hominoids from northern central Hungary; late Miocene;
a genus of Hominidae;
a genus of Hominidae;
genus of extinct primitive African primates of the Miocene epoch; sometimes considered a subgenus of Dryopithecus;
an anthropoid ape of the genus Proconsul;
extinct primate having powerful chewing muscles along with large molars and small incisors; fossils found in Kenya;
a genus of Hominoidea;
extinct primate of about 38 million years ago; fossils found in Egypt;
an extinct genus of Hominoidea;
tiny (150 to 300 grams) extinct primate of 46 to 50 million years ago; fossils found in Algeria; considered by some authorities the leading candidate for the first anthropoid;
usually considered as comprising orangutans; gorillas; chimpanzees; and sometimes gibbons;
any of the large anthropoid apes of the family Pongidae;
type genus of the family Pongidae: orangutans;
large long-armed ape of Borneo and Sumatra having arboreal habits;
gorillas;
largest anthropoid ape; terrestrial and vegetarian; of forests of central west Africa;
a kind of gorilla;
a kind of gorilla;
gorilla of Kivu highlands;
an adult male gorilla with grey hairs across the back;
chimpanzees; more closely related to Australopithecus than to other pongids;
intelligent somewhat arboreal ape of equatorial African forests;
masked or pale-faced chimpanzees of western Africa; distantly related to the eastern and central chimpanzees; possibly a distinct species;
long-haired chimpanzees of east-central Africa; closely related to the central chimpanzees;
black-faced chimpanzees of central Africa; closely related to eastern chimpanzees;
small chimpanzee of swamp forests in Zaire; a threatened species;
used in some classifications for the lesser apes (gibbons and siamangs); sometimes considered a subfamily of Pongidae;
gibbons and siamangs;
gibbons;
smallest and most perfectly anthropoid arboreal ape having long arms and no tail; of southern Asia and East Indies;
used in some classifications for the siamangs;
large black gibbon of Sumatra having the 2nd and 3rd toes partially united by a web;
(Old World monkeys) guenon; baboon; colobus monkey; langur; macaque; mandrill; mangabey; patas; proboscis monkey;
any of various long-tailed primates (excluding the prosimians);
of Africa or Arabia or Asia; having nonprehensile tails and nostrils close together;
type genus of the Cercopithecidae: guenons;
small slender African monkey having long hind limbs and tail and long hair around the face;
smallest guenon monkey; of swampy central and west African forests;
white and olive green East African monkey with long white tufts of hair beside the face;
South African monkey with black face and hands;
common savannah monkey with greenish-grey back and yellow tail;
mangabeys;
large agile arboreal monkey with long limbs and tail and white upper eyelids;
patas;
reddish long-tailed monkey of west Africa;
large terrestrial monkeys having doglike muzzles;
baboons;
greyish baboon of southern and eastern Africa;
baboons;
baboon of west Africa with a bright red and blue muzzle and blue hindquarters;
similar to the mandrill but smaller and less brightly colored;
macaques; rhesus monkeys;
short-tailed monkey of rocky regions of Asia and Africa;
of southern Asia; used in medical research;
Indian macaque with a bonnet-like tuft of hair;
tailless macaque of rocky cliffs and forests of northwestern Africa and Gibraltar;
monkey of southeast Asia, Borneo and the Philippines;
langurs;
