forward projecting part of the head of certain animals; includes the jaws and nose;
a long projecting or anterior elongation of an animal's head; especially the nose;
beaklike projection of the anterior part of the head of certain insects such as e.g. weevils;
a long flexible snout as of an elephant;
any of various nonruminant hoofed mammals having very thick skin: elephant; rhinoceros; hippopotamus;
order of mammals having few or no teeth including: New World anteaters; sloths; armadillos;
primitive terrestrial mammal with few if any teeth; of tropical Central America and South America;
armadillos; American anteaters; sloths;
armadillos;
burrowing chiefly nocturnal mammal with body covered with strong horny plates;
type genus of the Dasypodidae;
having nine hinged bands of bony plates; ranges from Texas to Paraguay;
a genus of Dasypodidae;
South American armadillo with three bands of bony plates;
solely the tatouay;
naked-tailed armadillo of tropical South America;
a genus of Dasypodidae;
Argentine armadillo with six movable bands and hairy underparts;
solely the giant armadillo;
about three feet long exclusive of tail;
pichiciago;
very small Argentine armadillo with pale silky hair and pink plates on head and neck;
a genus of Dasypodidae;
of southern South America;
a family of edentates comprising the true sloths;
any of several slow-moving arboreal mammals of South America and Central America; they hang from branches back downward and feed on leaves and fruits;
type genus of the Bradypodidae: three-toed sloths;
a sloth that has three long claws on each forefoot and each hindfoot;
mammal family consisting of the two-toed sloths;
a genus of Megalonychidae consisting of the two-toed sloth;
relatively small fast-moving sloth with two long claws on each front foot;
a sloth of Central America that has two long claws on each forefoot and three long claws on each hindfoot;
extinct ground sloths;
a large extinct ground sloth;
type genus of the Megatheriidae;
gigantic extinct terrestrial sloth-like mammal of the Pliocene and Pleistocene in America;
extinct South American edentates;
a variety of extinct edentate;
type genus of the Mylodontidae; sometimes included in family Megatheriidae;
large (bear-sized) extinct edentate mammal of the Pleistocene in South America;
supposed human-sized sloth-like creature reportedly sighted by Indians in the Amazon rain forest;
New World anteaters;
any of several tropical American mammals of the family Myrmecophagidae which lack teeth and feed on ants and termites;
type genus of the Myrmecophagidae; South American ant bear;
large shaggy-haired toothless anteater with long tongue and powerful claws; of South America;
only the silky anteater;
squirrel-sized South American toothless anteater with long silky golden fur;
lesser anteater;
small toothless anteater with prehensile tail and four-clawed forelimbs; of tropical South America and Central America;
pangolins; in some former classifications included in the order Edentata;
coextensive with the order Pholidota;
type genus of the Manidae;
toothless mammal of southern Africa and Asia having a body covered with horny scales and a long snout for feeding on ants and termites;
the part between the fetlock and the hoof;
margin between the skin of the pastern and the horn of the hoof;
projection behind and above a horse's hoof;
the joint between the cannon bone and the pastern;
the highest part of the back at the base of the neck of various animals especially draft animals;
lower part of the leg extending from the hock to the fetlock in hoofed mammals;
greatly developed metatarsal or metacarpal bone in the shank or cannon part of the leg in hoofed mammals;
tarsal joint of the hind leg of hoofed mammals; corresponds to the human ankle;
either side of the backbone between the hipbone and the ribs in humans as well as quadrupeds;
the part of an animal that corresponds to the human buttocks;
the loin and leg of a quadruped;
lower part of a horse's thigh between the hock and the stifle;
joint between the femur and tibia in a quadruped; corresponds to the human knee;
the side between ribs and hipbone;
the leg of an animal;
a posterior appendage such as a leg or the homologous structure in other animals;
the back limb of a quadruped;
the front limb (or the homologous structure in other animals, such as a flipper or wing);
the forelimb of a quadruped;
the flat broad limb of aquatic animals specialized for swimming;
one of a pair of fleshy appendages of a polychete annelid that functions in locomotion and breathing;
an organ specialized for sucking nourishment or for adhering to objects by suction;
a sucker on the feet of certain flies;
a sharp organ of offense or defense (as of a wasp or stingray or scorpion) often connected with a poison gland;
sense organs of fish and amphibians; believed to detect pressure changes in the water;
organ of locomotion and balance in fishes and some other aquatic animals;
unpaired median fin on the backs of fishes and some other aquatic vertebrates that help to maintain balance;
either of a pair of fins situated just behind the head in fishes that help control the direction of movement;
either of a pair of fins attached to the pelvic girdle in fishes that help control the direction of movement; correspond to hind limbs of a land vertebrate;
the tail of fishes and some other aquatic vertebrates;
a tail fin with unequal lobes in which the vertebral column turns upward into the larger lobe as in sharks;
symmetrical tail fin extending beyond the end of the vertebral column as in most bony fishes;
a bone of a fish;
an air-filled sac near the spinal column in many fishes that helps maintain buoyancy;
any of the membranous air-filled extensions of the lungs of birds;
any of the thin-walled extensions of the tracheae of insects;
oil-secreting gland situated at the base of the tail in most birds;
silk-producing gland of insects (especially of a silkworm) or spiders;
the joint of a mammal or bird that corresponds to the human elbow;
a small horny callus on the inner surface of a horse's leg;
the hollow spine of a feather;
one of the horny ribs that stiffen and support the wing of an insect;
any of the larger wing or tail feathers of a bird;
one of the main flight feathers projecting along the outer edge of a bird's wing;
a feather covering the shoulder of a bird;
feather growing from the tail (uropygium) of a bird;
a larval frog or toad;
