any heating apparatus;
a kitchen appliance used for cooking food; dinner was already on the stove;
a small machine bolt;
chimney consisting of a metal pipe of large diameter that is used to connect a stove to a flue;
plate iron that is thinner than tank iron;
a violin made by Antonio Stradivari or a member of his family;
a straight segment of a roadway or racecourse;
a straight-backed chair without arms;
hand tool consisting of a flat rigid rectangular bar (metal or wood) that can be used to draw straight lines (or test their straightness);
a device for straightening; a hair straightener;
a rock drill with flutes that are straight;
pin consisting of a short straight stiff piece of wire with a pointed end; used to fasten pieces of cloth or paper together;
a razor with a straight cutting edge enclosed in a case that forms a handle when the razor is opened for use;
a filter to retain larger pieces while smaller pieces and liquids pass through;
a gauge for measuring strain in a surface;
a garment similar to a jacket that is used to bind the arms tightly against the body as a means of restraining a violent person;
line consisting of a complex of fibers or filaments that are twisted together to form a thread or a rope or a cable;
whip consisting of a strip of leather used in flogging;
an elongated leather strip (or a strip of similar material) for binding things together or holding something in position;
a band that goes over the shoulder and supports a garment or bag;
hanger consisting of a loop of leather suspended from the ceiling of a bus or train; passengers hold onto it;
a hinge with two long straps; one strap is fastened to the surface of a moving part (e.g., a door or lid) and the other is fastened to the adjacent stationary frame;
a woman's garment that exposes the shoulders and has no shoulder straps;
a thin paper or plastic tube used to suck liquids into the mouth;
an artificial fly that has wings extending back beyond the crook of the fishhook;
a streamlined train;
a thoroughfare (usually including sidewalks) that is lined with buildings; they walked the streets of the small town; he lives on Nassau Street;
the part of a thoroughfare between the sidewalks; the part of the thoroughfare on which vehicles travel; be careful crossing the street;
a wheeled vehicle that runs on rails and is propelled by electricity;
ordinary clothing suitable for public appearances (as opposed to costumes or sports apparel or work clothes etc.);
a lamp supported on a lamppost; for illuminating a street;
a device designed to provide additional strength; the cardboard backing was just a strengthener; he used gummed reinforcements to hold the page in his notebook;
an antibiotic produced by the actinomycete Streptomyces griseus and used to treat tuberculosis;
a basic antibiotic derived from a soil actinomycete;
a straightaway section of a racetrack;
a litter for transporting people who are ill or wounded or dead; usually consists of a sheet of canvas stretched between two poles;
a mechanical device used to make something larger (as shoes or gloves) by stretching it;
a wooden framework on which canvas is stretched and fixed for oil painting;
trousers made of a stretchy fabric;
a tool used in a foundry to shape a mold in sand;
a tool or rod used to level off grain or other granular material that is heaped in a measure;
an implement for sharpening scythes;
the part of a mechanical device that strikes something;
a lightweight cord;
a tightly stretched cord of wire or gut, which makes sound when plucked, struck, or bowed;
a collection of objects threaded on a single strand;
a musical instrument in which taut strings provide the source of sound;
a long horizontal timber to connect uprights;
brace consisting of a longitudinal member to strengthen a fuselage or hull;
a very narrow necktie usually tied in a bow;
artifact consisting of a narrow flat piece of material;
thin piece of wood or metal;
light consisting of long tubes (instead of bulbs) that provide the illumination;
a mercantile establishment consisting of a row of various stores and business and restaurants along a road or busy street; usually opening on a parking lot;
an open mine (usually for coal) where the seams run close to the surface;
an oil well whose production has declined to less than ten barrels a day;
scientific instrument that provides a flashing light synchronized with the periodic movement of an object; can make moving object appear stationary;
a strongly made box for holding money or valuables; can be locked;
a strongly fortified defensive structure;
a burglarproof and fireproof room in which valuables are kept;
a leather strap used to sharpen razors;
support that is a constituent part of any structure or building;
a thing constructed; a complex entity constructed of many parts; the structure consisted of a series of arches; she wore her hair in an amazing construction of whirls and ribbons;
brace consisting of a bar or rod used to resist longitudinal compression;
a short thick nail;
ornament consisting of a circular rounded protuberance (as on a vault or shield or belt);
a center for student activities at a college or university;
a reading lamp with a flexible neck; used on a desk;
a building on a college campus dedicated to social and organizational activities of the student body;
a farm where horses are bred;
a small permanent magnet in a metal container; when the magnet clicks against the container it indicates that the magnet is directly over an iron nail that holds the wallboard to a stud;
workplace for the teaching or practice of an art; she ran a dance studio; the music department provided studios for their students; you don't need a studio to make a passport photograph;
workplace consisting of a room or building where movies or television shows or radio programs are produced and recorded;
an apartment with a living space and a bathroom and a small kitchen;
convertible consisting of an upholstered couch that can be converted into a double bed;
a room used for reading and writing and studying; he knocked lightly on the closed door of the study;
a classroom reserved for study;
miscellaneous unspecified objects; the trunk was full of stuff;
padding put in mattresses and cushions and upholstered furniture;
a small chamber in which packing is compressed around a reciprocating shaft or piston to form a seal;
a nut used to tighten a stuffing box;
any obstacle or impediment;
(cricket) any of three upright wooden posts that form the wicket;
a weapon designed to disable a victim temporarily by delivering a nonlethal high-voltage electric shock;
a dome-shaped shrine erected by Buddhists;
a pen for swine;
a pointed tool for writing or drawing or engraving; he drew the design on the stencil with a steel stylus;
a sharp pointed device attached to the cartridge of a record player;
a unit assembled separately but designed to fit with other units in a manufactured product;
the lowest molding of an architectural base or of a baseboard;
a car smaller than a compact car;
something (a person or object or scene) selected by an artist or photographer for graphic representation; a moving picture of a train is more dramatic than a still picture of the same subject;
machine gun that is a portable automatic firearm;
a submersible warship usually armed with torpedoes;
a torpedo designed to be launched from a submarine;
a warship designed to operate under water;
an apparatus intended for use under water;
a section of a section; a part of a part; i.e., a part of something already divided;
a subsidiary station where electricity is transformed for distribution by a low-voltage network;
a polypeptide antibiotic (similar to bacitracin) obtained from a soil bacterium;
