a port city in southwestern Norway; center for shipbuilding industry;
a port in central Norway on Trondheim Fjord;
a cape at the southern tip of Norway;
a Scandinavian kingdom in the eastern part of the Scandinavian Peninsula;
the capital and largest city of Sweden; located in southern Sweden on the Baltic; the Nobel Prize is awarded in Stockholm;
a port in southern Sweden;
a city in southern Sweden;
a port in southwestern Sweden; second largest city in Sweden;
a city in east central Sweden to the northwest of Stockholm;
a republic in central Europe; split into East Germany and West Germany after World War II and reunited in 1990;
a republic in north central Europe on the Baltic; established by the Soviet Union in 1954; reunified with West Germany in 1990;
a republic in north central Europe on the North Sea; established in 1949 from the zones of Germany occupied by the British and French and Americans after the German defeat; reunified with East Germany in 1990;
an area in Germany around the upper Elbe river; the original home of the Saxons;
a state in northwestern Germany;
a city in western Germany near the Dutch and Belgian borders; formerly it was Charlemagne's northern capital;
capital of Germany located in eastern Germany;
the part of Berlin under United States and British and French control until 1989;
a city of northwestern Germany linked by the Weser River to the port of Bremerhaven and the North Sea; in the Middle Ages it was a leading member of the Hanseatic League;
a port city in northwestern Germany at the mouth of the Weser River on the North Sea; has a deep natural harbor and is an important shipping center;
a city in east central Germany; formerly called Karl-Marx-Stadt until 1990; noted for textile manufacturing;
an industrial city in northwestern Germany; flourished from the 13th to 17th century as a member of the Hanseatic League;
a city in southeastern Germany on the Elbe River; it was almost totally destroyed by British air raids in 1945;
a city in southeastern Germany famous for fairs; formerly a music and publishing center;
a city in west central Germany noted for cutlery;
a German city near Leipzig; scene of the adoption in 1919 of the constitution of the Weimar Republic that lasted until 1933;
a state in southern Germany famous for its beer; site of an automobile factory;
a town in northern Germany (near Hanover) that is famous as the setting for the legend of the Pied Piper;
a town in Bavaria (near Munich);
a city in western Germany on the Rhine River; was the capital of West Germany between 1949 and 1989;
a commercial center and river port in western Germany on the Rhine River; flourished during the 15th century as a member of the Hanseatic League;
a city in central Germany;
an industrial city in western Germany on the Rhine;
a city in western Germany; industrial center of the Ruhr;
a German city; an industrial and commercial and financial center;
a city in the Saxony region of Germany on the Saale River; a member of the Hanseatic League during the 13th and 14th centuries;
a port city in northern Germany on the Elbe River that was founded by Charlemagne in the 9th century and is today the largest port in Germany; in 1241 it formed an alliance with Lubeck that became the basis for the Hanseatic League;
a port city in northwestern Germany; formerly a member of the Hanseatic League;
a city in northwestern Germany and an important Baltic port; a leading member of the Hanseatic League;
a city in southwestern Germany at the confluence of the Rhine and Neckar rivers;
the capital and largest city of Bavaria in southwestern Germany;
a city in southeastern Germany; site of Allied trials of Nazi war criminals (1945-46 );
a city in northeastern Germany; site of the Potsdam Conference in the summer of 1945;
a city in northeastern Germany near the Baltic sea; an important member of the Hanseatic League in the 14th century;
a city in southwestern Germany famous for innovative architecture;
a city in western Germany; a spa since Roman times;
a city of south central Germany;
a picturesque region of Germany around the Rhine river;
a territory in southwestern Germany formerly ruled by the counts palatine;
the territory of an Elector (of the Holy Roman Empire) that expanded to become the kingdom of Prussia in 1701;
a former kingdom in north-central Europe including present-day northern Germany and northern Poland; in the 19th century Prussia led the economic and political unification of the German states;
a major industrial and coal mining region in the valley of the Ruhr river in northwestern Germany;
a historical region of southern Germany;
a former Portuguese colony that was annexed by Indonesia in 1976; voted for independence from Indonesia in 1999 and in May 2002 became an independent nation;
a republic in northwestern South America; became independent from Spain in 1822; the landscape is dominated by the Andes;
the largest city of Ecuador;
the capital of Ecuador;
a group of islands in the Pacific off South America; owned by Ecuador; known for unusual animal life;
an African country to the north of Ethiopia on the Red Sea; achieved independence from Ethiopia in 1993;
the capital of Eritrea;
a port town in Eritrea on an inlet of the Red Sea;
Ethiopia is a republic in northeastern Africa on the Red Sea; formerly called Abyssinia;
the capital of Ethiopia and the country's largest city; located in central Ethiopia;
a group of more than 800 islands (100 inhabited) in the southwestern Pacific; larger islands (Viti Levu and Vanua Levu) are of volcanic origin surrounded by coral reefs; smaller islands are coral;
a volcanic island in the Fijis;
a volcanic island in the Fijis;
an independent state within the British Commonwealth located on the Fiji Islands;
the capital and largest city of Fiji (on Viti Levu island);
republic in northern Europe; achieved independence from Russia in 1917;
a region in Finland and Russia between the Gulf of Finland and the White Sea;
the capital and largest city of Finland; located in southern Finland; a major port and commercial and cultural center;
a city in southern Finland;
an industrial city in south central Finland;
an archipelago of some 6,000 islands in the Gulf of Bothnia under Finnish control;
a town that is the chief port of the Aland islands;
a republic in southeastern Europe on the southern part of the Balkan peninsula; known for grapes and olives and olive oil;
ancient Greece; a country of city-states (especially Athens and Sparta) that reached its peak in the fifth century BCE;
a region of ancient Greece on the north coast of the Peloponnese;
an island in the Aegean Sea;
an island in the Aegean Sea in the Saronic Gulf;
an island in the Aegean Sea off the west coast of Turkey; belongs to Greece;
a group of over 200 islands in the southern Aegean;
a group of islands in the southeast Aegean Sea;
a small region of ancient Greece where the Doric dialect was spoken;
an island of eastern Greece in the eastern Aegean Sea; in antiquity it was famous for lyric poetry;
a Greek island in the southeast Aegean Sea 10 miles off the Turkish coast; the largest of the Dodecanese; it was colonized before 1000 BC by Dorians from Argos; site of the Colossus of Rhodes;
an ancient coastal region of northwestern Asia Minor (including Lesbos) where the Aeolians founded several cities around 1100 BC;
the largest Greek island in the Mediterranean; site of the Minoan civilization that reached its peak in 1600 BC;
an ancient town on Crete where Bronze Age culture flourished from about 2000 BC to 1400 BC;
a Greek island to the west of Greece; in Homeric legend Odysseus was its king;
a group of islands off the west coast of Sicily in the Mediterranean;
an autonomous area in northeastern Greece that is the site of several Greek Orthodox monasteries founded in the tenth century;
the capital and largest city of Greece; named after Athena (its patron goddess); in the 5th century BC ancient Athens was the world's most powerful and civilized city;
a hill to the to the west of the Athenian acropolis where met the highest governmental council of ancient Athens and later a judicial court;
a gateway to the west of ancient Athens near which a distinctive style of pottery has been found;
an ancient town on a promontory in western Greece;
the territory of Athens in ancient Greece where the Ionic dialect was spoken;
the modern Greek port near the site of the ancient city that was second only to Athens;
an ancient city in southeastern Greece; dominated the Peloponnese in the 7th century BC;
an ancient Greek city on the slopes of Mount Parnassus; site of the oracle of Delphi;
an ancient city is southern Greece; center of the Mycenaean civilization during the late Bronze Age;
