a province in north-central China; formerly part of the Silk Road to Turkistan and India and Persia;
a populous province in northeastern China;
a province in southeastern central China between the Nan Ling mountains and the Chang Jiang; noted for its timber and valuable mineral resources;
a populous province of south central China;
a province of southern China;
the capital city of the Chinese province of Gansu on the Yellow River;
an industrial conurbation in northeastern China on the southern end of the Liaodong Peninsula; it now includes the cities of Dalian and Lushun;
a port and shipbuilding center in northeastern China on the Liaodong Peninsula; now a part of Luda;
a city in east central China; the capital of ancient China during several dynasties;
a major port city in northeastern China on the Liaodong Peninsula; now a part of Luda;
a city of eastern China on Hangzhou Bay; regarded by Marco Polo as the finest city in the world;
a walled city in southeastern China on the Gan Jiang;
an industrial city in southern China;
a city in eastern China on the Yangtze River; a former capital of China; the scene of a Japanese massacre in the 1930s;
the largest city of China; located in the east on the Pacific; one of the largest ports in the world;
a city in northeastern China;
an ancient city in northeastern China noted for coal mining and steel production;
an industrial city of northeastern China in Hebei province;
a major industrial center in northeastern China on the Grand Canal near the Yellow Sea; 3rd largest city in China;
an inland waterway 1000 miles long in eastern China; extends from Tianjin in the north to Hangzhou in the south;
a city of central China on the Chang Jiang; the commercial and industrial center of central China;
a city of central China; capital of ancient Chinese empire 221-206 BC;
an autonomous province in far northwestern China on the border with Mongolia and Kazakhstan; the largest province in the People's Republic of China and the homeland of the Uighur people;
an autonomous region of northeastern China that was annexed by the Manchu rulers in 1635 and became an integral part of China in 1911;
a northern industrial city of China to the northwest of Beijing;
an island in southeastern Asia 100 miles off the coast of mainland China in the South China Sea;
a government on the island of Taiwan established in 1949 by Chiang Kai-shek after the conquest of mainland China by the Communists led by Mao Zedong;
the capital of Nationalist China; located in northern Taiwan;
a city in Taiwan;
formerly a Crown Colony on the coast of southern China in Guangdong province; leased by China to Britain in 1842 and returned in 1997; one of the world's leading commercial centers;
a former Portuguese province on the south coast of China and two islands in the South China Sea; reverted to China in 1999;
a peninsula of southeastern Asia that includes Myanmar and Cambodia and Laos and Malaysia and Thailand and Vietnam;
the French colonies of the territory now occupied by Cambodia, Laos, and Vietnam;
a republic in northwestern South America with a coastline on the Pacific Ocean and the Caribbean Sea; achieved independence from Spain in 1821 under the leadership of Simon Bolivar; Spanish is the official language;
a port city of northern Colombia near the Caribbean on the Magdalena River;
capital and largest city of Colombia; located in central Colombia on a high fertile plain;
city in southwestern Colombia in a rich agricultural area;
city in western Colombia; important coffee center;
a port city in northwestern Colombia on the Caribbean;
a city in northern Colombia; a suburb of Barranquilla;
three main islands and numerous islets in the Indian Ocean between Mozambique and Madagascar;
a country on the Comoro Islands;
a republic in west-central Africa; achieved independence from France in 1960;
the capital and largest city of the Republic of the Congo;
a republic in central Africa; achieved independence from Belgium in 1960;
a city in eastern Congo at the northern end of Lake Kivu near the border with Rwanda;
a city in southwestern Congo; former name (until 1966) was Luluabourg;
the capital of the Democratic Republic of the Congo on the Congo river opposite Brazzaville;
a city in southeastern Congo near the border with Zambia; a copper mining center; former name (until 1966) was Elisabethville;
Mexico and Central America;
the isthmus joining North America and South America; extends from the southern border of Mexico to the northern border of Colombia;
a republic in Central America; one of the most politically stable countries in Latin America;
the capital and largest city of Costa Rica;
a republic in western Africa on the Gulf of Guinea; one of the most prosperous and politically stable countries in Africa;
city recognized by the United States as the capital of the Ivory Coast; largest city of the Ivory Coast;
capital of the Ivory Coast;
a republic in Central America; achieved independence from Spain in 1821; noted for low per capita income and illiteracy; politically unstable;
the capital and largest city of Guatemala;
a country on the northeastern coast of Central America on the Caribbean; formerly under British control;
a republic in Central America; achieved independence from Spain in 1821; an early center of Mayan culture;
the capital and largest city of Honduras;
industrial city in northwestern Honduras;
a republic on the Pacific coast of Central America;
the capital and largest city of El Salvador; has suffered from recurrent earthquakes;
a city in western El Salvador;
a republic in Central America; achieved independence from Spain in 1821;
the capital and largest city of Nicaragua;
a republic on the Isthmus of Panama; achieved independence from Colombia in 1903;
the capital and largest city of Panama;
a port city at the Caribbean entrance to the Panama Canal;
a zone consisting of a strip of land across the Isthmus of Panama that contains the Panama Canal;
a peninsula in Central America extending into the Gulf of Mexico between the Bay of Campeche and the Caribbean Sea;
a state of Mexico on the northern part of the Yucatan Peninsula;
the capital of the Mexican state of Yucatan;
a Mexican state on the eastern part of the Gulf of Campeche;
a Mexican city on the Bay of Campeche;
a popular island resort off the northeastern tip of the Yucatan peninsula;
a republic in southern North America; became independent from Spain in 1810;
a port and fashionable resort city on the Pacific coast of southern Mexico; known for beaches and water sports (including cliff diving);
a state in northern Mexico; mostly high plateau;
a city in northern Mexico in the state of Chihuahua; commercial center of northern Mexico;
a city in northern Mexico on the Rio Grande opposite El Paso;
a city in east central Mexico;
a state in northern Mexico; mostly high plateau;
a city in northwestern Mexico;
a city in north central Mexico; mining center;
a city in southwestern Mexico; a popular health resort and site of architecture from the Spanish colonial era;
a city in northwestern Mexico near the Gulf of California;
a city in central Mexico;
a city in northeastern Mexico opposite Brownsville near the mouth of the Rio Grande;
a port city in western Mexico on the Pacific Ocean; tourist center;
a city in northwestern Mexico near the California border;
the capital and largest city of Mexico is a political and cultural and commercial and industrial center; one of the world's largest cities;
an industrial city in northeastern Mexico;
a town in northern Mexico on the border of Arizona;
a city of southeastern Mexico;
a city of east central Mexico (west of Veracruz); a popular resort;
a city in south central Mexico (southeast of Mexico City) on the edge of central Mexican plateau;
a Mexican state on the eastern side of the Yucatan Peninsula;
a city in central Mexico;
