a mountainous area of Antarctica bounded by the Ross Sea and Wilkes Land;
a village park consisting of a plot of grassy land;
an overcrowded residential area;
a health resort near a spring or at the seaside;
a line corresponding to the surface of the water when the vessel is afloat on an even keel; often painted on the hull of a ship;
a line marking the level reached by a body of water;
a line marking the highest level reached;
a line marking the lowest level reached;
a ridge of land that separates two adjacent river systems;
the watershed of a continent (especially the watershed of North America formed by a series of mountain ridges extending from Alaska to Mexico);
that part of the continental divide formed by the Rocky Mountains in the United States;
a line leading to a place or point; he looked the other direction; didn't know the way home;
a route followed by traders (usually in caravans);
an ancient trade route between China and the Mediterranean (4,000 miles); followed by Marco Polo in the 13th century to reach Cathay;
a water route between the Atlantic Ocean and the Pacific Ocean along the northern coast of North America; Europeans since the 16th century had searched for a short route to the Far East before it was successfully traversed by Roald Amundsen (1903-1906 );
the direction or path along which something moves or along which it lies;
the heading or position of a vessel relative to the trim of its sails;
general line of orientation; the river takes a southern course; the northeastern trend of the coast;
in a direction parallel with lines of latitude;
in a direction parallel with lines of longitude;
the direction of the Kaaba toward which Muslims turn for their daily prayers;
a general direction in which something tends to move; the shoreward tendency of the current; the trend of the stock market;
(physics) an imaginary surface joining all points in space that are reached at the same instant by a wave propagating through a medium;
a coastal region of Antarctica on the Indian Ocean to the south of Australia; most of the territory is claimed by Australia;
the hemisphere that includes North America and South America;
the countries of (originally) Europe and (now including) North America and South America;
the region of the United States lying to the west of the Mississippi River;
the western United States during its frontier period;
a field planted with wheat;
the general location where something is; I questioned him about his whereabouts on the night of the crime;
a wild and uninhabited area left in its natural condition; it was a wilderness preserved for the hawks and mountaineers;
a small area at a racecourse where awards are given to the owners of winning horses;
the finishing line for a foot race; he broke the tape in record time;
the finishing line on a racetrack;
space allocated for your work (as in an office);
a tract of land enclosed for particular activities (sometimes paved and usually associated with buildings); they opened a repair yard on the edge of town;
(formerly) an enclosed field for tilting contests;
a tract of land where logs are accumulated;
the point above the observer that is directly opposite the nadir on the imaginary sphere against which celestial bodies appear to be projected;
the location of a planet in the zodiac at which it is believed to exert its maximum influence;
a belt-shaped region in the heavens on either side to the ecliptic; divided into 12 constellations or signs for astrological purposes;
(astrology) one of 12 equal areas into which the zodiac is divided;
the first sign of the zodiac which the sun enters at the vernal equinox; the sun is in this sign from about March 21 to April 19;
the second sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about April 20 to May 20;
the third sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about May 21 to June 20;
the fourth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about June 21 to July 22;
the fifth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about July 23 to August 22;
the sixth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about August 23 to September 22;
the seventh sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about September 23 to October 22;
the eighth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about October 23 to November 21;
the ninth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about November 22 to December 21;
the tenth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about December 22 to January 19;
the eleventh sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about January 20 to February 18;
the twelfth sign of the zodiac; the sun is in this sign from about February 19 to March 20;
a locally circumscribed place characterized by some distinctive features;
a neutral zone between two rival powers that is created in order to diminish the danger of conflict;
a military area where combat forces operate;
a combat zone where military operations are coordinated (especially a designated area in international waters where the rights of neutrals are not respected by nations at war);
an area in hostile territory that has been captured and is held awaiting further troops and supplies; an attempt to secure a bridgehead behind enemy lines; the only foothold left for British troops in Europe was Gibraltar;
a bridgehead seized by airborne troops;
a bridgehead on the enemy's shoreline seized by an amphibious operation; the Germans were desperately trying to contain the Anzio beachhead;
a city district known for its vice and high crime rate;
the territory claimed by a juvenile gang as its own;
a dangerous area;
a zone from which military forces or operations or installations are prohibited; tensions exist on both sides of the demilitarized zone separating North Korea and South Korea;
an agreed area where military supplies are dropped to ground troops;
an area where a battle has occurred with many fatalities;
(usually plural) an area where many people have died (usually by massacre or genocide during war or violent civil disturbance);
a city district where development receives special tax advantages;
a part of the city far removed from the center; they built a factory on the outskirts of the city;
(baseball) the area over home plate between a batter's knees and shoulders through which a pitch must pass in order to be called a strike;
an area subject to tidal action;
any of the 24 regions of the globe (loosely divided by longitude) throughout which the same standard time is used;
a six million square mile area that includes the Caribbean and the Gulf of Mexico and the eastern Pacific Ocean; includes the principal routes used by drug smugglers;
the capital city of a nation;
the capital city of a province;
the capital city of a political subdivision of a country;
the European mainland; Englishmen like to visit the Continent but they wouldn't like to live there;
any one of the countries occupying the European continent;
any one of the countries occupying Scandinavia;
the Balkan countries collectively;
any one of the countries on the Balkan Peninsula;
any one of the countries occupying the African continent;
a geographical area in eastern Africa;
a republic in southwestern Africa on the south Atlantic coast (formerly called South West Africa); achieved independence from South Africa in 1990; the greater part of Namibia forms part of the high Namibian plateau of South Africa;
capital of Namibia in the center of the country;
any one of the nations occupying the Asian continent;
an ancient country is eastern Asia Minor;
an ancient country in central Asia Minor;
an ancient country in western and central Asia Minor;
an ancient city in south western Phrygia in Asia Minor; site of an early Christian Church;
an ancient region of northern Asia Minor on the Black Sea; it reached its height under Mithridates VI but was later incorporated into the Roman Empire;
a peninsula in southwestern Asia that forms the Asian part of Turkey;
any one of the countries occupying the South American continent;
any country on the North American continent;
any one of the countries occupying Central America; these countries (except for Belize and Costa Rica) are characterized by low per capita income and unstable governments;
a mountainous landlocked country in central Asia; bordered by Iran to the west and Russia to the north and Pakistan to the east and south; Soviet troops invaded Afghanistan in 1979;
a city in northwestern Afghanistan on the site of several ancient cities;
a town in eastern Afghanistan (east of Kabul);
the capital and largest city of Afghanistan; located in eastern Afghanistan;
