closely confined;
confined or shut in by heavy snow;
delayed or confined or cut off by a storm; the airport was filled with stormbound passengers;
delayed or shut in by bad weather; weather-bound traffic; irritable weather-bound children;
not confined;
of livestock and domestic poultry; permitted to graze or forage rather than being confined to a feedlot;
overfilled or compacted or concentrated; a crowded theater; a crowded program; crowded trains; a young mother's crowded days;
crowded or massed together; give me...your huddled masses; the huddled sheep turned their backs against the wind;
filled to capacity; a suitcase jammed with dirty clothes; stands jam-packed with fans; a packed theater;
filled with great numbers crowded together; I try to avoid the thronged streets and stores just before Christmas;
having or allowing sufficient room; an uncrowded train; an uncrowded view;
suitable to your needs; a congenial atmosphere to work in; two congenial spirits united...by mutual confidence and reciprocal virtues- T.L.Peacock;
friendly and pleasant; a sociable gathering;
not suitable to your tastes or needs; the uncongenial roommates were always fighting; the task was uncongenial to one sensitive to rebuffs;
not agreeing with your tastes or expectations; found the task disagreeable and decided to abandon it; a job temperamentally unsympathetic to him;
coinciding when superimposed;
matching point for point; coincident circles;
coinciding exactly when superimposed; identical triangles;
not congruent;
corresponding in character or kind;
suitable and fitting; the tailored clothes were harmonious with her military bearing;
lacking in harmony or compatibility or appropriateness; a plan incongruous with reason; incongruous behavior; a joke that was incongruous with polite conversation;
not in agreement;
not in keeping with what is correct or proper; completely inappropriate behavior;
lacking in harmony of parts; an inharmonious (or incongruous) mixture of architectural styles;
characterized by often poignant difference or incongruity between what is expected and what actually is; madness, an ironic fate for such a clear thinker; it was ironical that the well-planned scheme failed so completely;
serving or tending to connect;
syntactically connecting sentences or elements of a sentence; andis a copulative conjunction;
connecting or tending to connect; connective remarks between chapters; connective tissue in animals; conjunctive tissue in plants;
serving or tending to divide or separate;
expressing antithesis or opposition; the adversative conjunction butin poor but happy;
necessitating a choice between mutually exclusive possibilities; alternative possibilities were neutrality or war;
syntactically establishing a relation of contrast between sentences or elements of a sentence; disjunctive conjunctions like but, or, or thoughserve a contrastive function;
serving to divide or marking a division; the divisional line between two states;
serving to separate or divide into parts; partitive tendencies in education; the uniting influence was stronger than the separative;
(used of an accent in Hebrew orthography) indicating that the word marked is separated to a greater or lesser degree rhythmically and grammatically from the word that follows it;
progressing melodically by intervals of a second; conjunct motion of an ascending scale;
progressing melodically by intervals larger than a major second;
joined or linked together;
having a common boundary or edge; abutting; touching; Rhode Island has two bordering states; Massachusetts and Conncecticut; the side of Germany conterminous with France; Utah and the contiguous state of Idaho; neighboring cities;
joining; forming an adjunct;
closely related; syllable to blessed syllable affined- Wallace Stevens;
connecting without a break; within a common boundary; the 48 conterminous states; the contiguous 48 states;
connected by a link, as railway cars or trailer trucks;
built against or attached to a wall; engaged columns;
connected by blood or close acquaintance with people of wealth or social position; a well-connected Edinburgh family;
not joined or linked together;
remote and separate physically or socially; existed over the centuries as a world apart; preserved because they inhabited a place apart- W.H.Hudson; tiny isolated villages remote from centers of civilization; an obscure village;
not connected to the sternum or breastbone; asternal ribs;
no longer connected or joined; a detached part; on one side of the island was a hugh rock, almost detached; the separated spacecraft will return to their home bases;
have the connection undone; having become separate;
showing the parts of something separated but in positions that show their correct relation to one another; the manufacturer provided an exploded view of the apparatus;
not fastened together;
having the coupling undone; the uncoupled caboose rolled down the incline;
subject to being conquered or overcome; knew her fears were ultimately conquerable;
susceptible to being defeated;
susceptible to being subjugated;
not capable of being conquered or vanquished or overcome; a tribute to his courage...and his unconquerable will- R.E.Danielson; faced unconquerable difficulties;
incapable of being overcome, challenged or refuted; an impregnable argument; impregnable self-confidence;
impossible to subdue;
impossible to surmount;
incapable of being overcome or subdued; an invincible army; her invincible spirit;
never having lost;
knowing and perceiving; having awareness of surroundings and sensations and thoughts; remained conscious during the operation; conscious of his faults; became conscious that he was being followed;
aware of yourself as an individual or of your own being and actions and thoughts; self-conscious awareness; self-conscious about their roles as guardians of the social values- D.M.Potter;
partially conscious; not completely aware of sensations;
consciously perceiving; sentient of the intolerable load; a boy so sentient of his surroundings- W.A.White;
not conscious; lacking awareness and the capacity for sensory perception as if asleep or dead; lay unconscious on the floor;
unconscious from a blow or shock or intoxication; the boxer was out cold; pass out cold;
in a state of deep and usually prolonged unconsciousness; unable to respond to external stimuli; a comatose patient;
(used of things) lacking sense or awareness; fine innocent weather;
unresponsive to stimulation; he lay insensible where he had fallen; drugged and senseless;
knocked unconscious by a heavy blow;
concerning mental functioning that is not represented in consciousness; nonconscious psychic processes;
in a state of partial coma;
just below the level of consciousness;
solemnly dedicated to or set apart for a high purpose; a life consecrated to science; the consecrated chapel; a chapel dedicated to the dead of World War II;
invested with ministerial or priestly functions; an ordained priest;
dedicated in fulfillment of a vow; votive prayers;
treated with contempt; many desecrated shrines and cemeteries;
divested of consecration;
treated irreverently or sacrilegiously;
befitting or characteristic of a priest or the priesthood; priestly dedication to the people of his parish;
not priestly; unbefitting a priest; unpriestly behavior;
resistant to change;
pompously ultraconservative and nationalistic;
conservative in professional manner; employers are looking for buttoned-up types;
old-fashioned and out of date;
stubbornly conservative and narrow-minded;
extremely conservative;
tolerant of change; not bound by authoritarianism, orthodoxy, or tradition;
having or showing active concern for protection of civil liberties protected by law;
having or demonstrating belief in the essential goodness of man and the autonomy of the individual; favoring civil and political liberties, government by law with the consent of the governed, and protection from arbitrary authority;
having or showing belief in the need for economic growth in addition to traditional liberalistic values;
favoring or promoting reform (often by government action);
under group or government control; socialized ownership; socialized medicine;
of or relating to a welfare state;
(sometimes followed by with) in agreement or consistent or reliable; testimony consistent with the known facts; I have decided that the course of conduct which I am following is consistent with my sense of responsibility as president in time of war- FDR;
in keeping; salaries agreeable with current trends; plans conformable with your wishes; expressed views concordant with his background;
(followed by to) in conformance to or agreement with; pursuant to our agreement; pursuant to the dictates of one's conscience;
