someone affected by aphasia or inability to use or understand language;
someone who formulates aphorisms or who repeats aphorisms;
a person who argues to defend or justify some policy or institution; an apologist for capital punishment;
(New Testament) one of the original 12 disciples chosen by Christ to preach his gospel;
any important early teacher of Christianity or a Christian missionary to a people;
an ardent early supporter of a cause or reform; an apostle of revolution;
(Roman Catholic Church) a representative of the Holy See in a country that has no formal diplomatic relations with it;
a native or inhabitant of Appalachia;
a communist who was a member of the administrative system of a communist party;
a humorous but derogatory term for an official of a large organization (especially a political organization); Democratic apparatchiks;
someone who tries to bring peace by acceding to demands; An appeaser is one who feeds a crocodile--hoping it will eat him last--Winston Churchill;
the party who appeals a decision of a lower court;
someone who humbles himself as a sign of respect; who behaves as if he had no self-respect;
an official who is appointed;
a person who seizes or arrests (especially a person who seizes or arrests in the name of justice);
the butt of a prank played on April 1st;
a skilled worker who can live in underwater installations and participate in scientific research;
an ambitious and aspiring young person; a lofty aspirant; two executive hopefuls joined the firm; the audience was full of Madonna wannabes;
works for an expert to learn a trade;
one who estimates officially the worth or value or quality of things;
one who determines authenticity (as of works of art) or who guarantees validity;
a person who is fully aware of something and understands it; he is not an appreciator of our dilemma;
someone who takes for his or her own use (especially without permission);
an authority with power to approve;
a scholar who specializes in Arab languages and culture;
a member of one of a group of Semitic peoples inhabiting Aram and parts of Mesopotamia from the 11th to the 8th century BC;
a member of a widespread group of Amerindians living in northeastern South America;
someone chosen to judge and decide a disputed issue; the critic was considered to be an arbiter of modern literature; the arbitrator's authority derived from the consent of the disputants; an umpire was appointed to settle the tax case;
someone who engages in arbitrage (who purchases securities in one market for immediate resale in another in the hope of profiting from the price differential);
someone with the power to settle matters at will; she was the final arbiter on all matters of fashion;
a person who archaizes;
(Anglican Church) an ecclesiastical dignitary usually ranking just below a bishop;
a wife or widow of an archduke or a princess of the former ruling house of Austria;
a sovereign prince of the former ruling house of Austria;
an anthropologist who studies prehistoric people and their culture;
a bishop of highest rank;
a person who is expert in the use of a bow and arrow;
someone who creates plans to be used in making something (such as buildings);
a person in charge of collecting and cataloguing archives;
a senior clergyman and dignitary;
a member of the council of the Areopagus;
a native or inhabitant of the city of Argos;
an adherent of Arianism (the belief that Jesus Christ was not truly God);
a member of the aristocracy;
a follower of Aristotle or an adherent of Aristotelianism;
someone who specializes in arithmetic;
a person of liberal ideals who takes no action to realize them;
a nobleman entitled to bear heraldic arms;
a squire carrying the armor of a knight;
an enlisted man responsible for the upkeep of small arms and machine guns etc.;
a worker skilled in making armor or arms; a sword made by a famous English armorer;
someone who manufactures arms and munitions;
a military attache who is a commissioned or warrant officer in an army;
the child of a career officer of the United States Army;
a member of the military who is trained in engineering and construction work;
an officer in the armed forces; he's a retired army officer;
a musician who adapts a composition for particular voices or instruments or for another style of performance;
someone who arrives (or has arrived);
a person who through conceit makes pretentious claims to rights or advantages that he or she is not entitled to or to qualities that he or she does not possess;
a maker of arrows;
a criminal who illegally sets fire to property;
a critic of paintings;
a dealer in works of art requiring esthetic evaluation;
the director in charge of the artistic features of a theatrical production (costumes and scenery and lighting);
an editor who is responsible for illustrations and layouts in printed matter;
a historian of art;
a person afflicted with arthritis; the hands of an elderly arthritic;
someone who pronounces words;
a serviceman in the artillery;
an artist who makes illustrations (for books or magazines or advertisements etc.);
a person whose creative work shows sensitivity and imagination;
a public performer (a dancer or singer);
a person who poses for a painter or sculptor;
someone studying to be an artist;
someone who teaches art;
someone who ascends;
a pompous fool;
a murderer (especially one who kills a prominent political figure) who kills by a surprise attack and often is hired to do the deed; his assassins were hunted down like animals; assassinators of kings and emperors;
a member of a secret order of Muslims (founded in the 12th century) who terrorized and killed Christian Crusaders;
an analyst who assays (performs chemical tests on) metals;
someone who is a member of a legislative assembly;
a woman assemblyman;
a person who assents;
someone who claims to speak the truth; a bold asserter; a declarer of his intentions; affirmers of traditional doctrine; an asseverator of strong convictions; an avower of his own great intelligence;
a person (or property) that is assessed;
insulting terms of address for people who are stupid or irritating or ridiculous;
(law) the party to whom something is assigned (e.g., someone to whom a right or property is legally transferred);
(law) the party who makes an assignment;
a person who contributes to the fulfillment of a need or furtherance of an effort or purpose; my invaluable assistant; they hired additional help to finish the work;
a teacher or lower rank than an associate professor;
a person who joins with others in some activity or endeavor; he had to consult his associate before continuing;
a person with subordinate membership in a society, institution, or commercial enterprise; associates in the law firm bill at a lower rate than do partners;
a teacher lower in rank than a full professor but higher than an assistant professor;
a person suffering from asthma; she is a chronic asthmatic; the painful gasps of a dying asthmatic;
the navigator of a spacecraft;
someone who predicts the future by the positions of the planets and sun and Moon;
a person trained to travel in a spacecraft; the Russians called their astronauts cosmonauts;
a physicist who studies astronomy;
an astronomer who studies the physical properties of celestial bodies;
a scientist knowledgeable about cosmography;
