death of a liveborn infant within the first 28 days of life;
sudden and unexpected death of an apparently healthy infant during sleep;
clinical neurological syndrome characterized by muscular twitching and cramps and (when severe) seizures; associated with calcium deficiency (hypoparathyroidism) or vitamin D deficiency or alkalosis;
tingling sensations in the fingers; caused by compression on a nerve supplying the arm;
syndrome characterized by swelling of rib cartilage (causing pain);
neurological disorder characterized by facial grimaces and tics and movements of the upper body and grunts and shouts and coprolalia;
a symptom caused by an illness or a drug; the effects of sleep loss; the effect of the anesthetic;
a delayed effect of a drug or therapy; the drug had unexpected aftereffects;
a bad reaction to a hallucinogenic drug;
a benign side effect of some antibiotics; dark overgrowth of the papillae of the tongue;
a secondary and usually adverse effect of a drug or therapy; severe headaches are one of the side effects of the drug;
symptom consisting of a localized collection of pus surrounded by inflamed tissue;
an abscess of a common kind in the tissue around a tooth;
the tip of an abscess (where the pus accumulates);
symptom of being purulent (containing or forming pus);
blister containing a nonpurulent clear watery content;
blister containing blood or bloody serum usually caused by an injury;
protrusion of the eyeball from the socket;
involuntary shortening of stride and quickening of gait that occurs in some diseases (e.g., Parkinson's disease);
a furlike coating of matter as on the tongue;
necrotic tissue; a mortified or gangrenous part or mass;
(pathology) gangrene that develops in the presence of arterial obstruction and is characterized by dryness of the dead tissue and a dark brown color;
(pathology) a deadly form of gangrene usually caused by clostridium bacteria that produce toxins that cause tissue death; can be used as a bioweapon;
the presence of blood in the urine; often a symptom of urinary tract disease;
presence of hemoglobin in the urine;
abnormal deposit of hemosiderin; often a symptom of thalassemia or hemochromatosis;
cloudiness of the urine;
a symptom consisting of the involuntary expulsion of air from the nose;
the state of being enlarged;
an abnormal protuberance or localized enlargement;
swelling of the rumen or intestinal tract of domestic animals caused by excessive gas;
a lymph node that is inflamed and swollen because of plague or gonorrhea or tuberculosis;
generalized edema with accumulation of serum in subcutaneous connective tissue;
edema of the mucous membrane of the eyeball and eyelid lining;
swelling of the optic disc (where the optic nerve enters the eyeball); usually associated with an increase in intraocular pressure;
a painful swelling of the bursa of the first joint of the big toe;
a condition marked by uncontrollable tremor;
presence of white blood cells in the urine; symptom of urinary tract infection;
swelling from excessive accumulation of watery fluid in cells, tissues, or serous cavities;
swelling of the brain due to the uptake of water in the neuropile and white matter;
swelling caused by blood collecting in a body cavity (especially a swelling of the membrane covering the testis);
accumulation of blood in the vagina and uterus;
accumulation of menstrual blood in the vagina (usually due to an imperforate hymen);
swelling up with blood or other fluids (as with congestion);
swelling of the iris of the eye;
swelling of a lymph node;
swelling of the scrotum;
tumidity resulting from the presence of blood or other fluid in the tissues;
slight swelling of an organ or part;
a collection of blood under the scalp of a newborn; caused by pressure during birth;
a localized swelling filled with blood;
the swollen tissue around a healing wound or ulcer;
abnormally high amounts of bile pigment (bilirubin) in the blood;
a common disorder that is usually due to immaturity of the liver; usually subsides spontaneously;
abnormally high blood sugar usually associated with diabetes;
abnormally low blood sugar usually resulting from excessive insulin or a poor diet;
yellowing of the skin and the whites of the eyes caused by an accumulation of bile pigment (bilirubin) in the blood; can be a symptom of gallstones or liver infection or anemia;
yellowish appearance in newborn infants; usually subsides spontaneously;
an abnormal accumulation of bile pigment in the brain and other nerve tissue; causes yellow staining and tissue damage;
excessive accumulation of blood or other fluid in a body part;
accumulation of fluid in the pleural cavity (the space between the lungs and the walls of the chest) often resulting from disease of the heart or kidneys;
accumulation of blood in the pleural cavity (the space between the lungs and the walls of the chest);
increased blood in an organ or other body part;
congestion with blood; engorgement of the breast;
congestion in the lungs;
state of obstruction or stoppage or air in the nose or throat;
symptom consisting of a breaking out and becoming visible;
eruption on a mucous membrane (as the inside of the mouth) occurring as a symptom of a disease;
eruption on the skin occurring as a symptom of a disease;
any red eruption of the skin;
obstruction of the sweat ducts during high heat and humidity;
an itchy skin eruption characterized by weals with pale interiors and well-defined red margins; usually the result of an allergic response to insect bites or food or drugs;
partial or total lack of sensation in a part of the body; a symptom of nerve damage or dysfunction;
a symptom of some physical hurt or disorder; the patient developed severe pain and distension;
a dull persistent (usually moderately intense) pain;
an ache localized in or around a tooth;
pain in the teeth that results from a change in air pressure (as in flying or mountain climbing);
a state of acute pain;
pain in a joint or joints;
severe spasm of pain; the throes of dying; the throes of childbirth;
abnormal skin sensations (as tingling or tickling or itching or burning) usually associated with peripheral nerve damage;
hallucinated sensation that insects or snakes are crawling over the skin; a common side-effect of extensive use of cocaine or amphetamines;
the suffering of Jesus at the Crucifixion;
an ache localized in the back;
pain that feels hot as if it were on fire;
a burning pain in a limb along the course of a peripheral nerve; usually associated with skin changes;
acute abdominal pain (especially in infants);
pain in the chest;
a pain in the hand that is not traumatic;
extreme physical pain; the patient appeared to be in distress;
painful menstruation;
painful menstruation that is intrinsic to menstruation and not the result of a disease;
painful menstruation that is caused by some specific disorder (as endometriosis);
pain in the head caused by dilation of cerebral arteries or muscle contractions or a reaction to drugs;
pain in the tongue;
pain in muscles or joints sometimes experienced by children and often attributed to rapid growth;
pain caused by venous swelling at or inside the anal sphincter;
an ache localized in the stomach or abdominal region;
an ache localized in the middle or inner ear;
a painful recurring headache associated with the release of histamine from cells;
