make concrete and real;
make immaterial; remove the real essence of;
open up an area or prepare a way; She pioneered a graduate program for women students;
give rise to; cause to happen or occur, not always intentionally; cause a commotion; make a stir; cause an accident;
compel or make somebody or something to act in a certain way; People cannot be made to integrate just by passing a law!; Heat makes you sweat;
compel somebody to do something, often against his own will or judgment; She finally drove him to change jobs;
give occasion to;
supply the inspiration for; The article about the artist inspired the exhibition of his recent work;
evoke or provoke to appear or occur; Her behavior provoked a quarrel between the couple;
provoke; pick a fight or a quarrel;
set up or lay the groundwork for; establish a new department;
set or place definitely; Let's fix the date for the party!;
bring about; The trompe l'oeil-illusion establishes depth;
fight violence and try to establish peace in (a location) ; The U.N. troops are working to pacify Bosnia;
plan, organize, and carry out (an event) ; the neighboring tribe staged an invasion;
arrange for an illegal dogfight;
arrange by concord or agreement; Concord the conditions for the marriage of the Prince of Wales with a commoner;
make detailed arrangements or preparations;
arrange beforehand;
arrange in phases or stages; phase a withdrawal;
call forth;
put up or launch; mount a campaign against pornography;
prepare and supply with the necessary equipment for execution or performance; mount a theater production; mount an attack; mount a play;
rerun a performance of a play, for example;
play riffs;
play incorrectly, e.g., play a wrong note;
carry out (performances) ; They turned in a splendid effort; They turned in top jobs for the second straight game;
give an incentive for action; This moved me to sacrifice my career;
urge or force (a person) to an action; constrain or motivate;
get off the ground; Who started this company?; We embarked on an exciting enterprise; I start my day with a good breakfast; We began the new semester; The afternoon session begins at 4 PM; The blood shed started when the partisans launched a surprise attack;
start playing; The musicians struck up a tune;
enter upon an activity or enterprise;
arrange by systematic planning and united effort; machinate a plot; organize a strike; devise a plan to take over the director's office;
prepare or position for action or operation; lay a fire; lay the foundation for a new health care plan;
bring forth, The apple tree bore delicious apples this year; The unidentified plant bore gorgeous flowers;
bear seeds;
yield crops; This land crops well;
bear too much;
bear fruit; the trees fruited early this year;
cause to bear fruit;
make from scratch;
put together out of artificial or natural components or parts; the company fabricates plastic chairs; They manufacture small toys; He manufactured a popular cereal";
make by shaping or bringing together constituents; make a dress; make a cake; make a wall of stones;
make into a raft; raft these logs;
make a copy of with the intent to deceive; he faked the signature; they counterfeited dollar bills; She forged a Green Card;
make by combining materials and parts; this little pig made his house out of straw; Some eccentric constructed an electric brassiere warmer;
construct with drywall; dry-wall the basement of the house;
build locks in order to facilitate the navigation of vessels;
build or establish something abstract; build a reputation;
build of or with wattle;
construct by fitting or uniting parts together;
build again; The house was rebuild after it was hit by a bomb;
build with groins; The ceiling was groined;
construct with girders and beams such that only one end is fixed; Frank Lloyd Wright liked to cantilever his buildings;
destroy completely; the wrecking ball demolished the building; demolish your enemies; pulverize the rebellion before it gets out of hand;
create by putting components or members together; She pieced a quilt; He tacked together some verses; They set up a committee;
assemble without order or sense; She jumbles the words when she is supposed to write a sentence;
assemble once again, after taking something apart;
set up for a particular purpose; configure my new computer; configure a plane for a combat mission;
create by mixing or combining;
take apart into its constituent pieces;
make out of components (often in an improvising manner) ; She fashioned a tent out of a sheet and a few sticks;
make by tying pieces together; The fishermen tied their flies;
cast or model anew; She had to recast her image to please the electorate in her home state;
make by hand and with much skill; The artisan crafted a complicated tool;
make something by hand; We handcraft all our paper;
make barrels and casks;
make something, usually for a specific function; She molded the rice balls carefully; Form cylinders from the dough; shape a figure; Work the metal into a sword;
form or shape beforehand or determine the shape of beforehand;
form into a shape resembling the final, desired one;
form into a rounded elevation; mound earth;
form a mound over;
form into a hill;
shape roughly;
shape again or shape differently;
place (candle wicks) into hot, liquid wax;
cause (ores or powdery metals) to become a coherent mass by heating without melting;
construct, build, or erect; Raise a barn;
begin, or enable someone else to begin, a venture by providing the means, logistics, etc.; set up an election;
erect or construct, especially as a temporary measure; Can he rig up a P.A. system?;
tear down so as to make flat with the ground; The building was levelled;
destroy completely, as if down to the roots; the vestiges of political democracy were soon uprootedroot out corruption;
bring into a condition of decay or partial ruin by neglect or misuse;
press from a plastic; press a record;
form by pouring (e.g., wax or hot metal) into a cast or mold; cast a bronze sculpture;
cast again; The bell cracked and had to be recast;
pour molten metal into a mold of sand;
make on a potter's wheel; she threw a beautiful teapot;
make without a potter's wheel; This famous potter hand-builds all of her vessels;
prepare with dry heat in an oven; bake a cake;
prepare by brewing; people have been brewing beer for thousands of years;
prepare for eating by applying heat; Cook me dinner, please; can you make me an omelette?; fix breakfast for the guests, please;
dissolve cooking juices or solid food in (a pan) by adding liquid and stirring;
bake in a sauce, milk, etc., often with breadcrumbs on top;
pour liquor over and ignite (a dish) ;
make into a sandwich;
put on the stove or ready for cooking; put on the tea, please!;
prepare for eating if or as if a spatchcock; spatchcock a guinea hen;
coat or stuff with a spicy paste; devilled eggs;
prepare a hot meal; My husband doesn't cook;
