play on a violin; Zuckerman fiddled that song very nicely;
play on an instrument; The band played all night long;
play with a subtle and intuitively felt sense of rhythm;
play (a melody) again;
play as a prelude;
play something in the style of jazz;
play in ragtime; rag that old tune;
play on a bugle;
perform music on (a musical instrument) ; He plays the flute; Can you play on this old recorder?;
manipulate the registers of an organ;
play the bagpipes;
produce a rhythm by striking repeatedly; beat the drum;
play or sound together, in harmony;
play negligently on a musical instrument;
play chords on (a string instrument) ;
repeat an earlier theme of a composition;
play on a pipe; pipe a tune;
play smoothly or legato; the pianist slurred the most beautiful passage in the sonata;
operate the pedals on a keyboard instrument;
play loudly; They banged out The star-spangled banner;
perform an accompaniment to; The orchestra could barely follow the frequent pitch changes of the soprano;
sing with a choir or an orchestra; Every year the local orchestra and choir perform the Messiahand the audience is invited to sing along;
perform without preparation; he extemporized a speech at the wedding;
change the key of, in music; modulate the melody;
play on a string instrument with a bow;
produce tones with the voice; She was singing while she was cooking; My brother sings very well;
sing or celebrate in psalms; He psalms the works of God;
celebrate by singing, in the style of minstrels;
sing using syllables like do, reand mito represent the tones of the scale; The voice teacher showed the students how to solmizate;
sing in modulation;
sing in a choir;
deliver by singing; Sing Christmas carols;
sing by the syllables of solmization; solmizate a song before you learn the lyrics;
sing the parts of (a round) in succession;
sing a hymn;
sing carols; They went caroling on Christmas Day;
sing madrigals; The group was madrigaling beautifully;
give an interpretation or rendition of; The pianist rendered the Beethoven sonata beautifully;
play a percussion instrument;
play the harp; She harped the Saint-Saens beautifully;
lead, as in the performance of a composition; conduct an orchestra; Barenboim conducted the Chicago symphony for years;
lead musicians in the performance of; Bernstein conducted Mahler like no other conductor; she cannot conduct modern pieces;
organize or be responsible for; hold a reception; have, throw, or make a party; give a course;
play the violin or fiddle;
play or blow on the trumpet;
blow the clarion;
play fast notes on a wind instrument;
articulate by tonguing, as when playing wind instruments;
make or do or perform again; He could never replicate his brilliant performance of the magic trick;
reproduce or make an exact copy of; replicate the cell; copy the genetic information;
repeat stages of evolutionary development during the embryonic phase of life;
make a duplicate or duplicates of; Could you please duplicate this letter for me?;
form by reduplication; The consonant reduplicates after a short vowel; The morpheme can be reduplicated to emphasize the meaning of the word;
reproduce threefold; triplicate the letter for the committee;
reproduce fourfold; quadruplicate the bill;
print anew; They never reprinted the famous treatise;
reproduce by xerography;
photocopy printed or other graphic matter so that it is reduced in size;
make a copy by means of a Photostat device;
make a copy or equivalent of; reproduce the painting;
recreate a sound, image, idea, mood, atmosphere, etc.; this DVD player reproduces the sound of the piano very well; He reproduced the feeling of sadness in the portrait;
produce electric current by electrostatic or magnetic processes;
create anew; she recreated the feeling of the 1920's with her stage setting;
create anew and make over; He reinvented African music for American listeners;
bring back into existence; The candidate reinvented the concept of national health care so that he would get elected;
apprehend and reproduce accurately; She really caught the spirit of the place in her drawings; She got the mood just right in her photographs;
reproduce (a recording) on a recorder; The lawyers played back the conversation to show that their client was innocent;
work out; We have developed a new theory of evolution;
make something new, such as a product or a mental or artistic creation; Her company developed a new kind of building material that withstands all kinds of weather; They developed a new technique;
give form to, according to a plan; build a modern nation; build a million-dollar business;
to manufacture sections of (a building) , especially in a factory, so that they can be easily transported to and rapidly assembled on a building site of buildings;
make up; vamp up an excuse for not attending the meeting;
produce shoddily, without much attention to detail;
cultivate by growing, often involving improvements by means of agricultural techniques; The Bordeaux region produces great red wines; They produce good ham in Parma; We grow wheat here; We raise hogs here;
bear (a crop) ; this land does not carry olives;
produce in excess; produce more than needed or wanted;
work land as by ploughing, harrowing, and manuring, in order to make it ready for cultivation; till the soil;
work in the garden; My hobby is gardening;
do landscape gardening; My sons landscapes for corporations and earns a good living;
prepare for crops; Work the soil; cultivate the land;
to exhaust by excessive cultivation; the farmers overcropped the land;
to break and turn over earth especially with a plow; Farmer Jones plowed his east field last week; turn the earth in the Spring;
plough alternate strips by throwing the furrow onto an unploughed strip;
draw a harrow over (land) ;
dig with a hoe; He is hoeing the flower beds;
foster the growth of;
reproduce someone's behavior or looks; The mime imitated the passers-by; Children often copy their parents or older siblings;
mimic or imitate in an amusing or satirical manner; This song takes off from a famous aria;
imitate (a person or manner) , especially for satirical effect; The actor mimicked the President very accurately;
plan or create according to a model or models;
pattern, make, regulate, set, measure, or estimate according to some rate or standard;
model a country's social, political, and economic structure on the Soviet Union; Castro sovietized Cuba;
imitate in behavior; take as a model; Teenagers follow their friends in everything;
have (one's written work) issued for publication; How many books did Georges Simenon write?; She published 25 books during her long career;
set in type; My book will be typeset nicely; set these words in italics;
take a trial impression of;
set (printed matter) into a specific format; Format this letter so it can be printed out;
set in from the margin; Indent the paragraphs of a letter;
arrange or enter in tabular form;
put into print; The newspaper published the news of the royal couple's divorce; These news should not be printed;
