type genus of Dicranaceae;
mosses with perennial erect gametophores and stems with rows of leaves and drooping capsules;
a family of acrocarpous mosses;
type genus of the Bryaceae: mosses distinguished by mostly erect and tufted gametophytes and symmetrical short-necked capsules;
family of erect mosses with club-shaped paraphyses and the hexagonal cells of the upper leaf surface; sometimes treated as a subfamily of Bryaceae;
mosses similar to those of genus Bryum but larger;
coextensive with the genus Sphagnum; in some classifications isolated in a separate subclass;
a large genus constituting the order Sphagnales: atypical mosses of temperate bogs with leaves that can hold much water;
any of various pale or ashy mosses of the genus Sphagnum whose decomposed remains form peat;
liverworts: comprises orders Anthocerotales; Jungermanniales; Marchantiales; Sphaerocarpales;
any of numerous small green nonvascular plants of the class Hepaticopsida growing in wet places and resembling green seaweeds or leafy mosses;
large order of chiefly tropical liverworts;
moss-like liverwort with tiny scalelike leaves; usually epiphytic;
comprising the leafy members of the order Jungermanniales;
liverworts with gametophyte differentiated internally;
liverworts with prostrate and usually dichotomously branched thalli;
type genus of Marchantiaceae; liverworts that reproduce asexually by gemmae and have stalked antheridiophores;
a common liverwort;
small order sometimes included in the order Jungermanniales;
liverworts with bilaterally symmetrical gametophytes; sometimes placed in the order Jungermanniales;
type genus of Sphaerocarpaceae; liverworts with small many-lobed usually orbicular thallus;
containing all the vascular plants that do not bear seeds: ferns, horsetails, club mosses, and whisk ferns; in some classifications considered a subdivision of Tracheophyta;
genus of Carboniferous fossil ferns;
Carboniferous fossil fern characterized by a regular arrangement of the leaflets resembling a comb;
plants having vascular tissue and reproducing by spores;
any of numerous flowerless and seedless vascular plants having true roots from a rhizome and fronds that uncurl upward; reproduce by spores;
pteridophytes of other classes than Filicopsida;
an asexual reproductive cell;
a small usually single-celled asexual reproductive body produced by many nonflowering plants and fungi and some bacteria and protozoans and that are capable of developing into a new individual without sexual fusion; a sexual spore is formed after the fusion of gametes;
a sexually produced fungal spore borne on a basidium;
a small asexual spore that develops inside the cell of some bacteria and algae;
a nonmotile spore of red algae;
thick-walled asexual resting spore of certain fungi and algae;
an asexually produced fungal spore formed on a conidiophore;
a specialized fungal hypha that produces conidia;
a thick-walled sexual spore that develops from a fertilized oosphere in some algae and fungi;
a gamete; used especially of lower plants;
a spore of certain algae or fungi that lies dormant; may germinate after a prolonged period;
a chlamydospore that develops in the last stage of the life cycle of the rust fungus;
one of the four asexual spores produced within a sporangium;
an asexual spore of some algae and fungi that moves by means of flagella;
the asexual spore of ferns that resembles dust; once thought to be seeds and to make the possessor invisible;
organs of fruiting (especially the reproductive parts of ferns and mosses);
fleshy spore-bearing inner mass of e.g. a puffball or stinkhorn;
spore-bearing layer of cells in certain fungi containing asci or basidia;
flask-shaped asexual structure containing conidia;
specialized leaf branch in certain aquatic ferns that encloses the sori or clusters of sporangia;
a small leafy outgrowth at the base of a leaf or its stalk; usually occurring in pairs and soon shed;
an undifferentiated part of a perianth that cannot be distinguished as a sepal or a petal (as in lilies and tulips);
seed plants; comprises the Angiospermae (or Magnoliophyta) and Gymnospermae (or Gymnospermophyta); in some classification systems Spermatophyta is coordinate with Pteridophyta (spore producing plants having vascular tissue and roots) and Bryophyta (spore producing plants lacking vascular tissue and roots);
in former classification systems: one of two major plant divisions, including all seed-bearing plants; superseded by the division Spermatophyta;
in former classification systems: one of two major plant divisions, including all plants that do not bear seeds: ferns, mosses, algae, fungi;
formerly recognized taxonomic group including all flowerless and seedless plants that reproduce by means of spores: ferns, mosses, algae, fungi;
plant that reproduces by means of seeds not spores;
young plant or tree grown from a seed;
any seed plant yielding balsam;
(botany) a plant that completes its entire life cycle within the space of a year;
(botany) a plant having a life cycle that normally takes two seasons from germination to death to complete; flowering biennials usually bloom and fruit in the second season;
(botany) a plant lasting for three seasons or more;
a plant originally cultivated but now growing wild;
a plant that grows in a moist habitat;
a plant that is found in an area where it had not been recorded previously;
a family of gymnosperms;
a genus of gymnosperms;
family of flowering plants having a single cotyledon (embryonic leaf) in the seed;
family of monocotyledonous plants of the subclass Liliidae; mostly herbs usually with petaloid sepals and petals and compound pistils;
genus of flowering plants having a single cotyledon (embryonic leaf) in the seed;
genus of monocotyledonous plants comprising mostly herbs having usually petaloid sepals and petals and compound pistils;
family of flowering plants having two cotyledons (embryonic leaves) in the seed which usually appear at germination;
family of dicotyledonous flowering plants regarded as among the most primitive of extant angiosperms;
family of mostly woody dicotyledonous flowering plants with flowers often unisexual and often borne in catkins;
family of relatively early dicotyledonous plants including mostly flowers;
family of more or less advanced dicotyledonous trees and shrubs and herbs;
family of more or less advanced dicotyledonous herbs and some trees and shrubs;
a family of dicotyledonous plants;
genus of flowering plants having two cotyledons (embryonic leaves) in the seed which usually appear at germination;
genus of dicotyledonous flowering plants regarded as among the most primitive of extant angiosperms;
genus of mostly woody relatively primitive dicotyledonous flowering plants with flowers often unisexual and often borne in catkins;
genus of relatively early dicotyledonous plants including mostly flowers;
genus of more or less advanced dicotyledonous trees and shrubs and herbs;
genus of more or less advanced dicotyledonous herbs and some trees and shrubs;
a genus of dicotyledonous plants;
includes lichen families;
includes lichen genera;
the order of fungi;
plants having naked seeds not enclosed in an ovary; in some systems considered a class (Gymnospermae) and in others a division (Gymnospermophyta); comprises three subdivisions (or classes): Cycadophytina (class Cycadopsida) and Gnetophytina (class Gnetopsida) and Coniferophytina (class Coniferopsida); in some classifications the Coniferophytina are divided into three groups: Pinophytina (class Pinopsida) and Ginkgophytina (class Ginkgopsida) and Taxophytina (class Taxopsida);
plants of the class Gymnospermae having seeds not enclosed in an ovary;
an ancestral fossil type from which modern gymnosperms are thought to have derived;
gymnospermous flowering plants; supposed link between conifers and angiosperms; in some systems classified as a class (Gnetopsida) and in others as a subdivision (Gnetophytina or Gnetophyta);
chiefly tropical or xerophytic woody plants; practically unknown as fossils but considered close to the ancestral line of angiosperms;
plants having small unisexual flowers and fleshy or winged fruit: in some classifications includes the genera Ephedra and Welwitschia as well as genus Gnetum;
type genus of the Gnetaceae; small trees or shrubs usually with climbing jointed stems and terminal spikes of flowers with orange-red seeds clustered in rough cones;
small tropical tree with tiered branches and divaricate branchlets having broad glossy dark green leaves; exploited for its edible young leaves and seeds that provide a fine flour;
ephedras: in some classifications included in the Gnetaceae;
a genus of African evergreen shrubs characterized by thick leaves and white flowers;
a shrub that is cultivated by Arabs for its leaves which are chewed or used to make tea;
type and sole genus of Ephedraceae: tropical and subtropical evergreen shrubby or creeping plants native to dry and inhospitable regions;
jointed and nearly leafless desert shrub having reduced scalelike leaves and reddish fleshy seeds;
Chinese ephedra yielding ephedrine;
in some classifications included in the Gnetaceae;
