looking pale and unhealthy; you're looking green; green around the gills;
put out of action (by illness);
ill and usually confined; laid up with a bad cold;
affected with or related to milk sickness;
feeling nausea; feeling about to vomit;
affected with palsy or uncontrollable tremor; palsied hands;
affected with paralysis;
suffering complete paralysis of the lower half of the body usually resulting from damage to the spinal cord;
affected with, suffering from, or characteristic of rickets; rickety limbs and joints; a rachitic patient;
afflicted with scrofula;
inclined to sneeze;
suffering from spastic paralysis; a spastic child;
constituting or afflicted with or caused by tuberculosis or the tubercle bacillus; a tubercular child; tuberculous patients; tubercular meningitis;
not healed; an unhealed wound;
mildly physically distressed; an upset stomach;
covered or soaked with a liquid such as water; a wet bathing suit; wet sidewalks; wet weather;
wet with dew;
sprinkled over; glistening grass besprent with raindrops;
(of soil) soft and watery; the ground was boggy under foot; a marshy coastline; miry roads; wet mucky lowland; muddy barnyard; quaggy terrain; the sloughy edge of the pond; swampy bayous;
unpleasantly cool and humid; a clammy handshake; clammy weather; a dank cellar; dank rain forests;
slightly wet; clothes damp with perspiration; a moist breeze; eyes moist with tears;
wet through and through; thoroughly wet; stood at the door drenched (or soaked) by the rain; the speaker's sodden collar; soppy clothes;
wet with light rain; a sad drizzly day; a wet drippy day;
containing or characterized by a great deal of water vapor; humid air; humid weather;
wet with mist; the misty evening;
hot or warm and humid; muggy weather; the steamy tropics; sticky weather;
wet with secreted or exuded moisture such as sweat or tears; wiped his reeking neck;
moist, damp, wet (especially of air); the raw and theumy damp of night air;
wet or smeared with a spilled liquid or moist material; a sloppy floor; a sloppy saucer;
(of weather) wet by periods of rain; showery weather; rainy days;
filled with steam or emitting moisture in the form of vapor or mist; a steaming kettle; steamy towels;
moist as with undried perspiration and with clothing sticking to the body; felt sticky and chilly at the same time;
(of a glutinous liquid such as paint) not completely dried and slightly sticky to the touch; tacky varnish;
still wet or moist;
wet as from washing; sometimes used in combination; rain-washed ;
filled with water; watery soil;
free from liquid or moisture; lacking natural or normal moisture or depleted of water; or no longer wet; dry land; dry clothes; a dry climate; dry splintery boards; a dry river bed; the paint is dry;
dried out by heat or excessive exposure to sunlight; a vast desert all adust; land lying baked in the heat; parched soil; the earth was scorched and bare; sunbaked salt flats;
made dry by contact with unheated air;
not giving off moisture on exposure to the air;
lacking sufficient water or rainfall; an arid climate; a waterless well; miles of waterless country to cross;
without a trace of moisture; as dry as a weathered bone; bone-dry leaves are a fire hazard; a drier to get the clothes bone dry;
thoroughly dried out; old boxes of desiccated Cuban cigars; dried-out boards beginning to split;
not still wet; the ink has dried; a face marked with dried tears;
depleted of water; a dried-up water hole;
(used especially of vegetation) having lost all moisture; dried-up grass; the desert was edged with sere vegetation; shriveled leaves on the unwatered seedlings; withered vines;
having or keeping the feet or shoes dry; a land bridge over which man and beasts could have crossed dry-shod;
dried in a kiln;
lacking rain; a rainless month; rainless skies;
somewhat arid; a semiarid region with little annual rainfall;
somewhat dry; swabbing left the deck semi-dry but still slippery;
needing moisture; thirsty fields under a rainless sky;
producing or secreting milk; a wet nurse; a wet cow; lactating cows;
having recently calved and therefore able to give milk; the cow is fresh;
not producing milk; a dry cow;
having no milk; milkless breasts;
supporting or permitting the legal production and sale of alcoholic beverages; a wet candidate running on a wet platform; a wet county;
opposed to or prohibiting the production and sale of alcoholic beverages; the dry vote led by preachers and bootleggers; a dry state;
containing moisture or volatile components; wet paint;
lacking moisture or volatile components; dry paint;
containing combined water (especially water of crystallization as in a hydrate);
without water; especially without water of crystallization;
having wheels;oftenusedincombination;
having no wheels or having no wheeled vehicles; dragging a wheelless stoneboat filled with rocks; wheelless societies;
of or designating salaried professional or clerical work or workers; the coal miner's son aspired to a white-collar occupation as a bookkeeper;
appropriate for or engaged in office work; clerical skills; a clerical job; the clerical staff;
engaged in by members of a profession; professional occupations include medicine and the law and teaching;
of or relating to a class of jobs once traditionally filled by women; a pink-collar employee;
of or designating manual industrial work or workers;
employed in industry; the industrial classes; industrial work;
doing or requiring physical work; manual labor; manual laborer;
working for hourly wages rather than fixed (e.g. annual) salaries; working-class occupations include manual as well as industrial labor;
conducive to or characteristic of physical or moral well-being; wholesome attitude; wholesome appearance; wholesome food;
of or providing nourishment; good nourishing stew;
of foods that are low in fats and sodium and other ingredients that may foster heart disease;
promoting health; healthful; a healthy diet; clean healthy air; plenty of healthy sleep; healthy and normal outlets for youthful energy; the salubrious mountain air and water- C.B.Davis; carrots are good for you;
providing abundant nourishment; a hearty meal; good solid food; ate a substantial breakfast; four square meals a day;
of or relating to foodstuff grown or raised without synthetic fertilizers or pesticides or hormones; organic eggs; organic vegetables; organic chicken;
favorable to health of mind or body; not the most salubrious campsite; one of the less salubrious suburbs;
detrimental to physical or moral well-being; unwholesome food; unwholesome habits like smoking;
detrimental to health;
lacking in nutritive value; the jejune diets of the very poor;
suggesting an unhealthy mental state; morbid interest in death; morbid curiosity;
causing or able to cause nausea; a nauseating smell; nauseous offal; a sickening stench;
containing plenty of fat, or eggs, or sugar; rich desserts; they kept gorging on rich foods;
having great (or a certain) extent from one side to the other; wide roads; a wide necktie; wide margins; three feet wide; a river two miles broad; broad shoulders; a broad river;
broad in the beam; a beamy cargo ship;
as from an altitude or distance; a bird's-eye survey; a panoramic view;
(of hats) having a broad brim;
extending relatively far inward; a deep border;
resembling a fan;
taking in or moving over (or as if over) a wide area; often used in combination; a sweeping glance; a wide-sweeping view of the river;
(motion pictures) projected on a screen with much greater width than height;
not wide; a narrow bridge; a narrow line across the page;
(of circumstances) tending to constrict freedom;
reduced in size as by squeezing together; his narrowed eyes;
having a narrow mouth;
very narrow; a thin line across the page;
narrow; strait is the gate;
long and narrow like a strap; straplike leaves;
