of or relating to boron;
belonging or relating to or resembling Boskop man;
of or relating to plants or botany; botanical garden;
resembling a cluster of grapes in form;
of or pertaining to Botswana or the people of Botswana;
of or relating to fish and marine life that dwell on the bottom of a body of water;
of or relating to fish and marine life that feed on the bottom of a body of water;
of or relating to writing alternate lines in opposite directions;
of or relating to an arm; brachial artery;
of or belonging to the phylum Brachiopoda;
of or belonging to the suborder Brachyura;
pertaining to or resembling or functioning as a bract;
having bracts;
having bracteoles;
of or relating to or characteristic of a brahmin;
of or relating to gills (or to parts of the body derived from embryonic gills);
of or relating to or characteristic of the subclass Branchiopoda;
resembling the sound of a brass instrument;
(of guns) designed to be loaded at the breech;
of or relating to the bregma of the skull;
without a brim; a brimless hat;
of or relating to the power (the shattering effect) of an explosive;
responding to or operating at a wide band of frequencies; a broadband antenna;
of or relating to or being a communications network in which the bandwidth can be divided and shared by multiple simultaneous signals (as for voice or data or video);
huge; relating to or characteristic of the imaginary country of Brobdingnag;
relating to or containing bromine (especially pentavalent bromine);
given to uttering bromides;
of or relating to or toward the cheek;
suffering from bulimia;
resembling a burr; especially in being prickly;
relating to or affecting a bursa;
relating to or resembling a hawk of the genus Buteo;
having the qualities of butter or yielding or containing a substance like butter;
relating to or producing butyric acid;
relating to or having the symptoms of cachexia;
of or relating to evil spirits;
of or relating to cacodyl;
of or relating to the records of a cadastre;
of or relating to a cadaver or corpse; we had long anticipated his cadaverous end;
of or relating to a caduceus;
of or relating to or belonging to the family Caeciliidae;
of or relating to a caesura;
of or containing caffein;
marked by cairns;
relating to the heel bone or heel;
composed of or containing or resembling calcium carbonate or calcite or chalk;
of slipper-shaped blossoms; the calceiform lip of certain orchids;
derived from or containing calcium or lime;
bearing or producing or containing calcium or calcium carbonate or calcite;
of or relating to or containing calcite;
relating to or caused by or having a calculus or calculi;
relating to or characteristic of or used in a calendar or time measurement; calendric systems; solstice is a time of calendric importance;
made of calico or resembling calico in being patterned; calico dresses; a calico cat;
of or relating to calisthenics;
of or relating to a callithump;
of or relating to calories in food; comparison of foods on a caloric basis; the caloric content of foods;
of food have no (or few) calories; a noncaloric drink;
of or relating to the measurement of heat;
of or relating to or resembling a calyx;
relating to or resembling a calyculus;
having a calyculus;
having a calyptra;
having calypters;
of or relating to or functioning as a cambium;
shaped like a bell or campana; campanulate flowers of the genus Campanula;
being or having the properties of camphor; camphoraceous odor;
relating to or derived from or containing camphor; camphoric liniments;
relating to or like or having a canaliculus;
of or relating to a cancroid;
relating to or especially immediately preceding or following the heliacal rising of Canicula (the Dog Star); canicular days;
of or relating to the dog days of summer; the canicular heat of the Deep South;
of or relating to or characteristic of members of the family Canidae;
of or relating to a pointed conical tooth;
of or relating to capacitance;
of or relating to the French dynasty founded by Hugh Capet;
of or pertaining to an ecclesiastical chapter; capitular estates;
of or pertaining to Cappadocia or its people or culture;
being or pertaining to or resembling a goat or goats; caprine creatures; a caprine strain of virus; a caprine voice;
of or relating to a capsule;
resembling a capsule; the capsular ligament is a sac surrounding the articular cavity of a freely movable joint and attached to the bones;
of or relating to fish of the family Carangidae;
having or relating to or characterized by a ring composed of carbon atoms;
containing or treated with carbolic acid;
relating to or containing the carbonyl group;
relating to or containing the carboxyl group or carboxyl radical;
causing or tending to cause cancer; the carcinogenic action of certain chemicals;
being or relating to carcinoma; a carcinomatous lesion;
of or relating to a cardiograph;
of or pertaining to or affecting both the heart and the lungs and their functions; cardiopulmonary resuscitation;
relating to or resembling a carina;
relating to or characteristic of carnivores; the lion and other carnivorous animals;
of or relating to the life and times of kings Charles I or Charles II of England;
of or relating to the Frankish dynasty founded by Charlemagne's father;
of or relating to either of the two major arteries supplying blood to the head and neck;
belonging to or forming or containing carpels;
following the practices or characteristic of carpetbaggers; carpetbag adventurers; a carpetbag government;
relating to or resembling a carpospore;
having carpospores;
of or relating to cartilage;
of or relating to the making of maps or charts;
