large feline of forests in most of Asia having a tawny coat with black stripes; endangered;
southern short-haired tiger;
a female tiger;
offspring of a male lion and a female tiger;
offspring of a male tiger and a female lion;
cheetahs;
long-legged spotted cat of Africa and southwestern Asia having nonretractile claws; the swiftest mammal; can be trained to run down game;
any of many extinct cats of the Old and New Worlds having long swordlike upper canine teeth; from the Oligocene through the Pleistocene;
saber-toothed tigers;
North American sabertooth; culmination of sabertooth development;
false sabertoothed tigers;
North American cat of the Miocene and Pliocene; much earlier and less specialized than members of the genus Smiledon;
bears and extinct related forms;
massive plantigrade carnivorous or omnivorous mammals with long shaggy coats and strong claws;
type genus of Ursidae: brown bears; in some classifications genus Ursus includes all bears;
large ferocious bear of Eurasia;
a conventional name for a bear used in tales following usage in the old epic Reynard the Fox;
yellowish-grey Syrian brown bear;
powerful brownish-yellow bear of the uplands of western North America;
brown bear of coastal Alaska and British Columbia;
American black bears; in some classifications not a separate genus from Ursus;
brown to black North American bear; smaller and less ferocious than the brown bear;
reddish-brown color phase of the American black bear;
Asiatic black bears; in some classifications not a separate genus from Ursus;
bear with a black coat living in central and eastern Asia;
polar bears; in some classifications not a separate genus from Ursus;
white bear of Arctic regions;
sloth bears; in some classifications not a separate genus from Ursus;
common coarse-haired long-snouted bear of south-central Asia;
genets; civets; mongooses;
small cat-like predatory mammals of warmer parts of the Old World;
cat-like mammal typically secreting musk used in perfumes;
type genus of the family Viverridae;
common civet of India and southeast Asia;
a genus of Viverridae;
a common civet of southeast Asia;
binturongs;
arboreal civet of Asia having a long prehensile tail and shaggy black hair;
large primitive cat-like carnivores inhabiting forests of Madagascar;
largest carnivore of Madagascar; intermediate in some respects between cats and civets;
monotypic genus of Madagascar civets closely related to palm civets;
civet of Madagascar;
genets;
agile Old World viverrine having a spotted coat and long ringed tail;
banded palm civets;
an East Indian civet;
mongooses;
agile grizzled Old World viverrine; preys on snakes and rodents;
keen-sighted viverrine of southern Asia about the size of a ferret; often domesticated;
northern African mongoose; in ancient times thought to devour crocodile eggs;
palm civets;
spotted or striped arboreal civet of southeast Asia and East Indies;
meerkats;
a mongoose-like viverrine of South Africa having a face like a lemur and only four toes;
a meerkat with a thin and elongated tail;
burrowing diurnal meerkat of southern Africa; often kept as a pet;
an old order dating to early Eocene: bats: suborder Megachiroptera (fruit bats); suborder Microchiroptera (insectivorous bats);
nocturnal mouselike mammal with forelimbs modified to form membranous wings and anatomical adaptations for echolocation by which they navigate;
fruit bats;
large Old World bat of warm and tropical regions that feeds on fruit;
a genus of Megachiroptera;
large bat with a head that resembles the head of a fox;
a variety of fruit bat;
a variety of fruit bat;
East Indian fruit bats;
any of various fruit bats of the genus Nyctimene distinguished by nostrils drawn out into diverging tubes;
a genus of Megachiroptera;
a variety of fruit eating bat;
most of the bats in the world; all bats except fruit bats insectivorous bats;
typically having large ears and feeding primarily on insects; worldwide in distribution;
a carnivorous bat with ears like a mouse;
bat having a leaflike flap at the end of the nose; especially of the families Phyllostomatidae and Rhinolophidae and Hipposideridae;
New World leaf-nosed bats;
leafnose bats;
large-eared greyish bat of southern California and northwestern Mexico;
type genus of the family Phyllostomatidae;
New World bat with a pointed nose leaf; found from southern United States to Paraguay;
a variety of leaf-nosed bat;
a genus of Phyllostomatidae;
small-eared Mexican bat with a long slender nose;
Old World leaf-nosed bats;
a bat of the family Rhinolophidae having a horseshoe-shaped leaf on the nose;
Old World leafnose bats;
horseshoe bats;
any of numerous bats of the family Hipposideridae of northwest Africa or Philippines or Australia having a horseshoe-shaped leaf on the nose;
orange horseshoe bats;
a common bat of northwestern Australia having orange or yellow fur;
Old World false vampire bats;
any New or Old World carnivorous bat erroneously thought to suck blood but in fact feeding on insects;
type genus of the Megadermatidae;
large carnivorous Old World bat with very large ears;
the majority of common bats of temperate regions of the world;
a variety of carnivorous bat;
a genus of Vespertilionidae;
common Eurasian bat with white-tipped hairs in its coat;
a genus of Vespertilionidae;
North American bat of a brick or rusty red color with hairs tipped with white;
any of numerous medium to small insectivorous bats found worldwide in caves and trees and buildings;
largest and most widely distributed genus of bats;
the small common North American bat; widely distributed;
