change the appearance of, especially by marking with different colors;
become vascular and have vessels that circulate fluids; The egg yolk vascularized;
furnish with an opening to allow air to circulate or gas to escape; The architect did not think about ventilating the storage space;
make more striking or animated; his remarks always vivify an otherwise dull story;
debase and make vulgar; The Press has vulgarized Love and Marriage;
destroy completely by or as if by fire; The wildfire scorched the forest and several homes; the invaders scorched the land;
become superficially burned; my eyebrows singed when I bent over the flames;
make pliant and flexible; These boots are not yet suppled by frequent use;
undergo a sudden and severe downturn; the economy crashed; will the stock market crash again?;
make professional or give a professional character to; Philosophy has not always been professionalized and used to be a subject pursued only by amateurs;
become professional or proceed in a professional manner or in an activity for pay or as a means of livelihood;
make obscene; This line in the play smuts the entire act;
make motionless;
give better travel conditions to; The airline upgraded me when I arrived late and Coach Class was full;
get better travel conditions; I upgraded to First Class when Coach Class was overbooked;
change phonetically as part of a systematic historical change; Grimm showed how the consonants shifted;
pour or flow in a steady stream; mist rolled in from the sea; tourists rolled in from the neighboring countryside;
go mad, go crazy; He flipped when he heard that he was being laid off;
make into or use as a weapon or a potential weapon; Will modern physicists weaponize String Theory?;
burn with great heat and intense light; the powder deflagrated;
convert (an amine) into a diazo compound;
convert (plant material) into hay;
convert into wood or cause to become woody;
transform (a metal) into an ore;
convert into a mineral substance;
convert (oxygen) into ozone;
convert into slag;
convert into a sulfate;
convert into cutin;
change into a duplex;
give erotic character to or make more interesting; eroticize the ads;
become sticky;
bring into alignment with; an amendment to piggyback the current law;
block the action of;
reduce in size or number; the company downsized its research staff;
make in a smaller size; the car makers downsized the SUVs when fuel became very expensive;
take off or away; this prefix was subtracted when the word was borrowed from French;
become deformed by forces tending to produce a shearing strain;
modify (software) for use on a different machine or platform;
reduce a vowel to a neutral one, such as a schwa;
destress and thus weaken a sound when pronouncing it;
remove from a larger whole; the new start-up company carved out a large chunk of the market within a year;
make one's day-to-day activities more efficient;
make less clear; the stroke clouded memories of her youth;
suffer or be susceptible to damage; These fine china cups damage easily;
get the meaning of something; Do you comprehend the meaning of this letter?;
to try to avoid detection especially by police; After we knock off that liquor store we'll have to lay low for a while;
know and comprehend the nature or meaning of; She did not understand her husband; I understand what she means;
comprehend; I sensed the real meaning of his letter;
become aware of not through the senses but instinctively; I sense his hostility; i smell trouble; smell out corruption;
grasp the meaning; Can you follow her argument?; When he lectures, I cannot follow;
grasp with the mind or develop an understanding of; did you catch that allusion?; We caught something of his theory in the lecture; don't catch your meaning; did you get it?; She didn't get the joke; I just don't get him;
understand; He didn't figure her;
understand, usually after some initial difficulty; She didn't know what her classmates were plotting but finally caught on;
comprehend; He could not touch the meaning of the poem;
know or grasp by intuition or feeling;
arrange and integrate in the mind; I cannot digest all this information;
perceive (an idea or situation) mentally; Now I see!; I just can't see your point; Does she realize how important this decision is?; I don't understand the idea;
become conscious of; She finally perceived the futility of her protest;
become clear or enter one's consciousness or emotions; It dawned on him that she had betrayed him; she was penetrated with sorrow;
be received or understood;
create an emotional response; The music struck a chord with the listeners;
be fully aware of; realize fully; Do you appreciate the full meaning of this letter?;
show due and full appreciation; The diners did the food and wine justice;
consider reasonable or due; I'm expecting a full explanation as to why these files were destroyed;
accept (someone) to be what is claimed or accept his power and authority; The Crown Prince was acknowledged as the true heir to the throne; We do not recognize your gods;
acknowledge a new land owner as one's landlord; he was attorned by the tenants;
concede the loss or worthlessness of something or somebody; write it off as a loss;
believe to be the case; I understand you have no previous experience?;
gain knowledge of (an area not known or experienced) by extrapolating;
make sense of a language; She understands French; Can you read Greek?;
be understanding of; You don't need to explain--I understand!;
be familiar or acquainted with a person or an object; She doesn't know this composer; Do you know my sister?; We know this movie; I know him under a different name; This flower is known as a Peruvian Lily;
be cognizant or aware of a fact or a specific piece of information; possess knowledge or information about; I know that the President lied to the people; I want to know who is winning the game!; I know it's time;
keep informed of fully aware; I keep track of the stock market developments;
fail to keep informed or aware; She has so many books, she just lost track and cannot find this volume;
be ignorant of or in the dark about;
be aware of the truth of something; have a belief or faith in something; regard as true beyond any doubt; I know that I left the key on the table; Galileo knew that the earth moves around the sun;
know how to do or perform something; She knows how to knit; Does your husband know how to cook?;
have fixed in the mind; I know Latin; This student knows her irregular verbs; Do you know the poem well enough to recite it?;
have (something) mastered; She has the names of the fifty states down pat;
be well-informed;
have firsthand knowledge of states, situations, emotions, or sensations; I know the feeling!; have you ever known hunger?; I have lived a kind of hell when I was a drug addict; The holocaust survivors have lived a nightmare; I lived through two divorces;
experience briefly; The ex-slave tasted freedom shortly before she died;
experience again, often in the imagination; He relived the horrors of war;
have a firm understanding or knowledge of; be on top of; Do you control these data?;
be or become completely proficient or skilled in; She mastered Japanese in less than two years;
gain knowledge or skills; She learned dancing from her sister; I learned Sanskrit; Children acquire language at an amazing rate;
learn something again, as after having forgotten or neglected it; After the accident, he could not walk for months and had to relearn how to walk down stairs;
discard something previously learnt, like an old habit;
try to forget; put out of one's memory or knowledge;
learn belatedly; find out about something after it happened; I'm trying to catch up with the latest developments in molecular biology;
get to know or become aware of, usually accidentally; I learned that she has two grown-up children; I see that you have been promoted;
discover some bad or hidden information about; She got the goods on her co-worker after reading his e-mail;
get wise to; They wised up to it;
cause someone to become aware of something;
detect a blunder or misstep; The reporter tripped up the senator;
be a student of a certain subject; She is reading for the bar exam;
attend academic courses without getting credit;
consume all of one's attention or time; Her interest in butterflies absorbs her completely;
