a narrow-minded adherence to a particular sect or party or denomination; he condemned religious sectarianism;
the intolerance and prejudice of a bigot;
excessive intolerance of opposing views;
exaggerated religious zealotry;
extreme intolerance of antisocial behavior (usually by an uncompromising application of the law); he urged zero tolerance for priests who abuse children sexually;
an attitude of admiration or esteem; she lost all respect for him;
the respect with which a person is held; they had a high estimation of his ability;
the general estimation that the public has for a person; he acquired a reputation as an actor before he started writing; he was a person of bad report;
a disrespectful mental attitude;
a reverent mental attitude;
an irreverent mental attitude;
an attitude of irreverence or contempt for a divinity;
an integrated set of attitudes and beliefs;
a shared orientation leading to mutual understanding; they are on the same wavelength;
an orientation that favors experimentation and innovation; the children of psychologists are often raised in an atmosphere of experimentalism;
a fresh orientation; a changed set of attitudes and beliefs;
a way of regarding situations or topics etc.; consider what follows from the positivist view;
a situation or topic as if viewed from an altitude or distance;
the position that the meaning of life should be sought in the future;
the position of greatest importance or advancement; the leading position in any movement or field; the Cotswolds were once at the forefront of woollen manufacturing in England; the idea of motion was always to the forefront of his mind and central to his philosophy;
a viewpoint toward a city or other heavily populated area; the dominant character of the cityscape is it poverty;
an extensive mental viewpoint; the political landscape looks bleak without a change of administration; we changed the landscape for solving the problem of payroll inequity;
the generally accepted perspective of a particular discipline at a given time; he framed the problem within the psychoanalytic paradigm;
a mental position from which things are viewed; we should consider this problem from the viewpoint of the Russians; teaching history gave him a special point of view toward current events;
a particular perspective or aspect of a situation; although he saw it in a different light, he still did not understand;
a range of mental vision; in his sight she could do no wrong;
a biased way of looking at or presenting something;
a point of view or general attitude or inclination; he altered the complexion of his times; a liberal political complexion;
a comprehensive view of the world and human life;
the view that the universe resembles a clock built by God and ticking along according to Newtonian mechanics;
a noncommittal or equivocal position;
a belief or orientation agreeing with conventional standards;
orthodoxy in thoughts and belief;
conformity with conventional thought and behavior;
strict conformity to the letter of the law rather than its spirit;
any opinions or doctrines at variance with the official or orthodox position;
a lack of orthodoxy in thoughts or beliefs;
an orientation that characterizes the thinking of a group or nation;
the principle of complete and unrestricted power in government;
a political theory favoring the abolition of governments;
a political theory favoring unlimited authority by a single individual;
the political doctrine of Machiavelli: any means (however unscrupulous) can be used by a ruler in order to create and maintain his autocratic government;
a political philosophy of avoiding the extremes of left and right by taking a moderate position or course of action;
a political theory that the people should own the means of production;
a political theory favoring collectivism in a classless society;
a form of communism developed in Cuba by Fidel Castro;
the political and economic theories of Lenin which provided the guiding doctrine of the Soviet Union; the modification of Marxism by Lenin stressed that imperialism is the highest form of capitalism (which shifts the struggle from developed to underdeveloped countries);
a form of communism developed in China by Mao Zedong;
the economic and political theories of Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels that hold that human actions and institutions are economically determined and that class struggle is needed to create historical change and that capitalism will ultimately be superseded by communism;
the form of communism advocated by Leon Trotsky; calls for immediate worldwide revolution by the proletariat;
a political or theological orientation advocating the preservation of the best in society and opposing radical changes;
an approach to politics or theology that represents a return to a traditional point of view (in contrast to more liberal or radical schools of thought of the 1960s);
extreme conservatism in political or social matters; the forces of reaction carried the election;
a political orientation favoring political or racial segregation;
advocacy of a system of government according to constitutional principles;
the political orientation of those who favor government by the people or by their elected representatives;
the belief in a gradual transition from capitalism to socialism by democratic means;
the political theory that if one nation comes under communist control then neighboring nations will also come under communist control;
the attitude that society should be governed by an elite group of individuals;
any political theory favoring immoderate uncompromising policies;
a political theory advocating an authoritarian hierarchical government (as opposed to democracy or liberalism);
the idea of a federal organization of more or less self-governing units;
a political orientation that advocates imperial interests;
the ideology of the political left; belief in or support of the tenets of the political left;
a political orientation that favors social progress by reform and by changing laws rather than by revolution;
the belief that rulers should be chosen for their superior abilities and not because of their wealth or birth;
a political orientation originating in the 1960s; blends liberal political views with an emphasis on economic growth;
an ideological belief in freedom of thought and speech;
a belief in and advocacy of monarchy as a political system;
an ideological position that holds Black culture to be independent and valid on its own terms; an affirmation of the African cultural heritage;
the political philosophy of the Orleanists;
the political orientation of those who favor progress toward better conditions in government and society;
the political orientation of those who favor revolutionary change in government and society;
the ideology of the most radical element of the French Revolution that instituted the Reign of Terror;
the political orientation of reactionaries;
the political orientation of those who hold that a republic is the best form of government;
the ideology of the political right; belief in or support of the tenets of the political right;
a political theory advocating state ownership of industry;
socialism to be established by gradual reforms within the law;
a form of socialist theory advocating state ownership of industry but managements by guilds of workers;
socialism achieved by voluntary sacrifice;
the belief in government by divine guidance;
the political orientation of a Utopian who believes in impossibly idealistic schemes of social perfection;
any political orientation favoring compromise to avoid conflict;
any policy that advocates maintaining peaceful international relations;
any political orientation favoring aggressive policies;
a political orientation of a people or a government to maintain a strong military force and to be prepared to use it aggressively to defend or promote national interests;
a policy of advocating war;
an attitude toward religion or religious practices;
a religious orientation of doubt; a denial of ultimate knowledge of the existence of God; agnosticism holds that you can neither prove nor disprove God's existence;
the heretical doctrine (associated with the Gnostics) that Jesus had no human body and his sufferings and death on the cross were apparent rather than real;
a religious orientation advocating gnosis as the way to release a person's spiritual element; considered heresy by Christian churches;
a Gnostic religion originating the 2nd and 3rd centuries that believes John the Baptist was the Messiah and that incorporates Jewish and Christian elements into a framework of dualistic beliefs;
the doctrine or belief that there is no God;
the doctrine or belief in the existence of a God or gods;
the form of theological rationalism that believes in God on the basis of reason without reference to revelation;
belief in a single God;
belief in multiple Gods;
(Christianity) the heretical belief that the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit are three separate gods;
any of various religions other than Christianity or Judaism or Islamism;
