the states'-rights doctrine that a state can refuse to recognize or to enforce a federal law passed by the United States Congress;
a doctrine that is taught; the teachings of religion; he believed all the Christian precepts;
(Judaism) a precept or commandment of the Jewish law;
the doctrine of a religious group;
a religious doctrine or theory based on Jesus or Jesus' teachings;
the theological doctrine that by faith and God's grace a Christian is freed from all laws (including the moral standards of the culture);
the comprehensive theological doctrine created by Saint Thomas Aquinas in the 13th century and still taught by the Dominicans;
doctrine that the useful is the good; especially as elaborated by Jeremy Bentham and James Mill; the aim was said to be the greatest happiness for the greatest number;
heretical doctrine taught by Arius that asserted the radical primacy of the Father over the Son;
the theological doctrine taught by Athanasius that Christ the Son is of the same substance as God the Father;
the mystical theological doctrine of Jakob Boehme that influenced the Quakers;
the doctrine of the High Anglican Church that after the consecration of the Eucharist the substance of the body and blood of Christ coexists with the substance of the consecrated bread and wine;
the theological doctrine of church government by bishops;
the doctrine that the state is supreme over the church in ecclesiastical matters;
the religious doctrine of Hinayana Buddhism;
the Roman Catholic doctrine of Cornelis Jansen and his disciples; salvation is limited to those who are subject to supernatural determinism and the rest are assigned to perdition;
the religious doctrine of Mahayana Buddhism;
the Christian heresy of the 2nd and 3rd centuries that rejected the Old Testament and denied the incarnation of God in Jesus as a human;
belief in the Christian doctrine of the millennium mentioned in the Book of Revelations;
a Christian heresy of the 5th and 6th centuries that challenged the orthodox definition of the two natures (human and divine) in Jesus and instead believed there was a single divine nature;
the theological doctrine that Christ had only one will even though he had two natures (human and divine); condemned as heretical in the Third Council of Constantinople;
the theological doctrine (named after Nestorius) that Christ is both the son of God and the man Jesus (which is opposed to Roman Catholic doctrine that Christ is fully God);
the theological doctrine put forward by Pelagius which denied original sin and affirmed the ability of humans to be righteous; condemned as heresy by the Council of Ephesus in 431;
the theological doctrine of the Society of Friends characterized by opposition to war and rejection of ritual and a formal creed and an ordained ministry;
the theological doctrine that human reason rather than divine revelation establishes religious truth;
the Hindu or Buddhist doctrine that a person may be reborn successively into one of five classes of living beings (god or human or animal or hungry ghost or denizen of Hell) depending on the person's own actions;
the theological doctrine that venerates the rose and the cross as symbols of Christ's Resurrection and redemption; claims various occult powers;
the branch of Christian theology that deals with salvation as the effect of a divine agency;
the theological doctrine that salvation results from the interaction of human will and divine grace;
the Calvinist doctrine that everyone is born in a state of corruption as a result of original sin;
any system of philosophy emphasizing the intuitive and spiritual above the empirical and material;
the Roman Catholic doctrine that the whole substance of the bread and the wine changes into the substance of the body and blood of Christ when consecrated in the Eucharist;
the theological doctrine that all people will eventually be saved;
the paleontology of vertebrates;
the theological doctrine that Jesus Christ had no human father; Christians believe that Jesus's birth fulfilled Old Testament prophecies and was attended by miracles; the Nativity is celebrated at Christmas;
a complex mental state involving beliefs and feelings and values and dispositions to act in certain ways; he had the attitude that work was fun;
the mental attitude that something is believable and should be accepted as true; he gave credence to the gossip; acceptance of Newtonian mechanics was unquestioned for 200 years;
a submissive mental attitude resulting from acceptance of the doctrine that everything that happens is predetermined and inevitable;
an acceptance (as of a claim) as true and valid; the recognition of the Rio Grande as a boundary between Mexico and the United States;
the attitudes and behavior that are characteristic of a particular social group or organization; the developing drug culture; the reason that the agency is doomed to inaction has something to do with the FBI culture;
the culture that emerges from the use of computers for communication and entertainment and business;
the attitudes and behavior in a social group that resolves political disputes by force of arms; the Kalashnikov culture in Afghanistan;
a highly diverse culture; the city's mosaic culture results in great diversity in the arts;
an attitude of defensiveness(especiallyinthephraseonthedefensive);
a no-nonsense attitude in business or politics; they play hardball in the Senate;
an attitude of arrogant superiority; get off your high horse and admit you are wrong;
an attitude characteristic of Southerners (especially in the US);
a habitual or characteristic mental attitude that determines how you will interpret and respond to situations;
the attitude (of a person or a government) that subordinates should be controlled in a fatherly way for their own good;
a rationalized mental attitude;
a firm and uncompromising stance or position; the governor took a hard line on drugs;
an attitude of mind especially one that favors one alternative over others; he had an inclination to give up too easily; a tendency to be too strict;
a general course along which something has a tendency to develop; I couldn't follow the direction of his thoughts; his ideals determined the direction of his career; they proposed a new direction for the firm;
a settled or prevailing or habitual course of a person's life; nothing disturbed the even tenor of her ways;
a general tendency to change (as of opinion); not openly liberal but that is the trend of the book; a broad movement of the electorate to the right;
a general direction of evolutionary change;
an evolutionary trend to be born earlier so that development is cut off at an earlier stage and juvenile characteristics are retained in adults of the species;
a figurative movement toward some attraction; the gravitation of the middle class to the suburbs;
a special disposition (as if from a divine source) to pursue a particular course; he was disappointed that he had not heard the Call;
the tendency, in Protestantism, to separate into religious denominations or to advocate such separations;
an inclination or desire; used in the plural in the phrase left to your own devices; eventually the family left the house to the devices of this malevolent force; the children were left to their own devices;
an inclination to support or be loyal to or to agree with an opinion; his sympathies were always with the underdog; I knew I could count on his understanding;
an inclination to favor some person or group;
a natural inclination; he has a proclivity for exaggeration;
a relatively permanent inclination to react in a particular way; the set of his mind was obvious;
a disposition to interpret statements in their literal sense;
the tendency for a memory or idea to persist or recur without any apparent stimulus for it;
an inclination beforehand to interpret statements in a particular way;
a predisposition in favor of something; a predilection for expensive cars; his sexual preferences; showed a Marxist orientation;
an inclination to approve; that style is in favor this season;
an inclination to withhold approval from some person or group;
an idiomatic term for being in disfavor; in the doghouse;
severe disapproval;
an inclination to favor one group or view or opinion over alternatives;
an inclination to evaluate reality exclusively in terms of human values;
belief in the superiority of one's own ethnic group;
belief in the preeminence of Europe and the Europeans;
a partiality that prevents objective consideration of an issue or situation;
a slight but noticeable partiality; the court's tilt toward conservative rulings;
a partiality for some particular place;
partiality that is not fair or equitable;
an inclination to weigh both views or opinions equally;
freedom from bias or from selfish motives;
ability to make judgments free from discrimination or dishonesty;
(psychology) bias introduced by an experimenter whose expectations about the outcome of the experiment can be subtly communicated to the participants in the experiment;
prejudice against (fear or dislike of) homosexual people and homosexuality;
prejudice against Muslims; Muslim intellectuals are afraid of growing Islamophobia in the West;
the prejudice that members of one race are intrinsically superior to members of other races;
the intense dislike for and prejudice against Jewish people;
the prejudice that members of the white race are superior to members of other races;
an intentional and controversial bias;
willingness to recognize and respect the beliefs or practices of others;
an inclination to tolerate or overlook opposing or shocking opinions or behavior;
an inclination to favor progress and individual freedom;
tolerance attributable to a lack of involvement;
unwillingness to recognize and respect differences in opinions or beliefs;
an inclination to criticize opposing opinions or shocking behavior;
a limitation of views or interests like that defined by a local parish;
narrowness of mind or ideas or views;
a lack of sophistication;
