not explained; accomplished by some unexplained process;
injurious to physical or mental health; noxious chemical wastes; noxious ideas;
exceedingly harmful;
harmful to the mind or morals; corrupt judges and their corrupting influence; the vicious and degrading cult of violence;
causing blisters;
not injurious to physical or mental health;
having no adverse effect;
dutifully complying with the commands or instructions of those in authority; an obedient soldier; obedient children; a little man obedient to his wife; the obedient colonies...are heavily taxed; the refractory remain unburdened- Edmund Burke;
willing to carry out the orders or wishes of another without protest; too acquiescent to challenge authority;
quick to comply; I have been to you a true and humble wife, at all times to your will conformable-Shakespeare;
willingly obedient out of a sense of duty and respect; a dutiful child; a dutiful citizen; Patient Griselda was a chaste and duteous wife;
prepared to accurately process date and time data between and into the 20th and 21st centuries;
not obeying or complying with commands of those in authority; disobedient children;
resistant to guidance or discipline; Mary Mary quite contrary; an obstinate child with a violent temper; a perverse mood; wayward behavior;
stubbornly resistant to authority or control; a fractious animal that would not submit to the harness; a refractory child;
habitually disposed to disobedience and opposition;
refusing to submit to authority; the recusant electors...cooperated in electing a new Senate- Mary W.Williams;
undesirably noticeable; the obtrusive behavior of a spoiled child; equally obtrusive was the graffiti;
not obtrusive or undesirably noticeable; a quiet, unobtrusive life of self-denial;
undistorted by emotion or personal bias; based on observable phenomena; an objective appraisal; objective evidence;
scientifically detached; unemotional; he spoke in the clipped clinical monotones typical of police testimony;
having no personal preference; impersonal criticism; a neutral observer;
capable of being verified; a verifiable account of the incident;
taking place within the mind and modified by individual bias; a subjective judgment;
particular to a given individual;
emanating from a person's emotions and prejudices;
(of e.g. evidence) not objective or easily verified;
caused by law or conscience to follow a certain course; felt obligated to repay the kindness; was obligated to pay off the student loan;
under a moral obligation to someone;
under a moral obligation to do something;
owing gratitude or recognition to another for help or favors etc;
under a legal obligation to someone;
required or under orders; I'm supposed to be there at ten; he was supposed to go to the store;
paying tribute; a tributary colony;
not obligated;
free of moral obligation;
restricted to a particular condition of life; an obligate anaerobe can survive only in the absence of oxygen;
able to exist under more than one set of conditions; a facultative parasite can exist as a parasite or a saprophyte;
easily perceived by the senses or grasped by the mind; obvious errors;
clearly revealed to the mind or the senses or judgment; the effects of the drought are apparent to anyone who sees the parched fields; evident hostility; manifest disapproval; patent advantages; made his meaning plain; it is plain that he is no reactionary; in plain view;
evident without proof or argument; an axiomatic truth; we hold these truths to be self-evident;
capable of being demonstrated or proved; obvious lies; a demonstrable lack of concern for the general welfare; practical truth provable to all men- Walter Bagehot;
clearly manifest; evident; frank enjoyment;
so obvious as to be easily solved or decided; an open-and-shut case;
needing no explanation;
easily understood or seen through (because of a lack of subtlety); a transparent explanation; a transparent lie;
made more obvious or prominent; the effect of...his irregular life could be seen writ large on his gaunt features;
not immediately apparent; in mathematical science connections are exhibited which...are extremely unobvious- A.N.Whitehead;
not readily apparent; the answer was at first unapparent;
not provable; it was both unproved and unprovable;
shut off to passage or view or hindered from action; a partially obstructed passageway; an obstructed view; justice obstructed is not justice;
preventing entry or exit or a course of action; a barricaded street; barred doors; the blockaded harbor;
completely obstructed or closed off; the storm was responsible for many blocked roads and bridges; the drain was plugged;
stopped up; clogged up; clogged pipes; clogged up freeways; streets choked with traffic;
at a complete standstill because of opposition of two unrelenting forces or factions; the chess game ended with white stalemated; the two factions are deadlocked over fringe benefits;
made difficult or slow; we blamed our impeded progress on lack of money;
closed off; an occluded artery;
(of a nose) blocked; a stopped (or stopped-up) nose;
affected with a sensation of stoppage or obstruction; a stuffy feeling in my chest;
affected with or obstructed by a clot of coagulated blood;
free from impediment or obstruction or hindrance; an unobstructed view;
affording free passage or view; a clear view; a clear path to victory; open waters; the open countryside;
(of a bodily tube or passageway) open; affording free passage; patent ductus arteriosus;
not slowed or prevented; a time of unimpeded growth; an unimpeded sweep of meadows and hills afforded a peaceful setting;
freed of obstructions; an unclogged drain;
held or filled or in use; she keeps her time well occupied; the wc is occupied;
(of facilities such as telephones or lavatories) unavailable for use by anyone else or indicating unavailability; (engagedis a British term for a busy telephone line); her line is busy; receptionists' telephones are always engaged; the lavatory is in use; kept getting a busy signal;
(of time) taken up; well-filled hours;
not held or filled or in use; an unoccupied telephone booth; unoccupied hours;
not occupied or in use; a free locker; a free lane;
not taken up by scheduled activities; a free hour between classes; spare time on my hands;
seized and controlled as by military invasion; the occupied countries of Europe;
not seized and controlled; unoccupied areas of France;
that has been withdrawn or retreated from;
unpleasant or disgusting especially to the senses; offensive odors;
offensive to the mind; an abhorrent deed; the obscene massacre at Wounded Knee; morally repugnant customs; repulsive behavior; the most repulsive character in recent novels;
gruesomely indicative of death or the dead; a charnel smell came from the chest filled with dead men's bones; ghastly shrieks; the sepulchral darkness of the catacombs;
annoying and unpleasant; some creepy kids were bothering her;
highly offensive; arousing aversion or disgust; a disgusting smell; distasteful language; a loathsome disease; the idea of eating meat is repellent to me; revolting food; a wicked stench;
suggesting the horror of death and decay; morbid details;
grossly offensive to decency or morality; causing horror; subjected to outrageous cruelty; a hideous pattern of injustice; horrific conditions in the mining industry;
causing disapproval or protest; a vulgar and objectionable person;
very offensive in smell or taste; a rank cigar;
dirty and disgusting; worry about the gossip and secretiveness and other scrimy sides- Al Hine;
of the nature of vermin; very offensive or repulsive;
giving no offense; a quiet inoffensive man; a refreshing inoffensive stimulant;
not causing disapproval; it was an innocuous remark; confined himself to innocuous generalities; unobjectionable behavior;
morally wholesome or acceptable; a past that was scarcely savory;
morally offensive; an unsavory reputation; an unsavory scandal;
morally offensive; odoriferous legislation;
causing anger or annoyance; offensive remarks;
expressing offensive reproach;
not causing anger or annoyance; inoffensive behavior;
incapable of offending or attacking;
for the purpose of attack rather than defense; offensive weapons;
designed to inflict death or personal injury rather than material destruction;
disposed to attack;
designed for or consisting of a brief attack followed by a quick escape; hit-and-run units; tip-and-run assaults;
involving invasion or aggressive attack; invasive war;
characterized by plundering or pillaging or marauding; bands of marauding Indians; predatory warfare; a raiding party;
