act or give recompense in recognition of someone's behavior or actions;
steal goods; take as spoils; During the earthquake people looted the stores that were deserted by their owners;
plunder (a town) after capture; the barbarians sacked Rome;
take illegally; of intellectual property; This writer plundered from famous authors;
subsist on a meager allowance; scratch and scrimp;
give up what is not strictly needed; he asked if they could spare one of their horses to speed his journey;
import or export without paying customs duties; She smuggled cigarettes across the border;
bring in from abroad;
sell or transfer abroad; we export less than we import and have a negative trade balance;
take up and practice as one's own;
choose and follow; as of theories, ideas, policies, strategies or plans; She followed the feminist movement; The candidate espouses Republican ideals;
leave as a guarantee in return for money; pawn your grandfather's gold watch;
hand over something to somebody as for temporary safekeeping; Check your coat at the door;
give over to another for care or safekeeping; consign your baggage;
consign for shipment on a vehicle; check your luggage before boarding;
commit again; It was recommitted into her custody;
commit in order to fulfill an obligation; obligate money;
commit forever; commit irrevocably;
send to an address;
cause to be admitted; of persons to an institution; After the second episode, she had to be committed; he was committed to prison;
admit into a hospital; Mother had to be hospitalized because her blood pressure was too high;
confer a trust upon; The messenger was entrusted with the general's secret; I commit my soul to God;
cut the price of;
assure payment of;
guarantee payment on; of checks;
bear the expenses of;
keep in one's possession; of animals;
relieve from; Rid the house of pests;
clear from impurities, blemishes, pollution, etc.; clear the water before it can be drunk;
rid of vermin; The exterminator disinfests the house;
free from a body or physical form or reality;
sell at artificially low prices;
determine the price of; The grocer priced his wares high;
manipulate in a fraudulent manner; rig prices;
price excessively high;
sell cheaper than one's competition;
offer for sale at a price lower than the market price;
put up as security or collateral;
issue bonds on;
eliminate by paying off (debts) ;
pay off (a mortgage) ;
liquidate gradually;
provide with cleats; cleat running shoes for better traction;
terminate by selling off or disposing of; He closed out his line of sports cars;
supply with coal;
furnish with a corbel;
furnish with a cornice;
get by acting quickly and smartly; snag a bargain;
provide with a constitution, as of a country; The United States were constitutionalized in the late 18th century;
provide with a copper bottom; copper-bottom a frying pan;
provide with drapery; curtain the bedrooms;
confiscate by distress;
levy a distress on;
supply with a gate; The house was gated;
buy on impulse without proper reflection;
provide with an index; index the book;
provide with a joint; the carpenter jointed two pieces of wood;
provide with electrical circuits; wire the addition to the house;
provide with new wiring; the university rewired the dormitories when most students brought computers and television sets;
give, sell, or transfer to another; She disposed of her parents' possessions;
dispose anew; The goods were redisposed at a great loss;
pay a kickback; make an illegal payment;
get in addition, as an increase; The candidate picked up thousands of votes after his visit to the nursing home;
achieve a point or goal; Nicklaus had a 70; The Brazilian team got 4 goals; She made 29 points that day;
supply in large amounts or quantities; We poured money into the education of our children;
dispose of by selling; The chairman of the company told the salesmen to move the computers;
supply in great quantities; Pump money into a project;
put into the care or protection of someone; He left the decision to his deputy; leave your child the nurse's care;
provide with fuel; Oil fires the furnace;
show appreciation to; He remembered her in his will;
supply with an excess of; flood the market with tennis shoes; Glut the country with cheap imports from the Orient;
add as an extra or as a gratuity;
return in kind; return a compliment; return her love;
spend sparingly, avoid the waste of; This move will save money; The less fortunate will have to economize now;
provide with a toggle or toggles;
provide with a patch; also used metaphorically; The field was patched with snow;
provide with water; We watered the buffalo;
afford access to; the door opens to the patio; The French doors give onto a terrace;
obtain illegally or unscrupulously; Grab power;
carry out or perform; deliver an attack, deliver a blow; The boxer drove home a solid left;
deliver (a blow) ; He landed several blows on his opponent's head;
to be given by assignment or distribution; The most difficult task fell on the youngest member of the team; The onus fell on us; The pressure to succeed fell on the youngest student;
to be given by right or inheritance; The estate fell to the oldest daughter;
demand payment of (a loan) ; Call a loan;
have on the surface or on the skin; carry scars;
acquire as a result of some effort or action; You cannot get water out of a stone; Where did she get these news?;
deliver in exchange or recompense; I'll give you three books for four CDs;
provide with leverage; We need to leverage this company;
supplement with leverage; leverage the money that is already available;
get or extort (money or other possessions) from someone; They bled me dry--I have nothing left!;
free or relieve (someone) of a burden;
furnish with a tap or spout, so as to be able to draw liquid from it; tap a cask of wine;
provide with a top or finish the top (of a structure) ; the towers were topped with conical roofs;
provide with reflectors, such as chemicals; the driveway was reflectorized for safety reasons;
substitute one creditor for another, as in the case where an insurance company sues the person who caused an accident for the insured;
obtain goods or services from an outside supplier; to contract work out; Many companies outsource and hire consultants in order to maintain a flexible workforce;
provide with parts, devices, or equipment not available or in use at the time of the original manufacture; They car companies retrofitted all the old models with new carburetors;
provide with a border or edge; edge the tablecloth with embroidery;
supply with projecting galleries; machicolate the castle walls;
provide with sanitary facilities or appliances;
