calculate principal and interest;
accumulate money for future use; He saves half his salary;
spend lavishly or wastefully on; He blew a lot of money on his new home theater;
spend at a high rate;
spend wastefully; wanton one's money away;
spend at less than the normal rate;
spend (money or other resources) unwisely;
spend money frugally; spend as little as possible;
spend less; buy at a reduced price;
pay out; spend money;
spend completely; I spend my pocket money in two days;
spend more than available of (a budget) ;
spend less than the whole of (a budget, for example) ;
require (time or space) ; It took three hours to get to work this morning; This event occupied a very short time;
spend or use time; I may be an hour;
spend thoughtlessly; throw away; He wasted his inheritance on his insincere friends; You squandered the opportunity to get and advanced degree;
live frugally and use less resources; In the new economy, we all have to learn to tighten our belts;
spend (significant amounts of money) ; He has money to burn;
indulge oneself; I splurged on a new TV;
use cautiously and frugally; I try to economize my spare time; conserve your energy for the ascent to the summit;
structure and run according to rational or scientific principles in order to achieve desired results; We rationalized the factory's production and raised profits;
tighten one's belt; use resources carefully;
collect or look around for (food) ;
forage food;
obtain or seek to obtain by cadging or wheedling; he is always shnorring cigarettes from his friends;
ask for and get free; be a parasite;
live off somebody's generosity; This young man refuses to work and is freeloading;
ask to obtain free; beg money and food;
beg by accosting people in the street and asking for money;
make an investment; Put money into bonds;
re-invest (a previous investment) into a similar fund or security; She rolled over her IRA;
negociate to repay a loan at a later date for an additional fee; roll over a loan;
invest (money) so that it is not taxable;
invest so as to make unavailable for other purposes; All my money is tied up in long-term investments;
invest at a risk; I bought this house not because I want to live in it but to sell it later at a good price, so I am speculating;
try to raise the price of stocks through speculative buying;
take possession of by force, as after an invasion; the invaders seized the land and property of the inhabitants; The army seized the town; The militia captured the castle;
conquer anew; The country reconquered the territory lost in the previous war;
occupy or take possession of beforehand or before another or appropriate for use in advance; the army preoccupied the hills;
take temporary possession of as a security, by legal authority; The FBI seized the drugs; The customs agents impounded the illegal shipment; The police confiscated the stolen artwork;
appropriate (property) for public use; the county condemned the land to build a highway;
requisition forcibly, as of enemy property; the estate was sequestered;
take a debtor's wages on legal orders, such as for child support; His employer garnished his wages in order to pay his debt;
take over ownership of; of corporations and companies;
seize and take control without authority and possibly with force; take as one's right or possession; He assumed to himself the right to fill all positions in the town; he usurped my rights; She seized control of the throne after her husband died;
seize control of; they hijacked the judicial process;
take over (a company) by buying a controlling interest of its stock; T. Boone Pickens raided many large companies;
demand as being one's due or property; assert one's right or title to; He claimed his suitcases at the airline counter; Mr. Smith claims special tax exemptions because he is a foreign resident;
put forward a claim and assert right or possession of; pretend the title of King;
demand and take for use or service, especially by military or public authority for public service;
release from government control;
claim back;
legally take something in place of a debt payment;
subject to foreclosing procedures; take away the right of mortgagors to redeem their mortgage;
make undue claims to having;
make off with belongings of others;
take illegally; rustle cattle;
steal in a store;
rob at gunpoint or by means of some other threat;
rob at gunpoint or with the threat of violence; I was mugged in the streets of New York last night;
copy illegally; of published material;
take without referencing from someone else's writing or speech; of intellectual property;
take unauthorized (intellectual material) ;
put in one's pocket; He pocketed the change;
make a lot of money;
make a profit; gain money or materially; The company has not profited from the merger;
make a satisfactory profit; The company turned a nice dime after a short time;
make a big profit; often in a short period of time; The investor really cleaned up when the stock market went up;
take advantage of or capitalize on;
make an unreasonable profit, as on the sale of difficult to obtain goods;
draw advantages from; he is capitalizing on her mistake; she took advantage of his absence to meet her lover;
make neither profit nor loss;
keep in safety and protect from harm, decay, loss, or destruction; We preserve these archeological findings; The old lady could not keep up the building; children must be taught to conserve our national heritage; The museum curator conserved the ancient manuscripts;
preserve (tissue) with plastics, as for teaching and research purposes; The doctor plastinates bodies to teach anatomy to his students;
deplete; exhaust one's savings; We quickly played out our strength;
keep or lay aside for future use; store grain for the winter; The bear stores fat for the period of hibernation when he doesn't eat;
lay in provisions; The vessel victualled before the long voyage;
put into long-term storage;
put (something) in a place for storage; the treasure found int he ancient tomb was reposited in the museum;
store on a wharf; Wharf the merchandise;
store in a tank by causing (something) to flow into it;
store in a loft;
store in a warehouse;
find a place for and put away for storage; where should we stow the vegetables?; I couldn't store all the books in the attic so I sold some;
keep or store in a garage; we don't garage our car;
store (liquids or gases) in bottles;
store in a silo; ensile fodder for the cows;
secure and keep for possible future use or application; The landlord retained the security deposit; I reserve the right to disagree;
keep; She manages to hold down two jobs;
retain rights to; keep my job for me while I give birth; keep my seat, please; keep open the possibility of a merger;
pay in advance; Can you advance me some money?;
make illegal payments to in exchange for favors or influence; This judge can be bought;
give a conciliatory gift or bribe to;
buy stocks or shares of a company;
take money from an illegal transaction;
pay someone with influence in order to receive a favor;
pay back; Please refund me my money;
pay back for some expense incurred; Can the company reimburse me for my professional travel?;
have on hand; Do you carry kerosene heaters?;
come upon after searching; find the location of something that was missed or lost; Did you find your glasses?; I cannot find my gloves!;
