tall herb with panicles of white flowers flushed with green; northwestern United States; sometimes placed in genus Swertia;
type genus of the Gentianaceae; cosmopolitan genus of herbs nearly cosmopolitan in cool temperate regions; in some classifications includes genera Gentianopsis and Gentianella;
any of various plants of the family Gentianaceae especially the genera Gentiana and Gentianella and Gentianopsis;
low-growing alpine plant cultivated for its dark glossy green leaves in basal rosettes and showy solitary bell-shaped blue flowers;
gentian of eastern North America having tubular blue or white flowers that open little if at all;
tufted sometimes sprawling perennial with blue flowers spotted with green; western North America;
similar to Gentiana andrewsii but with larger flowers;
robust European perennial having clusters of yellow flowers;
perennial Eurasian gentian with sky-blue funnel-shaped flowers of damp open heaths;
erect perennial of wet woodlands of North America having leaves and flower buds resembling those of soapwort;
a perennial marsh gentian of eastern North America;
genus of herbs with flowers that resemble gentian; in some classifications included in genus Gentiana;
gentian of eastern North America having clusters of bristly blue flowers;
gentian of Europe and China having creamy white flowers with fringed corollas;
genus of fringed gentians; in some classifications included in genus Gentiana;
any of various herbs of the genus Gentianopsis having the margins of the corolla lobes fringed; sometimes included in genus Gentiana;
tall widely distributed fringed gentian of eastern North America having violet-blue or white fringed flowers;
medium-tall fringed gentian with pale-blue to blue-purple flowers; circumboreal in distribution;
small blue-flowered fringed gentian of east central North America;
small blue-flowered fringed gentian of western United States (Rocky Mountains) especially around hot springs in Yellowstone National Park;
small blue-flowered fringed gentian of Sierra Nevada mountains;
genus of herbs of Eurasia and the Americas: spurred gentians;
any of various plants of the genus Halenia having flowers with spurred lobes;
genus of smooth slender North American herbs with showy flowers;
any of various plants of the genus Sabbatia having usually pink cymose flowers; occur from acid bogs to brackish marshes;
any of several pink-flowered marsh plant of the eastern United States resembling a true centaury;
prairie herb with solitary lilac-colored flowers;
genus of herbs of mountains of North America and Eurasia and Africa;
perennial of damp places in mountains of Eurasia and North America having dull-colored blue or violet flowers;
a family of Old World shrubs and trees of order Gentianales; related to Oleaceae but having four stamens and four petals;
genus of evergreen trees or shrubs; fruit is a drupe; grows in Africa through Arabia to India and China;
glabrous or pubescent evergreen shrub or tree of the genus Salvadora; twigs are fibrous and in some parts of the world are bound together in clusters and used as a toothbrush; shoots are used as camel fodder; plant ash provides salt;
trees and shrubs having berries or drupes or capsules as fruits; sometimes placed in the order Oleales: olive; ash; jasmine; privet; lilac;
coextensive with the family Oleaceae; in some classifications included in the order Gentianales;
evergreen trees and shrubs having oily one-seeded fruits;
a tree of the genus Olea cultivated for its fruit;
hard yellow often variegated wood of an olive tree; used in cabinetwork;
evergreen tree cultivated in the Mediterranean region since antiquity and now elsewhere; has edible shiny black fruits;
small ovoid fruit of the European olive tree; important food and source of oil;
northern Zealand tree having dense hard light-brown wood;
small New Zealand tree having red pulpy one-seeded fruit;
deciduous trees or shrubs: fringe tree;
any of various small decorative flowering trees or shrubs of the genus Chionanthus;
small bushy tree of southeastern United States having profuse clusters of white flowers;
genus of often spiny American shrubs and trees;
any plant of the genus Forestiera;
spiny branching deciduous shrub of southwestern United States having clusters of insignificant yellow-white flowers appearing before leaves followed by attractive black berrylike fruits;
forsythia;
any of various early blooming oleaceous shrubs of the genus Forsythia; native to eastern Asia and southern Europe but widely cultivated for their branches of bright yellow bell-shaped flowers;
ash;
any of various deciduous pinnate-leaved ornamental or timber trees of the genus Fraxinus;
strong elastic wood of any of various ash trees; used for furniture and tool handles and sporting goods such as baseball bats;
spreading American ash with leaves pale green or silvery beneath and having hard brownish wood;
small ash of swampy areas of southeastern United States;
shrubby ash of southwestern United States having fragrant white flowers;
shrubby California ash with showy off-white flowers;
tall ash of Europe to the Caucasus having leaves shiny dark-green above and pale downy beneath;
timber tree of western North America yielding hard light wood; closely related to the red ash;
vigorous spreading North American tree having dark brown heavy wood; leaves turn gold in autumn;
southern Mediterranean ash having fragrant white flowers in dense panicles and yielding manna;
smallish American tree with velvety branchlets and lower leaf surfaces;
a variety of red ash having glossy branchlets and lower leaf surfaces;
ash of central and southern United States with bluish-green foliage and hard brown wood;
low-growing ash of Texas;
timber tree of central and southeastern United States having hairy branchlets and a swollen trunk base;
small shrubby ash of southwestern United States and northwestern Mexico;
winged seed of the ash tree;
shrubs and woody climbers mostly of tropical and temperate Old World: jasmine; jessamine;
any of several shrubs and vines of the genus Jasminum chiefly native to Asia;
evergreen rambling yellow-flowered shrub of western China;
deciduous rambling shrub widely cultivated for its winter-blooming yellow flowers;
a climbing deciduous shrub with fragrant white or yellow or red flowers used in perfume and to flavor tea;
East Indian evergreen vine cultivated for its profuse fragrant white flowers;
genus of Old World shrubs: privet;
any of various Old World shrubs having smooth entire leaves and terminal panicles of small white flowers followed by small black berries; many used for hedges;
eastern Asian shrub cultivated especially for its persistent foliage;
fast-growing and tightly branched hybrid of Ligustrum ovalifolium and Ligustrum obtusifolium;
evergreen shrub of Japan and Korea having small dark leaves and flowers in loose panicles; related to but smaller than Chinese privet;
erect evergreen treelike shrub of China and Korea and Japan having acuminate leaves and flowers in long erect panicles; resembles Japanese privet;
small deciduous shrub having graceful arching branches and luxuriant foliage;
semi-evergreen Japanese shrub having malodorous flowers; used extensively for hedges because more likely to stay green that common privet;
deciduous semi-evergreen shrub used for hedges;
widely distributed genus of evergreen shrubs or trees of southern United States and Middle East and China and Japan;
small tree of southern United States having panicles of dull white flowers followed by dark purple fruits;
small genus of evergreen shrubs of the Mediterranean region;
evergreen shrub with white flowers and olivelike fruits;
genus of Old World shrubs or low trees having fragrant flowers in showy panicles: lilacs;
any of various plants of the genus Syringa having large panicles of usually fragrant flowers;
robust upright shrub of mountains of northern India having oblong-elliptic leaves and pale lilac or white malodorous flowers;
central European upright shrub having elliptic leaves and upright clusters of lilac or deep violet flowers;
small densely branching Asiatic shrub having lanceolate leaves and panicles of fragrant lilac flowers;
small tree of Japan having narrow pointed leaves and creamy-white flowers;
lilac of northern China having ovate leaves and profuse early summer rose-lilac flowers;
large European lilac naturalized in North America having heart-shaped ovate leaves and large panicles of highly fragrant lilac or white flowers;
hardened sugary exudation of various trees;
some genera placed in family Liliaceae;
any of various plants of the family Haemodoraceae; roots contain a deep red coloring matter;
type genus of family Haemodoraceae;
genus of monocotyledonous plants with curious woolly flowers on sturdy stems above a fan of sword-shaped leaves; includes kangaroo's paw and Australian sword lily; sometimes placed in family Amaryllidaceae;
sedgelike spring-flowering herb having clustered flowers covered with woolly hairs; Australia;
