not suitable or right or appropriate; slightly improper to dine alone with a married man; improper medication; improper attire for the golf course;
not in keeping with accepted standards of what is right or proper in polite society; was buried with indecent haste; indecorous behavior; language unbecoming to a lady; unseemly to use profanity; moved to curb their untoward ribaldry;
improper or even offensive; out-of-the-way remarks;
not in accord with established usage or procedure; the wrong medicine; the wrong way to shuck clams; it is incorrect for a policeman to accept gifts;
foretelling events as if by supernatural intervention; prophetic writings; prophetic powers; words that proved prophetic;
indistinctly prophetic;
prophetic of devastation or ultimate doom;
foreseeing the future;
obscurely prophetic; Delphic pronouncements; an oracular message;
resembling or characteristic of a prophet or prophecy; the high priest's divinatory pronouncement; mantic powers; a kind of sibylline book with ready and infallible answers to questions;
ominously prophetic;
warning of future misfortune;
of or relating to prediction; having value for making predictions;
not prophetic; not foreseeing correctly;
not offering prognostications;
having no predictive value;
of or concerned with or related to the future; prospective earnings; a prospective mother; a prospective bride; the statute is solely prospective in operation;
expected to become or be; in prospect; potential clients;
effective in or looking toward the future; he was preparing for future employment opportunities;
concerned with or related to the past; retrospective self-justification;
affecting things past; retroactive tax increase; an ex-post-facto law; retro pay;
kept safe or defended from danger or injury or loss; the most protected spot I could find;
secured with bastions or fortifications;
protected with battlements or parapets with indentations or embrasures for shooting through;
secure against burglary;
(of a wife) being under the protection of her husband; a woman covert;
protected by a deep wide ditch usually filled with water;
(used especially of machinery) protected by a shield to prevent injury;
offering safety; well protected or concealed; a snug harbor; a snug hideout;
protected against or able to withstand storms;
able to withstand exposure to weather without damage; weatherproof electric wiring; a weatherproof coat;
lacking protection or defense;
with no protection or shield; the exposed northeast frontier; open to the weather; an open wound;
having no protecting or concealing cover; naked to mine enemies- Shakespeare;
(used especially of machinery) not protected by a shield;
intended or adapted to afford protection of some kind; a protective covering; the use of protective masks and equipment; protective coatings; kept the drunken sailor in protective custody; animals with protective coloring; protective tariffs;
warding off; the swastika...a very ancient prophylactic symbol occurring among all peoples- Victor Schultze;
capable of preventing conception or impregnation; contraceptive devices and medications;
providing protective supervision; watching over or safeguarding; daycare that is educational and not just custodial; a guardian angel; tutelary gods;
avoiding or escaping from difficulty or danger especially enemy fire; pilots are taught to take evasive action;
overly protective; overprotective parents;
tending or having the power to preserve; timbers should be treated with a preservative substance;
shielding (or designed to shield) against harm or discomfort; the protecting blanket of snow; a protecting alibi;
(of tariff) protective of national interests by restricting imports;
providing or ensuring safety;
not affording protection;
feeling self-respect or pleasure in something by which you measure your self-worth; or being a reason for pride; proud parents; proud of his accomplishments; a proud moment; proud to serve his country; a proud name; proud princes;
having or showing feelings of unwarranted importance out of overbearing pride; an arrogant official; arrogant claims; chesty as a peacock;
pleased and proud; beaming parents;
feeling self-importance; too big for his britches; had a swelled head; he was swelled with pride;
(used colloquially) overly conceited or arrogant; a snotty little scion of a degenerate family-Laurent Le Sage; they're snobs--stuck-up and uppity and persnickety;
exhibiting self-importance; big talk;
having or showing self-esteem;
having or showing arrogant superiority to and disdain of those one views as unworthy; some economists are disdainful of their colleagues in other social disciplines; haughty aristocrats; his lordly manners were offensive; walked with a prideful swagger; very sniffy about breaches of etiquette; his mother eyed my clothes with a supercilious air; a more swaggering mood than usual- W.L.Shirer;
characteristic of false pride; having an exaggerated sense of self-importance; a conceited fool; an attitude of self-conceited arrogance; an egotistical disregard of others; so swollen by victory that he was unfit for normal duty; growing ever more swollen-headed and arbitrary; vain about her clothes;
proud of your house or its furnishings or upkeep;
excessively proud;
feeling pleasurable satisfaction over something by which you measures your self-worth; proud of their child;
proud or arrogant because of your wealth (especially in the absence of other distinction);
trying to maintain dignity and self respect despite shabbiness;
marked by meekness or modesty; not arrogant or prideful; a humble apology; essentially humble...and self-effacing, he achieved the highest formal honors and distinctions- B.K.Malinowski;
subdued or brought low in condition or status; brought low; a broken man; his broken spirit;
humble in spirit or manner; suggesting retiring mildness or even cowed submissiveness; meek and self-effacing;
established beyond doubt; a proven liar; a Soviet leader of proven shrewdness;
shown to be valid beyond a reasonable doubt; the established facts in the case;
supported by evidence; their evidenced friendliness to the US;
tested and proved useful or correct; a tested method;
proved to be true; a verified claim;
not proved; unproved allegations; unproved assumptions;
in the process of being tested or tried;
lacking proof or substantiation;
providing carefully for the future; wild squirrels are provident; a provident father plans for his children's education;
mindful of the future in spending money; careful with money;
planning prudently for the future; large goals that required farsighted policies; took a long view of the geopolitical issues;
having provided for the future;
thoughtful of the future; careful forethoughtful planning;
not provident; not providing for the future;
lacking foresight or scope; a short view of the problem; shortsighted policies; shortsighted critics derided the plan; myopic thinking;
careless of the future;
lacking forethought;
serving or tending to provoke, excite, or stimulate; stimulating discussion or exciting controversy; a provocative remark; a provocative smile; provocative Irish tunes which...compel the hearers to dance- Anthony Trollope;
causing or tending to cause anger or resentment; a provoking delay at the airport;
disturbingly provocative; an intriguing smile;
capable of producing violent emotion or arousing controversy; the highly charged issue of abortion;
arousing to action or rebellion;
rousing to activity or heightened action as by spurring or goading; tossed a rousing political comment into the conversation;
not provocative;
capable of allaying hostility;
not inflammatory;
careful and sensible; marked by sound judgment; a prudent manager; prudent rulers; prudent hesitation; more prudent to hide than to fight;
heedful of potential consequences; circumspect actions; physicians are now more circumspect about recommending its use; a discreet investor;
marked by the exercise of good judgment or common sense in practical matters; judicious use of one's money; a wise decision;
careful in regard to your own interests; the prudent use and development of resources; wild squirrels are provident;
arising from or characterized by prudence especially in business matters; he abstained partly for prudential reasons;
not prudent or wise; very imprudent of her mother to encourage her in such silly romantic ideas; would be imprudent for a noneconomist to talk about the details of economic policy- A.M.Schlesinger;
not given careful consideration; ill-considered actions often result in disaster; an ill-judged attempt;
lacking or showing lack of judgment or discretion; unwise; an injudicious measure; the result of an injudicious decision;
imprudently incurring risk; do something rash that he will forever repent- George Meredith;
acting or arriving or performed exactly at the time appointed; she expected guests to be punctual at meals; he is not a particularly punctual person; punctual payment;
according to schedule or without delay; on time; the train is prompt;
