accompanying; all rights carry with them corresponding responsibilities;
closely related or associated; a city in which communism and democracy had to live side by side;
lacking a logical or causal relation;
mistakenly related;
statistically unrelated;
not varying together;
having a bearing on or connection with the subject at issue; the scientist corresponds with colleagues in order to learn about matters relevant to her own research;
capable of being applied; having relevance; gave applicable examples to support her argument;
relevant and appropriate; he asks questions that are germane and central to the issue;
having precise or logical relevance to the matter at hand; a list of articles pertinent to the discussion; remarks that were to the point;
having no bearing on or connection with the subject at issue; an irrelevant comment; irrelevant allegations;
of superficial relevance if any; a digressive allusion to the day of the week; a tangential remark;
not pertinent to the matter under consideration; an issue extraneous to the debate; the price was immaterial; mentioned several impertinent facts before finally coming to the point;
not capable of being applied; rules inapplicable to day students;
of no legal significance (as having been previously decided);
bearing in mind; attentive to; ever mindful of her health; mindful of his responsibilities; mindful of these criticisms, I shall attempt to justify my action;
cautiously attentive; careful of her feelings; heedful of his father's advice;
serving to bring to mind; cannot forbear to close on this redolent literary note- Wilder Hobson; a campaign redolent of machine politics;
not mindful or attentive; while thus unmindful of his steps he stumbled- G.B.Shaw;
suffering from a partial loss of memory;
capable of being replaced;
capable of replacing or changing places with something else; permitting mutual substitution without loss of function or suitability; interchangeable electric outletsinterchangeable parts;
impossible to replace; irreplaceable antiques;
(used especially of art) depicting objects, figures,or scenes as seen; representational art; representational images;
depicted in a recognizable manner;
of visual imagery of almost photographic accuracy;
consisting of or forming human or animal figures; a figural design; the figurative art of the humanistic tradition- Herbert Read;
characterized by or of the nature of or using mimesis; a mimetic dance; the mimetic presentation of images;
representing what is real; not abstract or ideal; realistic portraiture; a realistic novel; in naturalistic colors; the school of naturalistic writers;
of or relating to a style of art in which objects do not resemble those known in physical nature;
not representing or imitating external reality or the objects of nature; a large abstract painting;
represented in simplified or symbolic form;
characterized by simple geometric forms in design and decoration; a buffalo hide painted with red and black geometric designs;
adhering to fixed types or methods; highly restrained and formal; the more hieratic sculptures leave the viewer curiously unmoved;
characteristic of the earliest phase of geometric art especially in Greece;
characterized by stylized but recognizable subject matter;
standing for something else; the bald eagle is representative of the United States;
used in or characteristic of or containing allegory; allegorical stories; an allegorical painting of Victory leading an army;
serving as a visible symbol for something abstract; a crown is emblematic of royalty; the spinning wheel was as symbolic of colonical Massachusetts as the codfish;
not standing for something else;
having a good reputation; a reputable business; a reputable scientist; a reputable wine;
having an illustrious reputation; respected; our esteemed leader; a prestigious author;
deserving of esteem and respect; all respectable companies give guarantees; ruined the family's good name;
worthy of respect or honor; born of a redoubtable family;
receiving deferential regard; a respected family;
acceptable for a long time; time-honored customs;
lacking respectability in character or behavior or appearance;
tending to bring discredit or disrepute; blameworthy; his marks were not at all discreditable;
being unjustly brought into disrepute; a discredited politician; her damaged reputation;
known widely and usually unfavorably; a notorious gangster; the tenderloin district was notorious for vice; the infamous Benedict Arnold;
of questionable taste or morality; a louche nightclub; a louche painting;
morally degraded; a seedy district; the seamy side of life; sleazy characters hanging around casinos; sleazy storefronts with...dirt on the walls- Seattle Weekly; the sordid details of his orgies stank under his very nostrils- James Joyce; the squalid atmosphere of intrigue and betrayal;
ready or willing to receive favorably; receptive to the proposals;
accepting willingly; acceptive of every new idea; an acceptant type of mind;
characterized by or allowing admission; an Elizabethan tragedy admissive of comic scenes;
capable of mentally absorbing ; assimilative processes, assimilative capacity of the human mind;
having an open mind; hospitable to new ideas; open to suggestions;
not receptive;
not having an open mind; a closed mind unreceptive to new ideas;
capable of being reconciled; her way of thinking is reconcilable with mine;
capable of being made harmonious or consistent;
capable of being settled or resolved; all disputed points are potentially resolvable; a resolvable quarrel;
impossible to reconcile; irreconcilable differences;
impossible to bring into friendly accord; hostile factions;
not capable of being made consistent or harmonious; inconsistent accounts;
marked by self-restraint and reticence; was habitually reserved in speech, withholding her opinion-Victoria Sackville-West;
remote in manner; stood apart with aloof dignity; a distant smile; he was upstage with strangers;
showing modest reserve; she was diffident when offering a comment on the professor's lecture;
tending to reserve or introspection; a quiet indrawn man;
not cautious or reticent; unreserved behavior;
set aside for the use of a particular person or party;
reserved in advance;
subject to being reserved or booked; all seats bookable in advance;
not reserved;
not accepting reservations;
not reserved in advance;
capable of being resisted or withstood or frustrated; a resistible attack; such resistible temptations;
impossible to resist; overpowering; irresistible (or resistless) impulses; what happens when an irresistible force meets an immovable object?;
so strong as to be irresistible; an overpowering need for solitude; the temptation to despair may become overwhelming; an overwhelming majority;
firm in purpose or belief; characterized by firmness and determination; stood resolute against the enemy; faced with a resolute opposition; a resolute and unshakeable faith;
fixed in your purpose; bent on going to the theater; dead set against intervening; out to win every event;
characterized by great determination; a struggle against a determined enemy;
desperately determined; do-or-die revolutionaries; a do-or-die conflict;
marked by firm determination or resolution; not shakable; firm convictions; a firm mouth; steadfast resolve; a man of unbendable perseverence; unwavering loyalty;
characterized by firm and unwavering conviction; a foursquare refusal to yield;
recklessly determined; hell-bent on winning;
determined; she was firmly resolved to be a doctor; single-minded in his determination to stop smoking;
resolute in the face of pain or danger or adversity; spartan courage;
dependable; the stalwart citizens at Lexington; a stalwart supporter of the UN; stout hearts;
unshaken in purpose; wholly undismayed by the commercial failure of the three movies he had made;
not deterred; pursued his own path...undeterred by lack of popular appreciation and understanding- Osbert Sitwell;
uncertain how to act or proceed; the committee was timid and mediocre and irresolute;
lacking in resolution; the accident left others discouraged about going there;
lacking firmness of will or character or purpose; infirm of purpose; give me the daggers- Shakespeare;
disposed to psychological variability; his rather unstable religious convictions;
uncertain in purpose or action;
lacking will power or resolution; the role of the dissenter is not for the weak-kneed;
characterized by socially or conventionally acceptable morals; a respectable woman;
socially or conventionally correct; refined or virtuous; from a decent family; a nice girl;
fit to be seen; presentable clothes;
