a nuclear reaction occurring with absorption of energy;
a chemical reaction accompanied by the absorption of heat;
inability to control the flow of urine and involuntary urination;
a geological change in the mineral content of rock after the rock has formed;
loss of hair; the result of removing hair;
growing a crystal layer of one mineral on the crystal base of another mineral in such a manner that its crystalline orientation is the same as that of the substrate;
(geology) the mechanical process of wearing or grinding something down (as by particles washing over it);
a gradual decline of something; after the accounting scandal there was an erosion of confidence in the auditors;
the process of producing red blood cells by the stem cells in the bone marrow;
(ecology) the process by which a plant or animal becomes established in a new habitat;
assimilation into European culture;
excessive nutrients in a lake or other body of water, usually caused by runoff of nutrients (animal waste, fertilizers, sewage) from the land, which causes a dense growth of plant life; the decomposition of the plants depletes the supply of oxygen, leading to the death of animal life; he argued that the controlling factor in eutrophication is not nitrate but phosphate;
(biology) the sequence of events involved in the evolutionary development of a species or taxonomic group of organisms;
(computer science) the process of carrying out an instruction by a computer;
a nuclear reaction accompanied by the evolution of energy;
a chemical reaction accompanied by the evolution of heat;
the process of coughing up and spitting out;
a decrease that follows an exponential function;
(genetics) the process of expressing a gene;
the reduction of the intensity of radiation as a consequence of absorption and radiation;
the process of obtaining something from a mixture or compound by chemical or physical or mechanical means;
the process of exuding or passing out of a vessel into surrounding tissues; said of blood or lymph or urine;
the production of a litter of pigs;
a metabolic process that breaks down ingested fats into fatty acids and glycerol and then into simpler compounds that can be used by cells of the body;
the process in which part of the output of a system is returned to its input in order to regulate its further output;
the process of becoming feminized; the development of female characteristics (loss of facial hair or breast enlargement) in a male because of hormonal disorders or castration;
(medicine) the formation of morbific matter in an abscess or a vesicle and the discharge of pus;
a normal ongoing process that dissolves fibrin and results in the removal of small blood clots; drugs causing fibrinolysis have been utilized therapeutically;
the emission of electrons that are stripped from parent atoms by a high electric field;
flow into something (as a container);
the process whereby fluids pass through a filter or a filtering medium;
the process of combustion of inflammable materials producing heat and light and (often) smoke; fire was one of our ancestors' first discoveries;
a nuclear reaction in which a massive nucleus splits into smaller nuclei with the simultaneous release of energy;
reproduction of some unicellular organisms by division of the cell into two more or less equal parts;
reproduction of some multicellular organisms by division, as in the case of some starfish;
an operation that is completed in a specified number of regularly timed execution cycles;
a sudden burst of flame;
an arithmetic operation performed on floating-point numbers; this computer can perform a million flops per second;
the process of flocculating; forming woolly cloudlike aggregations;
any uninterrupted stream or discharge;
gradual internal motion or deformation of a solid body (as by heat); rock fracture and rock flowage are different types of geological deformation;
the confinement of an infection to a limited area;
a geological process that causes a bend in a stratum of rock;
(geology) the arrangement of leaflike layers in a rock;
(botany) the process of forming leaves;
the execution of a program that preempts the use of the processing system;
natural process that causes something to form; the formation of gas in the intestine; the formation of crystals; the formation of pseudopods;
the process of fossilizing a plant or animal that existed in some earlier age; the process of being turned to stone;
fractionation of a liquid by distillation;
a process that uses heat to separate a substance into its components;
(computer science) the condition of a file that is broken up and stored in many different locations on a magnetic disk; fragmentation slows system performance because it takes extra time to locate and assemble the parts of the fragmented file;
the withdrawal of heat to change something from a liquid to a solid;
a method of drying food or blood plasma or pharmaceuticals or tissue without destroying their physical structure; material is frozen and then warmed in a vacuum so that the ice sublimes;
the formation of frost or ice on a surface;
the bearing of fruit;
a nuclear reaction in which nuclei combine to form more massive nuclei with the simultaneous release of energy;
the merging of adjacent sounds or syllables or words;
the secretion of milk;
stimulation with a galvanic current;
the development and maturation of sex cells through meiosis;
the process of changing into gas; coal gas is produced by the gasification of coal;
the process of interacting with gas;
the process of breaking down proteins by the action of the gastric juice in the stomach;
the process in which a gastrula develops from a blastula by the inward migration of cells;
(geology) a natural process whereby geological features are modified;
the process whereby seeds or spores sprout and begin to grow;
the process of covering the earth with glaciers or masses of ice;
the next-to-last Pleistocene glaciation in the Alps and the deposits laid down at that time;
the next-to-last Pleistocene glaciation in northern Europe and the deposits laid down at that time;
the next-to-last Pleistocene glaciation in Britain and the deposits laid down at that time;
growth to a global or worldwide scale; the globalization of the communication industry;
an increase in the average temperature of the earth's atmosphere (especially a sustained increase that causes climatic changes);
the formation in animals of glycogen from glucose;
a metabolic process that breaks down carbohydrates and sugars through a series of reactions to either pyruvic acid or lactic acid and releases energy for the body in the form of ATP;
(electronics) the production of (semiconductor) crystals by slow crystallization from the molten state;
(biology) the process of an individual organism growing organically; a purely biological unfolding of events involved in an organism changing gradually from a simple to a more complex level; he proposed an indicator of osseous development in children;
a progression from simpler to more complex forms; the growth of culture;
female parthenogenesis in which the embryo contains only maternal chromosomes due to the failure of the sperm to fuse with the egg nucleus;
an industrial process for producing ammonia from nitrogen and hydrogen by combining them under high pressure in the presence of an iron catalyst;
the general form or mode of growth (especially of a plant or crystal); a shrub of spreading habit;
the process of becoming hard or solid by cooling or drying or crystallization; the hardening of concrete; he tested the set of the glue;
the production of young from an egg;
the natural process by which the body repairs itself;
dissipation of heat;
the process of becoming warmer; a rising temperature;
agglutination of red blood cells;
passage of stools containing blood (as from diverticulosis or colon cancer or peptic ulcer);
the formation of blood cells in the living body (especially in the bone marrow);
incomplete or partial metamorphosis in insects;
development of insects with incomplete metamorphosis in which no pupal stage precedes maturity;
lysis of erythrocytes with the release of hemoglobin;
the biological process whereby genetic factors are transmitted from one generation to the next;
the development of both microspores and megaspores;
complete metamorphosis in insects;
the development of a single kind of asexual spores;
a process in which human beings are involved;
the process of the formation of humus from plant remains;
the process of combining with water; usually reversible;
the process whereby hydrocarbon molecules of petroleum are broken down into kerosene and gasolene by the addition of hydrogen under high pressure in the presence of a catalyst;
a chemical process that adds hydrogen atoms to an unsaturated oil; food producers use hydrogenation to keep fat from becoming rancid;
