large genus of cacti characterized chiefly by nipple-shaped protuberances or tubercles on their surface;
any cactus of the genus Mammillaria;
a low tuberculate cactus with white feathery spines; northeastern Mexico;
genus of strongly ribbed globose or spheroid cacti of tropical South and Central America and the Caribbean;
small genus of arborescent cacti of Mexico and Central America;
arborescent cactus of western Mexico bearing a small oblong edible berrylike fruit;
low-growing cacti of the Great Plains of North America;
small clustering cactus of southwestern United States; a threatened species;
a genus of the cactus family with scarlet flowers;
any of several cacti of the genus Nopalea resembling prickly pears;
large genus of cactuses native to America: prickly pears;
cacti having spiny flat joints and oval fruit that is edible in some species; often used as food for stock;
arborescent cacti having very spiny cylindrical stem segments; southwestern United States and Mexico;
cactus having yellow flowers and purple fruits;
tropical American prickly pear of Jamaica;
genus of tropical American shrubby trees and woody climbers having slender branches with broad flat leaves and large panicles of flowers;
West Indian woody climber with spiny stems and numerous fragrant white flowers in panicles followed by small yellow to orange fruits;
large genus of epiphytic or lithophytic unarmed cacti with usually segmented stems and pendulous branches; flowers are small followed by berrylike fruits;
a plant of the genus Rhipsalis;
South American epiphytic or lithophytic cacti;
epiphytic cactus of Brazilian ancestry widely cultivated as a houseplant having jointed flat segments and usually rose-purple flowers that bloom in winter;
mostly epiphytic climbing cacti that bloom at night;
any of several night-blooming cacti of the genus Selenicereus;
tropical American climbing cactus having triangular branches; often cultivated for its large showy night-blooming flowers followed by yellow red-streaked fruits;
small genus of Brazilian cacti having flat fleshy usually branched joints and showy red or pink flowers followed by red fleshy fruits;
South American jointed cactus with usually red flowers; often cultivated as a houseplant; sometimes classified as genus Schlumbergera;
chiefly tropical herbaceous plants (including shrubs and trees) with racemose flowers: genera Phytolacca, Agdestis, Ercilla, Rivina, Trichostigma;
type genus of Phytolaccaceae: pokeweed;
perennial of the genus Phytolacca;
pokeweed of southeastern Asia and China;
tall coarse perennial American herb having small white flowers followed by blackish-red berries on long drooping racemes; young fleshy stems are edible; berries and root are poisonous;
fast-growing herbaceous evergreen tree of South America having a broad trunk with high water content and dark green oval leaves;
a genus with one species that is a rapidly growing climbing vine with tuberous roots; grown in hot climates;
a genus of evergreen climbers;
small genus of erect perennial shrubby herbs; tropical and subtropical America;
bushy houseplant having white to pale pink flowers followed by racemes of scarlet berries; tropical Americas;
a genus of erect or climbing shrubs found in tropical South America;
family of usually succulent herbs; cosmopolitan in distribution especially in Americas;
a plant of the family Portulacaceae having fleshy succulent obovate leaves often grown as a potherb or salad herb; a weed in some areas;
genus of mainly tropical fleshy or trailing herbs;
a plant of the genus Portulaca having pink or red or purple or white ephemeral flowers;
widely cultivated in many varieties for its fleshy moss-like foliage and profusion of brightly colored flowers;
weedy trailing mat-forming herb with bright yellow flowers cultivated for its edible mildly acid leaves eaten raw or cooked especially in Indian and Greek and Middle Eastern cuisine; cosmopolitan;
large genus of low-growing herbs; widespread throughout tropical and warm temperate regions having usually basal leaves and panicles of purplish ephemeral flowers;
a plant of the genus Calandrinia;
succulent carpet-forming plant having small brilliant reddish-pink flowers; southwestern United States;
genus of mainly North American succulent herbs with white or pink flowers usually in terminal racemes;
similar to Claytonia virginica but having usually pink flowers; eastern North America;
small slender plant having one pair of succulent leaves at the middle of the stem and a loose raceme of white or pink or rose bowl-shaped flowers and an edible corm;
small cormous perennial grown for its low rosette of succulent foliage and racemes of pink-tinged white flowers; eastern North America;
genus of western North American low-growing herbs having linear woolly leaves and large pink flowers;
evergreen perennial having a dense basal rosette of long spatula-shaped leaves and panicles of pink or white-and-red-striped or pink-purple flowers; found on cliffs and in rock crevices in mountains of southwestern Oregon and northern California;
showy succulent ground-hugging plant of Rocky Mountains regions having deep to pale pink flowers and fleshy farinaceous roots; the Montana state flower;
small genus of densely tufted annual herbs; north temperate regions and South America and tropical Africa and Asia;
a plant of the genus Montia having edible pleasant-tasting leaves;
succulent plant with mostly basal leaves; stem bears 1 pair of broadly ovate or heart-shaped leaves and a loose raceme of 3-10 white flowers; western North America;
small Indian lettuce of northern regions;
a floating or creeping Indian lettuce having terminal racemes of pale rose flowers; wet areas at high elevations of western North America;
succulent herb sometimes grown as a salad or pot herb; grows on dunes and waste ground of Pacific coast of North America;
small genus of usually perennial herbs having deep woody taproots and flower heads of umbels or cymes;
pink clusters of densely packed flowers on prostrate stems resemble upturned pads of cats' feet; grow in coniferous forests of western North America;
genus of mainly American more-or-less succulent herbs;
plant with fleshy roots and erect stems with narrow succulent leaves and one reddish-orange flower in each upper leaf axil; southwestern United States; Indians once cooked the fleshy roots;
similar to Talinum aurantiacum but with narrower leaves and yellow-orange flowers; southwestern United States;
low plant with crowded narrow succulent leaves and fairly large deep pink axillary flowers that seem to sit on the ground; southwestern United States;
pink-flowered perennial of rocky regions of western United States;
erect plant with tuberous roots and terminal panicles of red to yellow flowers; southwestern North America to Central America; widely introduced elsewhere;
low cushion-forming plant with rose to crimson-magenta flowers and leaf midribs that persist as spines when the leaves die; southwestern United States;
an order of dicotyledonous plants;
a dilleniid dicot family of the order Rhoeadales that includes: genera Capparis, Cleome, Crateva, and Polanisia;
tropical or subtropical evergreen shrubs or small trees;
any of numerous plants of the genus Capparis;
small Australian tree bearing edible fruit resembling the pomegranate;
shrub of southern Florida to West Indies;
shrub or small tree of southern Florida to Central and South America;
small Australian tree bearing edible dark purple fruit;
prostrate spiny shrub of the Mediterranean region cultivated for its greenish flower buds which are pickled;
tropical and subtropical annual or perennial herbs or low shrubs;
any of various often strong-smelling plants of the genus Cleome having showy spider-shaped flowers;
native to South America but naturalized in warm parts of United States; grown for its long-lasting spider-shaped white to pink-purple flowers;
plant of western North America having trifoliate leaves and white or pink spider-shaped flowers; sometimes used as an ornamental;
tropical genus of small trees or shrubs;
widely distributed herbs having palmate leaves and creamy white to or pink to magenta flowers with many stamens of unequal length;
strong-scented herb common in southern United States covered with intermixed gland and hairs;
a large family of plants with four-petaled flowers; includes mustards, cabbages, broccoli, turnips, cresses, and their many relatives;
any of various plants of the family Cruciferae;
any of various plants of the family Cruciferae with edible leaves that have a pungent taste;
any of several water-loving cresses;
Old World genus of the family Cruciferae;
any Old World herb of the genus Aethionema; native of sunny limestone habitats;
a genus of herbs of the family Cruciferae; have broad leaves and white flowers and long siliques;
European herb that smells like garlic;
a genus of the family Cruciferae;
any garden plant of the genus Alyssum having clusters of small yellow or white flowers;
one species: rose of Jericho; resurrection plant;
small grey Asiatic desert plant bearing minute white flowers that rolls up when dry and expands when moist;
a genus of the mustard family having white or yellow or purplish flowers; closely related to genus Arabis;
a small invasive self-pollinating weed with small white flowers; much studied by plant geneticists; the first higher plant whose complete genome sequence was described;
a small noninvasive cross-pollinating plant with white flowers; closely related to Arabidopsis thaliana;
annual to perennial woody herbs of temperate North America, Europe and Asia: rockcress;
