weedy perennial of north temperate regions having woolly foliage and dirty white flowers in a leafy spike;
large genus of coarse gummy herbs of western North and Central America;
any of various western American plants of the genus Grindelia having resinous leaves and stems formerly used medicinally; often poisonous to livestock;
perennial gumweed of California and Baja California;
perennial gumweed of western and central North America;
sticky perennial herbs and subshrubs of western North America and warm South America;
any of several plants of the genus Gutierrezia having tiny flower heads that resemble the heads of matches;
similar to Gutierrezia sarothrae but with flower heads having fewer rays and disk flowers;
low-growing sticky subshrub of southwestern United States having narrow linear leaves on many slender branches and hundreds of tiny yellow flower heads;
annual of southwestern United States having rigid woody branches with sticky foliage and yellow flowers;
genus of Old World tropical herbs: velvet plants;
Javanese foliage plant grown for their handsome velvety leaves with violet-purple hairs;
genus of New Zealand mat-forming herbs or subshrubs: vegetable sheep;
cushion-forming New Zealand herb having leaves densely covered with tawny hairs;
genus of North and South American perennial herbs or shrubs with yellow flowers; in some classifications include species placed in other genera especially Hazardia;
a plant of the genus Haplopappus;
annual of southern United States and Mexico having bristly leaves and pale yellow flowers;
slender perennial of western North America having weakly bristly leaves and yellow flower heads;
small genus of shrubs and subshrubs of western United States having flowers that change color as they mature;
western American shrubs having white felted foliage and yellow flowers that become red-purple;
genus of American herbs with flowers having yellow rays: sneezeweeds;
any of various plants of the genus Helenium characteristically causing sneezing;
North American perennial with bright yellow late summer flowers;
stout perennial herb of western United States having flower heads with drooping orange-yellow rays; causes spewing sickness in sheep;
a sneezeweed of southwestern United States especially southern California;
genus of tall erect or branched American annual or perennial herbs with showy flowers: sunflowers;
any plant of the genus Helianthus having large flower heads with dark disk florets and showy yellow rays;
sunflower of eastern North America having narrow leaves and found in bogs;
annual sunflower grown for silage and for its seeds which are a source of oil; common throughout United States and much of North America;
very tall American perennial of central and the eastern United States to Canada having edible tuberous roots;
tall rough-leaved perennial with a few large flower heads; central United States;
tall perennial of central United States to Canada having golden-yellow flowers;
similar to the common sunflower with slender usually branching stems common in central United States;
tall perennial with hairy stems and leaves; widely cultivated for its large irregular edible tubers;
edible tuber of the Jerusalem artichoke;
large genus of mostly African and Australian herbs and shrubs: everlasting flowers; in some classifications includes genus Ozothamnus;
Australian plant naturalized in Spain having flowers of lemon yellow to deep gold; the frequent choice of those who love dried flowers;
oxeye;
any North American shrubby perennial herb of the genus Heliopsis having large yellow daisylike flowers;
genus of South African and Australian herbs or shrubs grown as everlastings; the various Helipterum species are currently in process of being assigned to other genera especially genera Pteropogon and Hyalosperma;
any of various plants of the genus Helipterum;
genus of yellow-flowered North American herbs;
hairy perennial with yellow flower heads in branched clusters; found almost everywhere in dry places from Canada to west central and western United States; sometimes placed in genus Chrysopsis;
large genus of perennial hairy herbs of Europe to western Asia to northwestern Africa and North America; few are ornamental; often considered congeneric with Pilosella;
any of numerous often hairy plants of the genus Hieracium having yellow or orange flowers that resemble the dandelion;
European hawkweed introduced into northeastern United States; locally troublesome weeds;
a hawkweed with a rosette of purple-veined basal leaves; Canada to northern Georgia and Kentucky;
small genus of low perennial herbs of montane Europe; in some classifications included in genus Tussilago;
rhizomatous herb with purple-red flowers suitable for groundcover; sometimes placed in genus Tussilago;
small genus of erect balsam-scented herbs; Pacific coast of the northwestern United States;
low tufted plant having hairy stems each topped by a flower head with short narrow yellow rays; northwestern United States;
similar to but smaller than alpine hulsea;
genus of herbs of temperate Australia including some from genus Helipterum;
widely distributed genus of herbs with milky juice; includes some cosmopolitan weeds;
European weed widely naturalized in North America having yellow flower heads and leaves resembling a cat's ears;
genus of Old World herbs or subshrubs: elecampane;
any plant of the genus Inula;
tall coarse Eurasian herb having daisylike yellow flowers with narrow petals whose rhizomatous roots are used medicinally;
small genus of American herbs or shrubs; in some classifications placed in a separate family Ambrosiaceae;
any of various coarse shrubby plants of the genus Iva with small greenish flowers; common in moist areas (as coastal salt marshes) of eastern and central North America;
tall annual marsh elder common in moist rich soil in central North America that can cause contact dermatitis; produces much pollen that is a major cause of hay fever;
small herbs closely related to chicory: dwarf dandelions;
any small branched yellow-flowered North American herb of the genus Krigia;
small yellow-flowered herb resembling dandelions of central and southeastern United States;
an herb with milky juice: lettuce; prickly lettuce;
any of various plants of the genus Lactuca;
annual or perennial garden plant having succulent leaves used in salads; widely grown;
lettuce with long dark-green spoon-shaped leaves;
distinguished by leaves arranged in a dense rosette that develop into a compact ball;
distinguished by leaves having curled or incised leaves forming a loose rosette that does not develop into a compact head;
lettuce valued especially for its edible stems;
European annual wild lettuce having prickly stems; a troublesome weed in parts of United States;
small genus of herbs of Australia and South America having small solitary white or purple flowers similar to true daisies of genus Bellis;
small genus of herbs of Pacific coast of North and South America;
small slender woolly annual with very narrow opposite leaves and branches bearing solitary golden-yellow flower heads; southwestern Oregon to Baja California and Arizona; often cultivated;
genus of western United States annuals with showy yellow or white flowers;
California annual having flower heads with yellow rays tipped with white;
hawkbit;
any of various common wildflowers of the genus Leontodon; of temperate Eurasia to Mediterranean regions;
fall-blooming European herb with a yellow flower; naturalized in the United States;
edelweiss;
alpine perennial plant native to Europe having leaves covered with whitish down and small flower heads held in stars of glistening whitish bracts;
comprises plants often included in the genus Chrysanthemum;
tall leafy-stemmed Eurasian perennial with white flowers; widely naturalized; often placed in genus Chrysanthemum;
similar to oxeye daisy;
hybrid garden flower derived from Chrysanthemum maximum and Chrysanthemum lacustre having large white flower heads resembling oxeye daisies; often placed in the genus Chrysanthemum;
perennial of Portugal similar to the oxeye daisy;
New Zealand edelweiss;
perennial herb closely resembling European edelweiss; New Zealand;
genus of perennial North American herbs with aromatic usually cormous roots;
any of various North American plants of the genus Liatris having racemes or panicles of small discoid flower heads;
herb with many stems bearing narrow slender wands of crowded rose-lavender flowers; central United States and Canada to Texas and northern Mexico;
perennial of southeastern and central United States having very dense spikes of purple flowers; often cultivated for cut flowers;
genus of Old World herbs resembling groundsel: leopard plants;
any of various plants of temperate Eurasia; grown for their yellow flowers and handsome foliage;
one species: Texas star;
Texas annual with coarsely pinnatifid leaves; cultivated for its showy radiate yellow flower heads;
one species: yellow ageratum;
shrub of southwestern Mediterranean region having yellow daisylike flowers;
wildflowers of western North America;
