any of several rock-loving cresses of the genus Arabis;
North American rock cress having very long curved pods;
European cress having stiff erect stems; sometimes placed in genus Turritis;
or genus Arabis: erect cress widely distributed throughout Europe;
horseradish;
coarse Eurasian plant cultivated for its thick white pungent root;
the root of the horseradish plant; it is grated or ground and used for seasoning;
biennial or perennial herbs of north temperate regions: winter cress;
any plant of the genus Barbarea: yellow-flowered Eurasian cresses; widely cultivated for winter salad;
of southwestern Europe; cultivated in Florida;
noxious cress with yellow flowers; sometimes placed in genus Sisymbrium;
hoary alyssum;
tall European annual with downy grey-green foliage and dense heads of small white flowers followed by hairy pods; naturalized in North America; sometimes a troublesome weed;
genus of Eurasian herbs and small shrubs: buckler mustard;
plant of southeastern Europe having yellow flowers like those of mustard and pods with open valves resembling bucklers;
mustards: cabbages; cauliflowers; turnips; etc.;
wild original of cultivated cabbages; common in western coastal Europe;
any of various cultivars of the genus Brassica oleracea grown for their edible leaves or flowers;
any of various cultivated cabbage plants having a short thick stalk and large compact head of edible usually green leaves;
cabbage plant with a compact head of crinkled leaves;
cabbage plant with a compact head of reddish purple leaves;
plant grown for its stout stalks of edible small green heads resembling diminutive cabbages;
a plant having a large edible head of crowded white flower buds;
plant with dense clusters of tight green flower buds;
a hardy cabbage with coarse curly leaves that do not form a head;
variety of kale having smooth leaves;
plant cultivated for its enlarged fleshy turnip-shaped edible stem;
any of several widely cultivated plants having edible roots;
widely cultivated plant having a large fleshy edible white or yellow root;
a cruciferous plant with a thick bulbous edible yellow root;
plant grown for its pungent edible leafy shoots;
any of several cruciferous plants of the genus Brassica;
oil obtained from mustard seeds and used in making soap;
Asiatic mustard used as a potherb;
plant with an elongated head of broad stalked leaves resembling celery; used as a vegetable in east Asia;
Asiatic plant grown for its cluster of edible white stalks with dark green leaves;
Asiatic plant cultivated for its swollen root crown and edible foliage;
widespread Eurasian annual plant cultivated for its pungent seeds; a principal source of table mustard;
Eurasian plant cultivated for its seed and as a forage crop;
seed of rape plants; source of an edible oil;
edible light yellow to brown oil from rapeseed used also as a lubricant or illuminant;
small genus of succulent annual herbs found on sandy shores of North America and Europe;
salt-tolerant seashore annual grown for its fragrant rose or violet flowers and fleshy grey-green foliage;
annual and biennial herbs of Mediterranean to central Asia;
annual European false flax having small white flowers; cultivated since Neolithic times as a source of fiber and for its oil-rich seeds; widely naturalized in North America;
shepherd's purse;
white-flowered annual European herb bearing triangular notched pods; nearly cosmopolitan as an introduced weed;
bittercress, bitter cress;
usually included in genus Cardamine; in some classifications considered a separate genus;
any of various herbs of the genus Cardamine, having usually pinnate leaves and racemes of white, pink or purple flowers; cosmopolitan except Antarctic;
a bitter cress of Europe and America;
European bittercress having a knotted white rootstock;
North American herb with pungent scaly or toothed roots;
mat-forming perennial found in cold springs of the eastern United States;
small white-flowered cress common in wet places in eastern North America;
small perennial herb of cooler regions of North America with racemose purple flowers;
Old World perennial plants grown for their showy flowers;
perennial of southern Europe having clusters of fragrant flowers of all colors especially yellow and orange; often naturalized on old walls or cliffs; sometimes placed in genus Erysimum;
any of several western American plants of the genus Cheiranthus having large yellow flowers;
a genus of the family Cruciferae;
a widely distributed Arctic cress reputed to have value in treatment or prevention of scurvy; a concentrated source of vitamin C;
annual or perennial herbs with large leaves that resemble the leaves of cabbages;
perennial of coastal sands and shingles of northern Europe and Baltic and Black Seas having racemes of small white flowers and large fleshy blue-green leaves often used as potherbs;
includes annual or biennial herbs of America and Europe very similar to and often included among those of genera Sisymbrium or Hugueninia; not recognized in some classification systems;
North American herb with bitter-tasting pinnate leaves resembling those of tansy;
wall rocket;
yellow-flowered European plant that grows on old walls and in waste places; an adventive weed in North America;
from Mediterranean region; a naturalized weed throughout southern Europe;
large genus of low tufted herbs of temperate and Arctic regions;
any of numerous low-growing cushion-forming plants of the genus Draba having rosette-forming leaves and terminal racemes of small flowers with scapose or leafy stems; fruit is a dehiscent oblong or linear silique;
annual weed of Europe and North America having a rosette of basal leaves and tiny flowers followed by oblong seed capsules;
annual to perennial herbs of the Mediterranean region;
erect European annual often grown as a salad crop to be harvested when young and tender;
large genus of annual or perennial herbs some grown for their flowers and some for their attractive evergreen leaves; Old World and North America;
any of numerous plants of the genus Erysimum having fragrant yellow or orange or brownish flowers;
any of several North American plants of the genus Erysimum having large yellow flowers;
showy erect biennial or short-lived perennial cultivated for its terminal racemes of orange-yellow flowers; sometimes placed in genus Cheiranthus;
biennial or short-lived perennial prairie rocket having orange-yellow flowers; western North America to Minnesota and Kansas; sometimes placed in genus Cheiranthus;
slender yellow-flowered European mustard often troublesome as a weed; formerly used as an anthelmintic;
genus of South African flowering herbs and subshrubs;
any of various South African herbs and subshrubs cultivated for long showy racemes of bright blue flowers with white eyes;
biennial or perennial erect herbs having nocturnally fragrant flowers;
long cultivated herb having flowers whose scent is more pronounced in the evening; naturalized throughout Europe to Siberia and into North America;
one species: tansy-leaved rocket;
perennial stellate and hairy herb with small yellow flowers of mountains of southern Europe; sometimes placed in genus Sisymbrium;
(Old World herbs and subshrubs) candytuft;
any of various flowering plants of the genus Iberis cultivated for their showy clusters of white to red or purple flowers; native to Mediterranean region;
(Old World genus of annual to perennial herbs) woad;
any of several herbs of the genus Isatis;
European biennial formerly grown for the blue coloring matter yielded by its leaves;
cosmopolitan genus of annual and biennial and perennial herbs: cress;
annual herb used as salad green and garnish;
genus of low-growing hairy herbs: bladderpods;
any of several hairy North American herbs having yellow racemose flowers and inflated pods;
sweet alyssum;
perennial European plant having clusters of small fragrant usually white flowers; widely grown in gardens;
small genus of European herbs: honesty;
southeastern European plant cultivated for its fragrant purplish flowers and round flat papery silver-white seedpods that are used for indoor decoration;
genus of plants usually found in coastal habitats; Mediterranean to Afghanistan;
any of various ornamental flowering plants of the genus Malcolmia;
