below some quantity or limit; fifty dollars or under;
in or into a state of subordination or subjugation; we must keep our disappointment under;
down to defeat, death, or ruin; their competitors went under;
into unconsciousness; this will put the patient under;
through a range downward; children six and under will be admitted free;
with the hand swung below shoulder level; throwing a ball underarm;
beneath the surface of the earth; water flowing underground;
in or into hiding or secret operation; the organization was driven underground;
slyly and secretly; Mean revenge, committed underhand- John Donne; oldline aristocratic diplomats underhandedly undermined the attempt...to align Germany with the Western democracies- C.G.Bowers;
under or below an object or a surface; at a lower place or level; directly beneath; we could see the original painting underneath; a house with a good foundation underneath;
on the lower or downward side; on the underside of; a chest of drawers all scratched underneath;
to an undue degree; she was unduly pessimistic about her future;
in an uneventful manner; the space shuttle landed uneventfully;
in an ungrammatical manner; this child speaks ungrammatically;
in a grammatical manner; this child already speaks grammatically;
to an unimaginable extent;
without interruption; this pleasant state of affairs had continued peacefully and uninterruptedly for many years;
in an unnatural way; his other arm lay across his chest, unnaturally, as if placed there deliberately, for a purpose;
in a natural or normal manner; speak naturally and easily;
with precedent;
in an unprecedented manner;
without reservation; I can unreservedly recommend this restaurant!;
in an unrestrained manner;
without scruples; she unscrupulously uses her charm to make men do what she wants;
in an unstinting manner;
without swerving; in a direct and unswerving manner; the ship travelled unswervingly through the night;
in a constant and steadfast manner; an unswervingly loyal man;
in a untrue manner; he silenced the whisperings which connected her, untruly and unfairly, with his separation from his wife;
in an unwarrantable manner or to an unwarranted degree; in this painting, the relationship of the upper part of the body to the lower is uneasy and the right thigh seems unwarrantably stressed;
in an unworthy manner;
to or in the interior of a country or region; they live upcountry;
upward on a hill or incline; this street lay uphill;
against difficulties; she was talking uphill;
in or into the highest position; the blade turned uppermost;
in or into the most prominent position, as in the mind; say what comes uppermost;
in an upright position;
in an honorable manner; he acted honorably;
in a dishonorable manner; he acted dishonorably;
in an urbane manner; I had tea occasionally with the Duke,said Mr. Eggers urbanely;
in a useful manner; extra money could be usefully spent on this project;
in a useless manner; the furniture was sitting around uselessly;
in a loving and uxorious manner; he kept deferring uxoriously to Mary;
in a vacant manner; she was staring vacantly into the room;
in a vacuous manner;
with valor; in a valiant manner; he fought valiantly until the end;
with validity; in a valid manner; this may not validly be done;
in a vapid manner; a vapidly smiling salesman;
with variation; in a variable manner or to a variable degree; it will be variably cloudy;
in a vehement manner; he vehemently denied the accusations against him;
in a verbose manner; she explained her ideas verbosely;
in truth; certainly; I verily think so; trust in the Lord...and verily thou shalt be fed- Ps 37:3;
indirectly, as, by, or through a substitute; she enjoyed the wedding vicariously;
in a watchful manner;
in a vile manner; his vilely spelt and illiterate letters;
in a virulent manner; an old woman advanced a few paces to shake her fist virulently in my face;
lively, in music; play this section vivace!;
with vivacity; he describes his adventures vivaciously;
in a shapely and voluptuous manner; a voluptuously curved woman;
in an eagerly voracious manner; she reads voraciously;
like a voyeur; he sneaks voyeuristically around the swimming pool;
in a vulnerable manner;
in a waggish manner;
up to the waist; the water rose waist-high;
in a weak or pale or languid manner; she was smiling wanly;
in a wanton manner; the animals were killed wantonly for sport;
with riches;
as something very heavy; she moved weightily;
in a serious manner; the speech was weighty and it was weightily delivered;
extremely; a whacking good story;
with a wheeze; he talked wheezily;
without reserve; without reservation; he adopted wholeheartedly some of the policies that he had previously criticized;
in a wholesome manner; the papers we found shed some valuable light on this question, wholesomely contradicting all lies;
from what place, source, or cause;
where in the world;
extremely; they all were whopping drunk;
to or over a great extent or range; far; wandered wide through many lands; he traveled widely;
to a great degree; her work is widely known;
with or by a broad space; stand with legs wide apart; ran wide around left end;
far from the intended target; the arrow went wide of the mark; a bullet went astray and killed a bystander;
to the fullest extent possible; open your eyes wide; with the throttle wide open;
in a willful manner; she had willfully deceived me;
in a wishful manner; he wishfully indulged in dreams of fame;
in a wistful manner; his sister would have looked beautiful in that dress, he thought wistfully, just like an angel;
in a withering manner; guns fired witheringly at the railroad cars;
in a witty manner; he would wittily chime into our conversation;
in the manner of a wolf;
in a manner to cause worry;
in a worried manner; I wonder what to do,she said worriedly; he paused worriedly before calling the bank;
in a worthy manner; with worthiness;
in a worthless manner;
in a wrathful manner; he looked at her, not wrathfully now, but quizzically;
in a wretched manner; I can't remember who I am,I said, wretchedly;
not only so, but; I therein do rejoice, yea, and will rejoice;
in a youthful manner; he is still youthfully enthusiastic;
in a zealous manner; she worked zealously to raise funds for the literacy project;
with zest; she scrubbed the floors of the new apartment zestfully;
in a zigzag course or on a zigzag path; birds flew zigzag across the blue sky;
with ice cream on top or on the side; we served the apple pie a la mode;
in the space between decks, on a ship;
in the interval; dancing all the dances with little rest between;
