a couplet consisting of two rhymed lines of iambic pentameter and written in an elevated style;
a quatrain consisting of two heroic couplets written in an elevated style; the rhyme scheme is abab;
a verse form suited to the treatment of heroic or elevated themes; dactylic hexameter or iambic pentameter;
a satirical imitation of heroic verse;
a stanza with eight lines of iambic pentameter and a concluding Alexandrine with the rhyme pattern abab bcbc c; the Spenserian stanza was introduced by Edmund Spenser in The Faerie Queene;
one section of a lyric poem or choral ode in classical Greek drama;
the section of a choral ode answering a previous strophe in classical Greek drama; the second of two metrically corresponding sections in a poem;
a literary composition of poor quality that was written quickly to make money (to boil the pot);
writing of poor quality; characterized by affected choice of archaic words;
matter that has been dictated and transcribed; a dictated passage; he signed and mailed his dictation without bothering to read it;
a short line of text that a web site puts on your computer's hard drive when you access the web site;
a cookie that is stored temporarily and is destroyed when you close the link;
a cookie that is saved permanently on your hard drive;
the words of something written; there were more than a thousand words of text; they handed out the printed text of the mayor's speech; he wants to reconstruct the original text;
the main body of a written work (as distinct from illustrations or footnotes etc.); pictures made the text easier to understand;
electronic text that is stored and used in the form of a digital image;
electronic text that is stored as strings of characters and that can be displayed in a variety of formats;
typewritten matter especially a typewritten copy of a manuscript;
a surface area where something has been erased; another word had been written over the erasure;
the blank space that surrounds the text on a page; he jotted a note in the margin;
a blank area; write your name in the space provided;
the space left between the margin and the start of an indented line;
the order of words in a text;
(computer science) dump of the contents of the chief registers in the CPU; usually used for debugging;
(computer science) a copy of the contents of a computer storage device; sometimes used in debugging programs;
a clean copy of a corrected draft;
matter to be printed; exclusive of graphical materials;
written matter preceding the main text of a book;
written matter following the main text of a book;
any of the various versions in the development of a written work; a preliminary draft; the final draft of the constitution;
text that is in a form that computer can store or display on a computer screen;
(computer science) matter that is in a form that a computer can store or display it on a computer screen; he sent them soft copy of the report;
(computer science) matter that is held in a computer and is typed or printed on paper; he ran off a hard copy of the report;
a part of a published serial;
an installment of a printed work;
a self-contained part of a larger composition (written or musical); he always turns first to the business section; the history of this work is discussed in the next section;
an earlier section of a written text; for instructions refer to the above;
the section of a newspaper that reports on sports;
a separate section of a legal document (as a statute or contract or will);
a clause in a contract providing for arbitration of disputes arising under the contract;
a clause in an insurance policy that relieves the insurer of responsibility to pay the initial loss up to a stated amount;
a clause in an insurance policy that provides for double the face value of the policy in the case of accidental death;
a clause in a contract that provides for an increase or a decrease in wages or prices or benefits etc. depending on certain conditions (as a change in the cost of living index);
an inconspicuous clause in a document or bill that affects its meaning in a way that is not immediately apparent; when I demanded my money he showed me the joker in the contract;
a clause that used to be part of the contract with a professional athlete extending the contract for a year beyond its expiration; the reserve clause was used to bind players to a particular ball club;
a clause that is appended to a legislative bill;
the central message of a communication; the body of the message was short;
a major division of a long written composition; the book of Isaiah;
a subdivision of a written work; usually numbered and titled; he read a chapter every night before falling asleep;
a brief section of a literary or dramatic work that forms part of a connected series;
a section of an entertainment that is assigned to a specific performer or performance; they changed his spot on the program;
a short section or illustration (as between radio or tv programs or in a magazine) that is often used for advertising;
a folded section placed between the leaves of another publication;
the first section of a communication;
(rhetoric) the introductory section of an oration or discourse;
(rhetoric) the second section of an oration in which the facts are set forth;
the initial part of the introduction; the opening established the basic theme;
an attention-getting opening presented at the start of a television show;
word of greeting used to begin a letter;
a short introductory essay preceding the text of a book;
a preliminary introduction to a statute or constitution (usually explaining its purpose);
a preliminary discussion inserted at the beginning of a book or treatise;
the last section of a communication; in conclusion I want to say...;
a short passage added at the end of a literary work; the epilogue told what eventually happened to the main characters;
a short speech (often in verse) addressed directly to the audience by an actor at the end of a play;
(rhetoric) the concluding section of an oration; he summarized his main points in his peroration;
supplementary material that is collected and appended at the back of a book;
a part added to a book or play that continues and extends it;
textual matter that is added onto a publication; usually at the end;
a brief addendum at the end of a newspaper article;
one of several distinct subdivisions of a text intended to separate ideas; the beginning is usually marked by a new indented line;
a section of text; particularly a section of medium length;
a passage selected from a larger work; he presented excerpts from William James' philosophical writings;
a selection of passages from different authors that is compiled as an aid in learning a language;
an authoritative and often-quoted passage;
the passage that is being read; he lost his place on the page;
a passage full of ornate and flowery language;
a passage that connects a topic to one that follows;
a transition (in literary or theatrical works or films) to an earlier event or scene that interrupts the normal chronological development of the story;
a transition (in literary or theatrical works or films) to a later event or scene that interrupts the normal chronological development of the story;
a daily written record of (usually personal) experiences and observations;
a shared on-line journal where people can post diary entries about their personal experiences and hobbies; postings on a blog are usually in chronological order;
writing in capital letters;
writing done with a typewriter;
typing that leaves alternate lines blank;
typing that does not leave lines blank;
typing that leaves two lines blank between lines of typing;
typewriting in which the fingers are trained to hit particular keys; typist can read and type at the same time;
text handwritten in the style of printed matter;
something written by hand; she recognized his handwriting; his hand was illegible;
writing that resembles hieroglyphics (usually by being illegible);
writing formed in the sky by smoke released from an airplane;
beautiful handwriting;
poor handwriting;
cramped or illegible handwriting;
an illegible scrawl; his signature was just a squiggle but only he could make that squiggle;
your name written in your own handwriting;
a signature written by one person for another;
a person's own signature;
a second confirming signature endorsing a document already signed;
