a non-finite form of the verb; in English it is used adjectivally and to form compound tenses;
an English verb followed by one or more particles where the combination behaves as a syntactic and semantic unit; turn outis a phrasal verb in the question how many turned out to vote?;
a participle expressing present action; in English is formed by adding -ing;
a participle that expresses completed action;
a verb (or verb construction) that requires an object in order to be grammatical;
a transitive verb that takes both a direct and an indirect object;
a verb (or verb construction) that does not take an object;
(linguistics) the underlying relation that a constituent has with the main verb in a clause;
the semantic role of an entity that is not the agent but is directly involved in or affected by the happening denoted by the verb in the clause;
the semantic role of the animate entity that instigates or causes the happening denoted by the verb in the clause;
the semantic role of the intended recipient who benefits from the happening denoted by the verb in the clause;
the semantic role of the entity (usually inanimate) that the agent uses to perform an action or start a process;
the semantic role of the noun phrase that designates the place of the state or action denoted by the verb;
the semantic role of the animate entity that is passively involved in the happening denoted by the verb in the clause;
the semantic role of the noun phrase whose referent exists only by virtue of the activity denoted by the verb in the clause;
the semantic role of the noun phrase that designates the time of the state or action denoted by the verb;
a language unit by which a person or thing is known; his name really is George Washington; those are two names for the same thing;
an additional name or an epithet appended to a name (as in Ferdinand the Great);
(law) a name under which a corporation conducts business that is not the legal name of the corporation as shown in its articles of incorporation;
the name derived from a person (real or imaginary); Down's syndrome is an eponym for the English physician John Down;
the person for whom something is named; Constantine I is the eponym for Constantinople;
a string of characters beginning with a period and followed by one or more letters; the optional second part of a PC computer filename; most applications provide extensions for the files they create; most BASIC files use the filename extension .BAS;
(computer science) the name given to a computer file in order to distinguish it from other files; may contain an extension that indicates the type of file;
a family name derived from name of your father or a paternal ancestor (especially with an affix (such as -son in English or O'- in Irish) added to the name of your father or a paternal ancestor);
a name derived from the name of your mother or a maternal ancestor;
the name of a street;
the name of a brokerage firm in which stock is held on behalf of a customer; all my stocks are held in street name;
slang for something (especially for an illegal drug); smackis a street name for heroin;
an alternative name that a person chooses or is given (especially in inner city neighborhoods); her street name is Bonbon;
the name used to identify the members of a family (as distinguished from each member's given name);
a woman's surname before marriage;
a name between your first name and your surname;
the name that precedes the surname;
the first name given to Christians at birth or christening;
the first name of a citizen of ancient Rome;
a familiar name for a person (often a shortened version of a person's given name); Joe's mother would not use his nickname and always called him Joseph; Henry's nickname was Slim;
a descriptive name for a place or thing; the nickname for the U.S. Constitution is Old Ironsides;
a name that has been assumed temporarily;
a fictitious name used when the person performs a particular social role;
an incorrect or unsuitable name;
the pseudonym of an actor;
an author's pseudonym;
the name that appears on the by-line to identify the author of a work;
identifying word or words by which someone or something is called and classified or distinguished from others;
a name of endearment (especially one using a diminutive suffix); Billyis a hypocorism for William;
an identifying appellation signifying status or function: e.g. Mr.or General; the professor didn't like his friends to use his formal title;
title for a civil or military leader (especially in Turkey);
a title that Leo X bestowed on Henry VIII and later withdrew; parliament restored the title and it has been used by English sovereigns ever since;
a Spanish courtesy title or form of address for men that is prefixed to the forename; Don Roberto;
a Spanish courtesy title or form of address for a woman; Dona Marguerita;
a German courtesy title or form of address for an adult woman;
a German courtesy title or form of address for an unmarried woman;
a Hebrew title of respect for a wise and highly educated man;
a German courtesy title or form of address for a man;
a form of address for an unmarried woman;
a form of address for a man;
a form of address for a married woman;
a form of address for a woman;
a Hebrew title of respect for a Jewish scholar or teacher;
a title of respect for a clergyman;
a Spanish title or form of address for a man; similar to the English Mror sir;
a Spanish title or form of address for a married woman; similar to the English Mrsor madam;
a Spanish title or form of address used to or of an unmarried girl or woman; similar to the English Miss;
an Italian title or form of address for a married woman;
an Italian title or form of address for an unmarried woman;
a title of respect for various ecclesiastical officials (as cathedral deans and canons and others);
a title used to address any British peer except a duke and extended to a bishop or a judge; Your Lordship; His Lordship;
a title used to address any peeress except a duchess; Your Ladyship; Her Ladyship;
an appellation signifying nobility; your majestyis the appropriate title to use in addressing a king;
the title of a baron;
the title of a viscount;
the name of a work of art or literary composition etc.; he looked for books with the word jazzin the title; he refused to give titles to his paintings; I can never remember movie titles;
the name by which a geographical place is known;
a line of text serving to indicate what the passage below it is about; the heading seemed to have little to do with the text;
a heading of a subsection printed within the body of the text;
the heading or caption of a newspaper article;
the heading that indicates the subject of an annotation or a literary composition or a dictionary entry;
the title of a newspaper or magazine; usually printed on the front page and on the editorial page;
a title or heading that is printed in red or in a special type;
a heading printed at the top of every page (or every other page) of a book;
a heading of a subdivision of a text;
the title (or a shortened title) of a book used as a running head;
a headline with the top line flush left and succeeding lines indented to the right;
a sensational newspaper headline;
a newspaper headline that runs across the full page;
a heading that names a statute or legislative bill; may give a brief summary of the matters it deals with; Title 8 provided federal help for schools;
(usually plural) written material introduced into a movie or TV show to give credits or represent dialogue or explain an action; the titles go by faster than I can read;
a general or descriptive heading for a section of a written work; the novel had chapter titles;
an entry on a list of persons who contributed to a film or written work; the credits were given at the end of the film;
brief description accompanying an illustration;
secondary or explanatory title;
an incorrect translation;
a literal translation used in studying a foreign language(oftenusedillicitly);
translation back into the original language; the teacher translated Latin texts into English which he gave to his students for retroversion;
translation of foreign dialogue of a movie or TV program; usually displayed at the bottom of the screen;
translation of the words of a foreign opera (or choral work) projected on a screen above the stage;
a single line of words in a poem;
(prosody) a line of verse that has the full number of syllables;
(prosody) a line of verse that has six iambic feet;
(prosody) a line of verse that lacks a syllable in the last metrical foot;
