the act of making copies; Gutenberg's reproduction of holy texts was far more efficient;
the immediate rebroadcast of some action (especially sports action) that has been recorded on videotape;
the reproduction of sound;
the reproduction of sound with little or no distortion;
the capacity of a system to reproduce loud sounds without distortion;
the act of reproducing recorded sound; he was allowed to hear the playback of his testimony;
copying (or trying to copy) the actions of someone else;
an imitation or repetition; the flower arrangement was created as an echo of a client's still life;
effort to equal or surpass another;
the resemblance of an animal species to another species or to natural objects; provides concealment and protection from predators;
the act of persisting or persevering; continuing or repeating behavior; his perseveration continued to the point where it was no longer appropriate;
the act of abiding (enduring without yielding);
the continuance of something begun with a view to its completion;
something that survives;
something that has survived from the past; a holdover from the sixties; hangovers from the 19th century;
the act of discontinuing or breaking off; an interruption (temporary or permanent);
the discontinuation of a franchise; especially the discontinuation of the right to vote;
the act by a donor that terminates the right of a person to inherit;
the act or instance of a planned discontinuation;
(law) a proceeding that permits a person to enter into a lawsuit already in progress; admission of person not an original party to the suit so that person can protect some right or interest that is allegedly affected by the proceedings; the purpose of intervention is to prevent unnecessary duplication of lawsuits;
a mode of conducting legal and parliamentary proceedings;
a particular course of action intended to achieve a result; the procedure of obtaining a driver's license; it was a process of trial and error;
a procedure employed by medical or dental practitioners;
a procedure employed by a dentist;
(genetics) the process of locating genes on a chromosome;
a procedure for operating something or for dealing with a given situation;
a prescribed procedure to be followed routinely; rote memorization has been the educator's standard operating procedure for centuries;
a standard procedure that is followed mindlessly; the union's support had been in lockstep for years;
the act of becoming stiff; stiffening his shoulders, he prepared to advance;
needlessly time-consuming procedure;
(law) a procedure whereby a party to a suit says that a particular line of questioning or a particular witness or a piece of evidence or other matter is improper and should not be continued and asks the court to rule on its impropriety or illegality;
(law) an objection grounded on the judge's relationship to one of the parties;
indirect procedure or action; he tried to find out by indirection;
a long and complicated and confusing procedure; all that academic rigmarole was a waste of time;
an unvarying or habitual method or procedure;
an exhausting routine that leaves no time for relaxation;
a settled and monotonous routine that is hard to escape; they fell into a conversational rut;
any activity that is performed in an especially solemn elaborate or formal way; the ceremony of smelling the cork and tasting the wine; he makes a ceremony of addressing his golf ball; he disposed of it without ceremony;
an ancient ritual for preparing and serving and drinking tea;
the proper or conventional behavior on some solemn occasion; an inaugural ceremony;
a ceremonial purification of the Roman population every five years following the census;
any customary observance or practice;
a ceremony having religious meaning;
a military custom performed in observance of some event or anniversary;
a religious meal shared as a sign of love and fellowship;
the activity of worshipping;
the elevation of a person (as to the status of a god);
worship of ancestors;
an established ceremony prescribed by a religion; the rite of baptism;
the rite of staying awake for devotional purposes (especially on the eve of a religious festival);
a vigil held over a corpse the night before burial; there's no weeping at an Irish wake;
a vigil before certain feasts (as e.g. Easter);
rites performed in connection with a death or burial;
secret rite in the cults of ancient Greek or Roman deities involving singing and dancing and drinking and sexual activity;
offensive terms for the practices and rituals of the Roman Catholic Church;
the practice of quoting from books or plays etc.; since he lacks originality he must rely on quotation;
the prescribed procedure for conducting religious ceremonies;
exaggerated emphasis on the importance of rites or ritualistic forms in worship;
the act of circumcising performed on males eight days after birth as a Jewish and Muslim religious rite;
the Jewish rite of circumcision performed on a male child on the eighth day of his life;
going without clothes as a social practice;
the habitual practice of systematization and classification;
the practice of adopting the clothes or the manner or the sexual role of the opposite sex;
the act of public worship following prescribed rules; the Sunday service;
a service conducted in a house of worship; don't be late for church;
a short religious service;
a service at which people sing hymns and pray together;
a service conducted in a place of worship that has its own altar; he was late for chapel;
a rite or body of rites prescribed for public worship;
the Christian worship services;
a religious rite or service prescribed by ecclesiastical authorities; the offices of the mass;
canonical prayers recited daily by priests (e.g. the breviary of the Roman Catholic Church);
a Roman Catholic office honoring the Virgin Mary; similar to but shorter than the Divine Office;
an office read or sung before a burial mass in the Roman Catholic Church;
service committing a body to the grave; the committal service will be held next Monday;
a service in the Roman Catholic Church formerly read or chanted at 3 PM (the ninth hour counting from sunrise) but now somewhat earlier;
a late afternoon or evening worship service;
(Roman Catholic Church) vespers of the office for the dead;
a devotional service (especially on New Year's Eve);
a formal religious ceremony conferring a specific grace on those who receive it; the two Protestant ceremonies are baptism and the Lord's Supper; in the Roman Catholic Church and the Eastern Orthodox Church there are seven traditional rites accepted as instituted by Jesus: baptism and confirmation and Holy Eucharist and penance and holy orders and matrimony and extreme unction;
the traditional Passover supper of Jesus with his disciples on the eve of his crucifixion;
(Judaism) the ceremonial dinner on the first night (or both nights) of Passover;
a Christian sacrament commemorating the Last Supper by consecrating bread and wine;
the part of the Eucharist when bread and wine are offered to God;
the act of participating in the celebration of the Eucharist; the governor took Communion with the rest of the congregation;
participation in Holy Communion by members of more than one church (eg Catholic and Orthodox);
the act of becoming betrothed or engaged;
the ceremony or sacrament of marriage;
the act of marrying; the nuptial ceremony; their marriage was conducted in the chapel;
a ritual performed in some cultures at times when an individual changes status (as from adolescence to adulthood);
archaic terms for a wedding or wedding feast;
a marriage performed by a government official rather than by a clergyman;
a marriage for love's sake; not an arranged marriage;
a Christian sacrament signifying spiritual cleansing and rebirth; most churches baptize infants but some insist on adult baptism;
the act of baptizing someone by pouring water on their head;
the act of sprinkling water in baptism (rare);
giving a Christian name at baptism;
a form of baptism in which part or all of a person's body is submerged;
baptism by immersion three times (in the names in turn of the Trinity);
a sacrament admitting a baptized person to full participation in the church;
