as lifeless as a stone;
(of exocrine glands) producing a secretion in which part of the secreting cell is released with the secretion; mother's milk is one apocrine secretion;
(of exocrine glands) producing a clear aqueous secretion without releasing part of the secreting cell; important in regulating body temperature;
(of water) rising to the surface under internal hydrostatic pressure; an artesian well; artesian pressure;
(of water) rising naturally in a well to a height appreciably above that of the surrounding water table but not flowing out of the well;
exerting force or containing energy; live coals; tossed a live cigarette out the window; got a shock from a live wire; live ore is unmined ore; a live bomb; a live ball is one in play;
of a ball; the ball is still in play;
(used of minerals or stone) in its natural state and place; not mined or quarried; carved into the living stone;
not showing characteristics of life especially the capacity to sustain life; no longer exerting force or having energy or heat; Mars is a dead planet; dead soil; dead coals; the fire is dead;
being out or having grown cold; threw his extinct cigarette into the stream; the fire is out;
not having the capacity to support life; a lifeless planet;
(of a ball) a ball that is out of play is dead;
arranged in order according to the alphabet; an alphabetic arrangement; dictionaries list words in alphabetical order;
alphabetically arranged (as for beginning readers);
having been put in alphabetical order; the cards are all alphabetized, as you requested;
not alphabetic; an analphabetic arrangement of letters; Jesperson's system of phonetic transcription is analphabetic;
(of hatchlings) naked and blind and dependent on parents for food;
(of hatchlings) covered with down and having eyes open; capable of leaving the nest within a few days;
showing unselfish concern for the welfare of others;
limited to or caring only about yourself and your own needs;
absorbed in your own interests or thoughts etc;
having more than one possible meaning; ambiguous words; frustrated by ambiguous instructions, the parents were unable to assemble the toy;
having two purposes; twofold; our double-barreled desire to make things profitable as well as attractive- Louis Kronenbergers;
capable of being interpreted in two usually contradictory ways; double-edged praise;
resembling an oracle in obscurity of thought; the oracular sayings of Victorian poets; so enigmatic that priests might have to clarify it; an enigmatic smile;
ironically ambiguous; a left-handed compliment;
having many values, meanings, or appeals; subtle, multivalent allegory;
of words; having many meanings;
ambiguous (especially in the negative); she spoke in no uncertain terms;
having or exhibiting a single clearly defined meaning; As a horror, apartheid...is absolutely unambiguous- Mario Vargas Llosa;
having only one meaning;
having a strong desire for success or achievement;
marked by aggressive ambition and energy and initiative; an aggressive young executive; a pushful insurance agent;
desiring or striving for recognition or advancement;
strongly motivated to succeed;
unfulfilled or frustrated in realizing an ambition;
excessively ambitious;
having little desire for success or achievement;
lacking or characterized by lack of ambition or initiative; lazy; a shiftless student; studied in a shiftless way;
of or relating to an abnormal condition of the eye in which visual images are not in focus on the retina;
of or relating to the normal condition of the eye in which visual images are in clear focus on the retina;
more than enough in size or scope or capacity; had ample food for the party; an ample supply;
having the normally expected amount; gives full measure; gives good measure; a good mile from here;
more than adequate; a generous portion;
having ample fabric; the current taste for wide trousers; a full skirt;
deficient in amount or quality or extent; meager resources; meager fare;
lacking in amplitude or quantity; a bare livelihood; a scanty harvest; a spare diet;
extremely scanty; an exiguous budget;
providing only bare essentials; a hand-to-mouth existence;
barely satisfying a lower standard; the sharecropper's hardscrabble life;
contemptibly small in amount; a measly tip; the company donated a miserable $100 for flood relief; a paltry wage; almost depleted his miserable store of dried beans;
characterized by or promoting constructive metabolism; some athletes take anabolic steroids to increase muscle size temporarily;
of or relating to anabolism;
characterized by destructive metabolism;
of or relating to catabolism;
of valleys and rivers; progressing in a direction opposite to the dip in surrounding rock strata;
of valleys and rivers; running in the direction of the dip in surrounding rock strata;
not astigmatic;
of or relating to a defect in the eye or in a lens caused by a deviation from spherical curvature which prevents light rays from meeting at a common focus and so results in distorted images;
sloping downward away from a common crest;
sloping downward toward each other to create a trough;
migrating from the sea to fresh water to spawn;
migrating from fresh water to the sea to spawn;
(used of fish) migratory between fresh and salt waters;
of an air current or wind; rising especially up a slope; an anabatic wind;
of an air current or wind; moving downward or down a slope because of cooling especially at night;
a stage in psychosexual development when the child's interest is concentrated on the anal region; fixation at this stage is said to result in orderliness, meanness, stubbornness, compulsiveness, etc.;
a stage in psychosexual development when the child's interest is concentrated in the mouth; fixation at this stage is said to result in dependence, selfishness, and aggression;
of a circuit or device having an output that is proportional to the input; analogue device; linear amplifier;
of a circuit or device that represents magnitudes in digits; digital computer;
of a proposition that is necessarily true independent of fact or experience; all spinsters are unmarriedis an analytic proposition;
of a proposition whose truth value is determined by observation or facts; all men are arrogantis a synthetic proposition;
expressing a grammatical category by using two or more words rather than inflection;
relating to or being a language in which each word typically expresses a distinct idea and part of speech and syntactical relations are determined almost exclusively by word order and particles;
systematic combining of root and modifying elements into single words;
forming derivative or compound words by putting together constituents each of which expresses a single definite meaning;
using or skilled in using analysis (i.e., separating a whole--intellectual or substantial--into its elemental parts or basic principles); an analytic experiment; an analytic approach; a keenly analytic man; analytical reasoning; an analytical mind;
involving or of the nature of synthesis (combining separate elements to form a coherent whole) as opposed to analysis; limnology is essentially a synthetic science composed of elements...that extend well beyond the limits of biology- P.S.Welch;
characterized by inflections indicating grammatical distinctions; inflectional morphology is used to indicate number and case and tense and person etc.;
characterized by inflections indicating a semantic relation between a word and its base; the morphological relation between singand singerand songis derivational;
(of ovaries of flowering plants) consisting of carpels that are free from one another as in buttercups or roses;
(of ovaries of flowering plants) consisting of united carpels;
feeling or showing anger; angry at the weather; angry customers; an angry silence; sending angry letters to the papers;
incited, especially deliberately, to anger; aggravated by passive resistance; the provoked animal attacked the child;
marked by extreme anger; the enraged bull attached; furious about the accident; a furious scowl; infuriated onlookers charged the police who were beating the boy; could not control the maddened crowd;
marked by anger or resentment or hostility; black looks; black words;
characterized by anger; a choleric outburst; an irascible response;
very angry;
roused to anger; stayed huffy a good while- Mark Twain; she gets mad when you wake her up so early; mad at his friend; sore over a remark;
angered at something unjust or wrong; an indignant denial; incensed at the judges' unfairness; a look of outraged disbelief; umbrageous at the loss of their territory;
feeling or showing extreme anger; irate protesters; ireful words;
furiously angry; willful stupidity makes him absolutely livid;
showing scarcely suppressed anger; her tone was...conversational although...her eyes were smoldering- James Hensel;
vehemently incensed and condemnatory; they trembled before the wrathful queen; but wroth as he was, a short struggle ended in reconciliation;
not angry;
full of or marked by resentment or indignant ill will; resentful at the way he was treated; a sullen resentful attitude;
marked by strong resentment or cynicism; an acrimonious dispute; bitter about the divorce;
showing deep-seated resentment; preserve...from rancourous envy of the rich- Aldous Huxley;
not resentful; completely unresentful and forgiving;
having or showing no resentment or desire for revenge; remarkably unbitter toward her captors;
