unfamiliar; new experiences; experiences new to him; errors of someone new to the job;
infrequently exposed to; feet unused to shoes;
being or containing an acid; of a solution having an excess of hydrogen atoms (having a pH of less than 7);
having the characteristics of an acid; an acid reaction;
yielding an acid in aqueous solution;
relating to or containing an alkali; having a pH greater than 7; alkaline soils derived from chalk or limestone;
tending to become alkaline; slightly alkaline;
of or denoting or of the nature of or containing a base;
yielding a base in aqueous solution;
resembling a compound formed by replacing hydrogen in an acid by a metal;
having characteristics of both an acid and a base and capable of reacting as either;
thriving in a relatively acidic environment (especially of plants requiring a pH well below 7);
especially of some bacteria; growing well in an acid medium;
thriving in a relatively alkaline environment;(especiallyofplantsrequiringapHabove7);
recognized or made known or admitted; the acknowledged leader of the community; a woman of acknowledged accomplishments; his acknowledged error;
generally approved or compelling recognition; several accepted techniques for treating the condition; his recognized superiority in this kind of work;
owned up to; his admitted doubts; the conceded error; a confessed murderer; a self-confessed plagiarist;
accepted as real or true without proof; the assumed reason for his absence; assumptive beliefs;
that must be declared; declarable income;
acknowledged as a supposition; given the engine's condition, it is a wonder that it started;
purported; commonly put forth or accepted as true on inconclusive grounds; the foundling's putative father; the putative author of the book;
not recognized or admitted;
having value that is not acknowledged;
not openly made known; a secret marriage; a secret bride;
not admitted; unconfessed sins;
not recognized; he was unrecognized in his disguise;
eager to acquire and possess things especially material possessions or ideas; an acquisitive mind; an acquisitive society in which the craving for material things seems never satisfied;
marked by acquiring or amassing; we live in an accumulative society;
immoderately desirous of acquiring e.g. wealth; they are avaricious and will do anything for money; casting covetous eyes on his neighbor's fields; a grasping old miser; grasping commercialism; greedy for money and power; grew richer and greedier; prehensile employers stingy with raises for their employees;
desirous of owning; small children are so possessive they will not let others play with their toys;
given to taking by force what is desired;
living by or given to victimizing others for personal gain; predatory capitalists; a predatory, insensate society in which innocence and decency can prove fatal- Peter S. Prescott; a predacious kind of animal--the early geological gangster- W.E.Swinton;
excessively greedy and grasping; a rapacious divorcee on the prowl; ravening creditors; paying taxes to voracious governments;
meanly avaricious and mercenary; sordid avarice; sordid material interests;
not acquisitive; not interested in acquiring or owning anything;
of leaves or flowers; developing or opening in succession from base to apex;
of leaves or flowers; developing or opening in succession from apex to base;
characterized by energetic activity; an active toddler; active as a gazelle; an active man is a man of action;
on the move; up and about; the whole town was astir over the incident;
vigorously active; an acrobatic dance; an athletic child; athletic playing; gymnastic exercises;
moving quickly and lightly; sleek and agile as a gymnast; as nimble as a deer; nimble fingers; quick of foot; the old dog was so spry it was halfway up the stairs before we could stop it;
marked by excited activity; a hot week on the stock market;
more active than normal; a hyperactive child;
(of a person) very busy and active; is always on the go;
appropriate for sport or engagement in a sport;
not active physically or mentally; illness forced him to live an inactive life; dreamy and inactive by nature;
restricted to working in an office rather than in an active physical capacity;
inactive but capable of becoming active; her feelings of affection are dormant but easily awakened;
abnormally inactive;
slow and apathetic; she was fat and inert; a sluggish worker; a mind grown torpid in old age;
requiring sitting or little activity; forced by illness to lead a sedentary life;
engaged in full-time work; active duty; though past retirement age he is still active in his profession;
(military) set up and placed on active assignment; a newly activated unit;
not engaged in full-time work; inactive reserve; an inactive member;
not performing or scheduled for duties; He's off every Tuesday;
no longer active in your work or profession;
full of activity or engaged in continuous activity; an active seaport; an active bond market; an active account;
very active; doing a brisk business;
full of energetic and noisy activity; a bustling city;
crowded with or characterized by much activity; a very busy week; a busy life; a busy street; a busy seaport;
in full operation; a going concern;
ready for business; the stores are open;
(of movements) light and confidently active; he walked away with a springy step;
lacking activity; lying idle or unused; an inactive mine; inactive accounts; inactive machinery;
not giving performances; closed; the theater is dark on Mondays;
devoid of activity; this is a dead town; nothing ever happens here;
(of business) not active or brisk; business is dull (or slow); a sluggish market;
not in active use; the machinery sat idle during the strike; idle hands;
closed or immobilized by a strike; a strikebound airline;
tending to become more severe or wider in scope; active tuberculosis;
advancing in severity; progressive paralysis;
(pathology) not progressing or increasing; or progressing slowly;
lacking opportunities for development or advancement; stuck in a dead-end job;
commercially inactive; flat sales for the month; prices remained flat; a flat market;
(of tumors, e.g.) slow to heal or develop and usually painless; an indolent ulcer; leprosy is an indolent infectious disease;
(pathology) not presently active; latent infection; latent diabetes;
(pathology) causing no symptoms; a quiescent tumor;
disposed to take action or effectuate change; a director who takes an active interest in corporate operations; an active antagonism; he was active in drawing attention to their grievances;
advocating or engaged in activism;
involving active participation; he's a hands-on manager; hands-on operations;
(of a policy or person or action) controlling a situation by causing something to happen rather than waiting to respond to it after it happens;
lacking in energy or will; Much benevolence of the passive order may be traced to a disinclination to inflict pain upon oneself- George Meredith;
not involving participation or intervention; a hands-off foreign policy;
offering no resistance; resistless hostages; No other colony showed such supine, selfish helplessness in allowing her own border citizens to be mercilessly harried- Theodore Roosevelt;
(of e.g. volcanos) erupting or liable to erupt; active volcanos;
actively spewing out lava; a geyser is an intermittently eruptive hot spring;
(of e.g. volcanos) not erupting and not extinct ; a dormant volcano;
being quiet or still or inactive;
(of e.g. volcanos) permanently inactive; an extinct volcano;
physically inactive; Crater Lake is in the crater of a dead volcano of the Cascade Range;
(of e.g. volcanos) capable of erupting;
capable of erupting; a live volcano; the volcano is very much alive;
(used of verbs (e.g. to run) and participial adjectives (e.g. runningin running water)) expressing action rather than a state of being;
(used of verbs (e.g. beor own) and most participial adjectives) expressing existence or a state rather than an action;
expressing that the subject of the sentence has the semantic function of actor: Hemingway favors active constructions;
expressing that the subject of the sentence is the patient of the action denoted by the verb; academics seem to favor passive sentences;
exerting influence or producing a change or effect; an active ingredient;
rendered active; e.g. rendered radioactive or luminescent or photosensitive or conductive;
opposing or neutralizing or mitigating an effect by contrary action;
capable of lowering the surface tension of a liquid; used especially of detergents;
