unable to speak because of a brain lesion;
being without sound through injury or illness and thus incapable of all but whispered speech;
unable to speak because of hereditary deafness;
lacking the power of human speech; dumb animals;
unable to express yourself clearly or fluently; felt tongue-tied with embarrassment; incoherent with grief;
expressed without speech; a mute appeal; a silent curse; best grief is tongueless- Emily Dickinson; the words stopped at her lips unsounded; unspoken grief; choking exasperation and wordless shame- Thomas Wolfe;
temporarily incapable of speaking; struck dumb; speechless with shock;
uttered without the use of normal words or syllables;
capable of or involving speech or speaking; human beings--the speaking animals; a speaking part in the play;
having a manner of speaking as specified; often used in combination; golden-tongued ; sharp-tongued ;
not capable of or especially not involving speech or spoken lines; had a nonspeaking role in the play;
consisting of segments held together by joints;
having joints or jointed segments;
not consisting of segments that are held together by joints;
without joints or jointed segments;
feeling shame or guilt or embarrassment or remorse; are you ashamed for having lied?; felt ashamed of my torn coat;
suffering shame;
made to feel uncomfortable because of shame or wounded pride; too embarrassed to say hello to his drunken father on the street; humiliated that his wife had to go out to work; felt mortified by the comparison with her sister;
showing a sense of guilt; a guilty look; the hangdog and shamefaced air of the retreating enemy- Eric Linklater;
showing a sense of shame;
used of persons or their behavior; feeling no shame;
unrestrained by convention or propriety; an audacious trick to pull; a barefaced hypocrite; the most bodacious display of tourism this side of Anaheim- Los Angeles Times; bald-faced lies; brazen arrogance; the modern world with its quick material successes and insolent belief in the boundless possibilities of progress- Bertrand Russell;
feeling no shame; a shameless imposter; an unblushing apologist for fascism;
not embarrassed; a tinseled charm and unabashed sentimentality- Jerome Stone; an unembarrassed greeting as if nothing untoward had happened;
aggressively self-assured; an energetic assertive boy who was always ready to argue; pointing directly at a listener is an assertive act;
overly self-confident or self-assertive; a very cocky young man;
forceful and definite in expression or action; the document contained a particularly emphatic guarantee of religious liberty;
inclined to timidity or lack of self-confidence; a shy unassertive person;
not aggressively self-assured, though not necessarily lacking in confidence; she was quiet and nonassertive as she took control;
reluctant to draw attention to yourself;
characterized by or causing or resulting from the process of bringing ideas or events together in memory or imagination ; associative learning;
capable of being associated; words associable with politics;
not associative;
associated in an exclusive sexual relationship;
pledged to be married; the engaged couple;
future; betrothed; his intended bride;
emotionally involved;
not associated in an exclusive sexual relationship;
not promised in marriage; continued seeing him but on an unengaged basis;
firmly attached; the affixed labels;
affixed as an appendage;
attached by its base (as certain anthers to their filaments or stalks);
affixed or as if affixed with glue or paste; he stayed glued to one spot; pieces of pasted paper;
assembled for use; especially by being attached to a support;
not affixed; the stamp came loose;
attached directly by the base; not having an intervening stalk; sessile flowers; the shell of a sessile barnacle is attached directly to a substrate;
having or growing on or from a peduncle or stalk; a pedunculate flower; a pedunculate barnacle is attached to the substrate by a fleshy foot or stalk;
permanently attached to a substrate; not free to move about; sessile marine animals and plants;
having freedom to move about; vagile aquatic animals;
(of animals) able to swim about; not attached;
used of buildings joined by common sidewalls; a block of attached houses;
used of buildings; standing apart from others; detached houses; a detached garage;
standing apart; not attached to or supported by anything; a freestanding bell tower; a house with a separate garage;
attached on one side only; a semidetached house;
caught or fixed; stuck in the mud;
stranded on or as if on a crag; cragfast climbers;
free; a man with a mule got my car unstuck; the gears locked in second and would not come unstuck;
capable of being fastened or added to something else; a handle attachable by two bolts;
capable of being fastened or secured with a rope or bond;
attachable by a clip; clip-on earrings; a clip-on bow tie;
fastened by tying on; tie-on labels;
designed to be unfastened or disconnected without damage; shirts with detachable collars;
capable of being taken apart; the professor had a clastic model of the human brain;
marked by keen caution and watchful prudence; they were wary in their movements; a wary glance at the black clouds; taught to be wary of strangers;
vigilant; on guard against con artists; must remain on your guard in such a situation;
wary and distrustful; disposed to avoid persons or things; shy of strangers;
not alert to danger or deception; the shrieks of unwary animals taken by surprise; some thieves prey especially on unwary travelers; seduce the unwary reader into easy acquiescence- O.J.Campbell;
easily tricked because of being too trusting; gullible tourists taken in by the shell game;
displaying or feeling no wariness; an unguarded remark;
(often followed by to) giving care or attention; attentive to details; the nurse was attentive to her patient; an attentive suitor;
giving or marked by complete attention to; that engrossed look or rapt delight; then wrapped in dreams; so intent on this fantastic...narrative that she hardly stirred- Walter de la Mare; rapt with wonder; wrapped in thought;
giving attention;
paying close attention especially to details;
excessively solicitous;
showing hovering attentiveness; solicitous about her health; made solicitous inquiries about our family;
showing a lack of attention or care; inattentive students; an inattentive babysitter;
lost in thought; showing preoccupation; an absent stare; an absentminded professor; the scatty glancing quality of a hyperactive but unfocused intelligence;
having the attention diverted especially because of anxiety;
dreamy in mood or nature; a woolgathering moment;
showing lack of attention or boredom; the yawning congregation;
failing to keep in mind; forgetful of her responsibilities; oblivious old age;
pleasing to the eye or mind especially through beauty or charm; a remarkably attractive young man; an attractive personality; attractive clothes; a book with attractive illustrations;
capturing interest as if by a spell; bewitching smile; Roosevelt was a captivating speaker; enchanting music; an enthralling book; antique papers of entrancing design; a fascinating woman;
possessing an extraordinary ability to attract; a charismatic leader; a magnetic personality;
attractive especially by means of smallness or prettiness or quaintness; a cute kid with pigtails; a cute little apartment; cunning kittens; a cunning baby;
(British informal) pretty and neat; what a dinky little hat;
attracting or delighting; an engaging frankness; a piquant face with large appealing eyes;
very attractive; capturing interest; a fetching new hairstyle; something inexpressibly taking in his manner; a winning personality;
superficially attractive and stylish; suggesting wealth or expense; a glossy TV series;
attracting and holding interest as if by a spell; read the bedtime story in a hypnotic voice; she had a warm mesmeric charm; the sheer force of his presence was mesmerizing; a spellbinding description of life in ancient Rome;
overpoweringly attractive; irresistible beauty;
(of persons) pleasant in appearance and personality;
looking attractive in photographs;
creating a favorable impression; strong and vigorous and of prepossessing appearance;
charming in a childlike or naive way;
lacking beauty or charm; as unattractive as most mining regions;
lacking in physical beauty or proportion; a homely child; several of the buildings were downright homely; a plain girl with a freckled face;
devoid of brightness or appeal; a subfusc mining town; dark subfusc clothing;
creating an unfavorable or neutral first impression;
having the properties of a magnet; the ability to draw or pull; an attractive force;
