a unit strand of the vascular system in stems and leaves of higher plants consisting essentially of xylem and phloem;
any of the vascular bundles or ribs that form the branching framework of conducting and supporting tissues in a leaf or other plant organ;
the vein in the center of a leaf;
a sheet of vascular tissue separating the vascular bundles;
the woody part of plants: the supporting and water-conducting tissue, consisting primarily of tracheids and vessels;
long tubular cell peculiar to xylem;
(botany) tissue that conducts synthesized food substances (e.g., from leaves) to parts where needed; consists primarily of sieve tubes;
tube formed by cells joined end-to-end through which nutrients flow in flowering plants and brown algae;
false phloem;
strong woody fibers obtained especially from the phloem of from various plants;
abnormal swelling of plant tissue caused by insects or microorganisms or injury;
oak gall caused by larvae of a cynipid wasp;
a plant having foliage that persists and remains green throughout the year;
a plant having foliage that is shed annually at the end of the growing season;
a plant that when touched or ingested in sufficient quantity can be harmful or fatal to an organism;
a plant with a weak stem that derives support from climbing, twining, or creeping along a surface;
a vine or climbing plant that readily grows up a support or over other plants;
any plant (as ivy or periwinkle) that grows by creeping;
slender stem-like structure by which some twining plants attach themselves to an object for support;
usually coiled;
a plant that climbs by its adventitious roots e.g. ivy;
a plant having hard lignified tissues or woody parts especially stems;
a category in some early taxonomies;
having the shape or characteristics of a tree;
a dead tree that is still standing, usually in an undisturbed forest; a snag can provide food and a habitat for insects and birds;
a tall perennial woody plant having a main trunk and branches forming a distinct elevated crown; includes both gymnosperms and angiosperms;
any tree that is valued as a source of lumber or timber;
a small tree;
tree (as opposed to shrub);
any of several trees having seedpods as fruits;
a tree with limbs cut back to promote a more bushy growth of foliage;
young tree;
a tree planted or valued chiefly for its shade from sunlight;
any tree of the division Gymnospermophyta;
any gymnospermous tree or shrub bearing cones;
any tree having seeds and ovules contained in the ovary;
tree bearing edible nuts;
tree bearing aromatic bark or berries;
any of several trees having leaves or bark used to allay fever or thought to indicate regions free of fever;
the base part of a tree that remains standing after the tree has been felled;
(forestry) the stump of a tree that has been felled or headed for the production of saplings;
a dwarfed ornamental tree or shrub grown in a tray or shallow pot;
a dwarfed evergreen conifer or shrub shaped to have flat-topped asymmetrical branches and grown in a container;
an artificial plant resembling a bonsai;
small plants other than saplings growing on a forest floor;
low-growing plants planted in deep shade or on a steep slope where turf is difficult to grow;
a low woody perennial plant usually having several major stems;
a low shrub;
(Old Testament) the bush that burned without being consumed and from which God spoke to Moses;
dwarf shrub;
low-growing woody shrub or perennial with woody base;
any of various rough thorny shrubs or vines;
shrub noted primarily for its flowers;
a woody climbing usually tropical plant;
plant living on another plant and obtaining organic nutriment from it;
a parasitic plant that contains some chlorophyll and therefore is capable of photosynthesis;
a perennial plant that propagates by underground bulbs or tubers or corms;
plant adapted for life with a limited supply of water; compare hydrophyte and mesophyte;
land plant growing in surroundings having an average supply of water; compare xerophyte and hydrophyte;
a plant that grows partly or wholly in water whether rooted in the mud, as a lotus, or floating without anchorage, as the water hyacinth;
a semiaquatic plant that grows in soft wet land; most are monocots: sedge, sphagnum, grasses, cattails, etc; possibly heath;
plant that derives moisture and nutrients from the air and rain; usually grows on another plant but not parasitic on it;
a plant that is an epiphyte for part of its life;
an epiphytic vine or tree whose aerial roots extend down the trunk of a supporting tree and coalesce around it eventually strangling the tree;
plant that grows on or among rocks or is suitable for a rock garden;
plant that grows on rocks or stony soil and derives nourishment from the atmosphere;
plants growing among rocks;
an organism that feeds on dead organic matter especially a fungus or bacterium;
an organism that lives in and derives its nourishment from organic matter in stagnant or foul water;
an organism that lives in an oxygenated medium lacking organic matter;
plant capable of synthesizing its own food from simple organic substances;
the part of a plant from which the roots spring or the part of a stalk or trunk nearest the roots;
a developed system of roots;
(botany) the usually underground organ that lacks buds or leaves or nodes; absorbs water and mineral salts; usually it anchors the plant to the ground;
an air-filled root (submerged or exposed) that can function as a respiratory organ of a marsh or swamp plant;
(botany) main root of a plant growing straight downward from the stem;
root growing in an unusual location e.g. from a stem;
crop grown for its enlarged roots: e.g. beets; potatoes; turnips;
thimble-shaped mass of cells covering and protecting the growing tip of a root;
small root or division of a root;
thin hairlike outgrowth of an epidermal cell just behind the tip; absorbs nutrients from the soil;
a root that grows from and supports the stem above the ground in plants such as mangroves;
a plant structure resembling a leaf;
a plant or stem onto which a graft is made; especially a plant grown specifically to provide the root part of grafted plants;
root or part of a root used for plant propagation; especially that part of a grafted plant that supplies the roots;
a part (sometimes a root or leaf or bud) removed from a plant to propagate a new plant through rooting or grafting;
cuttings of plants set in the ground to grow as hawthorn for hedges or vines; a quickset of a vine planted in a vineyard;
a horizontal branch from the base of plant that produces new plants from buds at its tips;
the upper branches and leaves of a tree or other plant;
an arrangement of leafy branches forming the top or head of a tree;
plant growing from a tuber;
a fleshy underground stem or root serving for reproductive and food storage;
a horizontal plant stem with shoots above and roots below serving as a reproductive structure;
the main stem or central part about which plant organs or plant parts such as branches are arranged;
axis of a compound leaf or compound inflorescence;
woody stem of palms and tree ferns;
a slender or elongated structure that supports a plant or fungus or a plant part or plant organ;
a segment of a stem between two nodes;
stem of a bean plant;
a flattened stem resembling and functioning as a leaf;
