an opposition that has no intermediate grade; either one or the other;
a relation between two opposite states or principles that together exhaust the possibilities;
the relation that exists when opposites cannot coexist;
opposition between two conflicting forces or ideas;
a contradiction of ideas that serves as the determining factor in their interaction; this situation created the inner dialectic of American history;
the relation between propositions that cannot both be true at the same time;
exact opposition; public opinion to the contrary he is not guilty;
the relation between contraries;
some third thing similar to two opposites but distinct from both;
a relation of direct opposition; we thought Sue was older than Bill but just the reverse was true;
something inverted in sequence or character or effect; when the direct approach failed he tried the inverse;
a relational difference between states; especially between states before and after some event; he attributed the change to their marriage;
a significant change; the difference in her is amazing; his support made a real difference;
a graded change in the magnitude of some physical quantity or dimension;
a gradient in concentration of a solute as a function of distance through a solution; the movement of a solute down its concentration gradient is called diffusion;
a gradient in the gravitational forces acting on different parts of a nonspherical object; the gravity gradient of the moon causes the ocean tides on Earth;
change in temperature as a function of distance (especially altitude);
a logical relation between propositions p and q of the form if p then q; if p is true then q cannot be false;
the relation between opposing principles or forces or factors; the inherent antagonism of capitalism and socialism;
a three-dimensional shape;
(mathematics) an unbounded two-dimensional shape; we will refer to the plane of the graph as the X-Y plane; any line joining two points on a plane lies wholly on that plane;
a plane in which all points can be described in Cartesian coordinates;
the plane of a facet of an object (as of a cube);
the median plane of the body (or some part of the body);
(astronomy) the plane on which a body is orbiting;
the plane that is in the foreground of a drawing or painting; coextensive with but different from the objective surface of the work;
the plane that contains all the lines tangent to a specific point on a surface;
a shape created by natural forces; not man-made;
any of the various shape that leaves of plants can assume;
a figure whose sides are all equal;
a shape that spreads outward; the skirt had a wide flare;
a combination of points and lines and planes that form a visible palpable shape;
a figure formed by a set of straight lines or light rays meeting at a point;
a two-dimensional shape;
a three-dimensional shape;
a figure that is a part of another figure;
a length (straight or curved) without breadth or thickness; the trace of a moving point;
anything with a round shape resembling a teardrop;
a shape that curves or bulges outward;
a slight convexity (as of the surface of a road);
a slight convexity in the shaft of a column; compensates for the illusion of concavity that viewers experience when the sides are perfectly straight;
a shape having one or more sharp angles;
a shape that curves or bends inward;
a solid bounded by a cylindrical surface and two parallel planes (the bases);
a shape that is curved and without sharp angles;
a rounded spherical form;
a plane figure with rounded sides curving inward at the top and intersecting at the bottom; conventionally used on playing cards and valentines; he drew a heart and called it a valentine;
a closed plane figure bounded by straight sides;
an equiangular polygon;
a polygon such that no side extended cuts any other side or vertex; it can be cut by a straight line in at most two points;
a polygon such that there is a straight line that cuts it in four or more points;
a polygon with one or more reentrant angles;
a polygon with all sides and all angles equal;
a shape resulting from distortion;
an ill-defined or arbitrary shape;
the trace of a point whose direction of motion changes;
a curve (such as a circle) having no endpoints;
a closed curve that does not intersect itself;
a double curve resembling the letter S;
the curve theoretically assumed by a perfectly flexible and inextensible cord of uniform density and cross section hanging freely from two fixed points;
the double curve of the upper lip when considered to resemble Cupid's bow;
an undulating curve;
the exterior curve of an arch;
something in a thin curved form (like the neck of a goose);
the interior curve of an arch;
a circular segment of a curve; a bend in the road; a crook in the path;
a sharp curve or crook; a shape resembling a hook;
(biology) any hook-shaped process or part;
a curve that is tangent to each of a family of curves;
a bend or curve (especially in a coastline);
a line traced by a point traveling in a constant direction; a line of zero curvature; the shortest distance between two points is a straight line;
(mathematics) the shortest line between two points on a mathematically defined surface (as a straight line on a plane or an arc of a great circle on a sphere);
a straight line at right angles to another line;
a connecting shape;
a straight line that is the limiting value of a curve; can be considered as tangent at infinity; the asymptote of the curve;
a straight line or plane that touches a curve or curved surface at a point but does not intersect it at that point;
a straight line that intersects a curve at two or more points;
a line enclosing a plane areas;
a straight line from the center to the perimeter of a circle (or from the center to the surface of a sphere);
a straight line connecting the center of a circle with two points on its perimeter (or the center of a sphere with two points on its surface);
a line that bisects a plane figure;
a concave shape whose distinguishing characteristic is that the concavity faces downward;
a concavity in a surface (especially an anatomical depression);
a small concavity;
a shape whose base is a circle and whose sides taper up to a point;
a conical shape with a wider and a narrower opening at the two ends;
(geometry) a curve generated by the intersection of a plane and a circular cone;
a point or set of points common to two or more geometric configurations;
a plane figure that deviates from a square or circle due to elongation;
ellipse in which the two axes are of equal length; a plane curve generated by one point moving at a constant distance from a fixed point; he calculated the circumference of the circle;
a small circle;
something approximating the shape of a circle; the chairs were arranged in a circle;
a circle dividing a sphere or other surface into two usually equal and symmetrical parts;
a plane figure with the shape of half a circle;
a continuous portion of a circle;
one of a series of rounded projections (or the notches between them) formed by curves along an edge (as the edge of a leaf or piece of cloth or the margin of a shell or a shriveled red blood cell observed in a hypertonic solution etc.);
a straight line connecting two points on a curve;
a plane figure bounded by two radii and the included arc of a circle;
something with a round shape resembling a flat circular plate; the moon's disk hung in a cloudless sky;
a toroidal shape; a ring of ships in the harbor; a halo of smoke;
