an angle of 360 degrees;
the angle between the face of a cutting tool and the surface of the work;
(physics) the angle that a magnetic needle makes with the plane of the horizon;
the angle between the direction a gun is aimed and the position of a moving target (correcting for the flight time of the missile);
the angle (at a particular location) between magnetic north and true north;
the azimuth of a celestial body is the angle between the vertical plane containing it and the plane of the meridian;
a concave shape with an open top;
a long narrow furrow cut either by a natural process (such as erosion) or by a tool (as e.g. a groove in a phonograph record);
a groove or furrow (especially one in soft earth caused by wheels);
a hollow concave shape made by removing something;
something that bulges out or is protuberant or projects from its surroundings; the gun in his pocket made an obvious bulge; the hump of a camel; he stood on the rocky prominence; the occipital protuberance was well developed; the bony excrescence between its horns;
a part that bulges deeply; the belly of a sail;
a headlike protuberance on an organ or structure; the caput humeri is the head of the humerus which fits into a cavity in the scapula;
a bump on a ski slope;
a small lump or protuberance;
a sharp protuberance;
any small rounded protuberance (as on certain plants or animals);
any thickened enlargement;
something curved in shape;
any shape resembling the curved shape of the moon in its first or last quarters;
a concavity in a surface produced by pressing; he left the impression of his fingers in the soft mud;
any slight depression in a surface; there are approximately 336 dimples on a golf ball;
a quadric surface generated by rotating a hyperbola around its main axis;
a surface having parabolic sections parallel to a single coordinate axis and elliptic sections perpendicular to that axis;
a surface whose plane sections are all ellipses or circles; the Earth is an ellipsoid;
a subfigure consisting of a side of something;
the side of a right triangle opposite the right angle;
the perpendicular distance from the base of a geometric figure to the opposite vertex (or side if parallel);
the bottom side of a geometric figure from which the altitude can be constructed; the base of the triangle;
equality of distribution;
a symmetrical arrangement of the parts of a thing;
balance among the parts of something;
lack of proportion; imbalance among the parts of something;
a shape that is generated by rotating an ellipse around one of its axes; it looked like a sphere but on closer examination I saw it was really a spheroid;
a three-dimensional closed surface such that every point on the surface is equidistant from the center;
half of a sphere;
a solid figure bounded by a spherical surface (including the space it encloses);
an object with a spherical shape; a ball of fire;
a small sphere;
a surface generated by rotating a parallel line around a fixed line;
a ring-shaped surface generated by rotating a circle around an axis that does not intersect the circle;
the doughnut-shaped object enclosed by a torus;
anything that approximates the shape of a column or tower; the test tube held a column of white powder; a tower of dust rose above the horizon; a thin pillar of smoke betrayed their campsite;
anything that resembles a feather in shape or lightness; a plume of smoke; grass with large plumes;
a small column (or structure resembling a column) that is a part of a plant or animal;
(geology) a column of weathered and unusually shaped rock; a tall sandstone hoodoo;
a bulging cylindrical shape; hollow with flat ends;
a hollow cylindrical shape;
a small sphere;
a small round soft mass (as of chewed food);
a shape that is spherical and small; he studied the shapes of low-viscosity drops; beads of sweat on his forehead;
a drop of dew;
anything shaped like a falling drop (as a pendant gem on an earring);
any long raised strip;
a ridge on a corrugated surface;
the shape of a raised edge of a more or less circular object;
a V shape; the cannibal's teeth were filed to sharp points;
a convex shape that narrows toward a point;
a curve or surface whose equation (in Cartesian coordinates) is of the second degree;
a line determining the limits of an area;
the boundary line or the area immediately inside the boundary;
the outside boundary or surface of something;
a region marking a boundary;
(mathematics) a number equal to or greater than any other number in a given set;
(mathematics) a number equal to or less than any other number in a given set;
a line or cut across a fabric that is not at right angles to a side of the fabric;
(geometry) a straight line connecting any two vertices of a polygon that are not adjacent;
a depression in an otherwise level surface; there was a dip in the road;
any cup-shaped concavity; bees filled the waxen cups with honey; he wore a jock strap with a metal cup; the cup of her bra;
a depression scratched or carved into a surface;
(anatomy) a notch or small hollow;
a V-shaped indentation; mandibular notch;
a slight surface cut (especially a notch that is made to keep a tally);
a shape that sags; there was a sag in the chair seat;
a slight depression in the smoothness of a surface; his face has many lines; ironing gets rid of most wrinkles;
a wrinkle in the skin at the outer corner of your eyes;
the lines that form patterns on the skin (especially on the fingertips and the palms of the hands and the soles of the feet);
a facial wrinkle associated with frowning;
a crease on the palm; its length is said by palmists to indicate how long you will live;
a crease on the palm; palmists say it indicates your emotional nature;
a crease on the palm; palmists say it indicates how successful you will be;
a long narrow depression in a surface;
an angular or rounded shape made by folding; a fold in the napkin; a crease in his trousers; a plication on her blouse; a flexure of the colon; a bend of his elbow;
an irregular fold in an otherwise even surface (as in cloth);
a concave cut into a surface or edge (as in a coastline);
a split or indentation in something (as the palate or chin);
any of a number of tiny parallel grooves such as: the scratches left by a glacier on rocks or the streaks or ridges in muscle tissue;
a line generated by a point on one figure rolling around a second figure;
a line generated by a point on a circle rolling along a straight line;
a cycloid generated by a point inside the rolling circle;
a cycloid generated by a point outside the rolling circle;
the curve of y=sin x;
a circle that rolls around (inside or outside) another circle; generates an epicycloid or hypocycloid;
a line generated by a point on a circle rolling around another circle;
an epicycloid in which the rolling circle equals the fixed circle;
a line generated by a point on a circle that rolls around inside another circle;
an amorphous or indefinite shape; a shapeless mass;
an indistinct shapeless form;
an empty area or space; the huge desert voids; the emptiness of outer space; without their support he'll be ruling in a vacuum;
an empty area (usually bounded in some way between things); the architect left space in front of the building; they stopped at an open space in the jungle; the space between his teeth;
