a cavity or space in something; hunger had caused the hollows in their cheeks;
a connecting point at which several lines come together;
the shape or manner in which things come together and a connection is made;
an unoccupied space;
space that is surrounded by something;
(bowling) the space between the headpin and the pins behind it on the right or left; the ball hit the pocket and gave him a perfect strike;
a very small circular shape; a row of points; draw lines between the dots;
any tiny hole admitting passage of a liquid (fluid or gas);
a figure that branches from a single root; genealogical tree;
a tree diagram used to illustrate phylogenetic relationships;
a tree diagram showing a reconstruction of the transmission of manuscripts of a literary work;
the middle of the chief navigable channel of a waterway that forms the boundary line between states;
any sharply pointed projection;
a narrowing that reduces the flow through a channel;
a smooth surface (as of a bone or cut gemstone);
a straight line segment whose length is magnitude and whose orientation in space is direction;
(mathematics) a straight line extending from a point;
the distinctive form in which a thing is made; pottery of this cast was found throughout the region;
a part of a forked or branching shape; he broke off one of the branches;
(biology) a branching or armlike part of an animal;
the region of the angle formed by the junction of two branches; they took the south fork; he climbed into the crotch of a tree;
an enclosed space; the trapped miners found a pocket of air;
a three-dimensional shape with six square or rectangular sides;
a polyhedron having a polygonal base and triangular sides with a common vertex;
an egg-shaped object;
any polyhedron having four plane faces;
any polyhedron having five plane faces;
any polyhedron having six plane faces;
a parallelepiped bounded by six similar faces (either rhombuses or parallelograms);
any polyhedron having eight plane faces;
any polyhedron having ten plane faces;
any polyhedron having twelve plane faces;
any polyhedron having twenty plane faces;
any one of five solids whose faces are congruent regular polygons and whose polyhedral angles are all congruent;
the space enclosed by three or more planes that intersect in a vertex;
the angle formed by two edges of a polyhedral angle;
a tetrahedron with four equilateral triangular faces;
a hexahedron with six equal squares as faces;
the four-dimensional analogue of a cube;
a cubelike object;
a dodecahedron with twelve regular pentagons as faces;
an octahedron with eight equilateral triangles as faces;
an icosahedron with twenty equilateral triangles as faces;
a truncated cone or pyramid; the part that is left when a cone or pyramid is cut by a plane parallel to the base and the apical part is removed;
a frustum formed from a pyramid;
a frustum formed from a cone;
a polyhedron whose vertices all lie in one or the other of two parallel planes; the faces that lie in those planes are the bases of the prismatoid;
a prismatoid whose bases are polygons having the same number of sides and whose other faces are trapezoids or parallelograms;
any projection that resembles the tail of an animal;
any long thin projection that is transient; tongues of flame licked at the walls; rifles exploded quick knives of fire into the dark;
the angle a rocket makes with the vertical as it curves along its trajectory;
a polyhedron whose faces are trapeziums;
either of two equal and opposite angles formed by the intersection of two straight lines;
a whorl of leaves growing around a stem;
the angle included by a photographic lens;
the channel or break produced by erosion of relatively soft soil by water; it was several days after the storm before they could repair the washout and open the road;
the angle of arrival (or departure) of a radio wave with respect to the axis of an antenna array;
any shape that is triangular in cross section;
any solid convex shape that juts out from something;
a projection or ridge that suggests a keel;
the state of being split or cleft; there was a cleavage between the liberal and conservative members;
a state that is intermediate between extremes; a middle position; a happy medium;
the state of being ornamented;
a mode of being or form of existence of a person or thing; the human condition;
a state at a particular time; a condition (or state) of disrepair; the current status of the arms negotiations;
the set of circumstances that affect someone's welfare; hazardous working conditions; harsh living conditions;
the prevailing context that influences the performance or the outcome of a process; there were wide variations in the conditions of observation;
an illness, disease, or other medical problem; a heart condition; a skin condition;
the condition of being secured to a base; the plant needs a firm anchorage; the mother provides emotional anchorage for the entire family;
the general condition of body and mind; his delicate health; in poor health;
a particular functioning condition or arrangement; switched from keyboard to voice mode;
the state of being conditional;
(physics) the lowest energy state of an atom or other particle;
(ecology) the status of an organism within its environment and community (affecting its survival as a species);
the condition of being noisy (as in a communication channel);
the condition of sharing in common with others (as fellows or partners etc.);
the condition of being prepossessed; the king's prepossession in my favor is very valuable;
the condition of having been made regular (or more regular);
a condition in which a quantity no longer responds to some external influence;
(chemistry) the stage at which a substance will receive no more of another substance in solution or in a vapor;
the state of being silent (as when no one is speaking); there was a shocked silence; he gestured for silence;
a condition or position in which you find yourself; the unpleasant situation (or position) of having to choose between two evils; found herself in a very fortunate situation;
the amount and state of snow for skiing;
a position particularly well suited to the person who occupies it; he found his niche in the academic world;
the status or fact of being elected; they celebrated his election;
the state of being a nation;
the condition of having been proposed as a suitable candidate for appointment or election; there was keen competition for the nomination; his nomination was hotly protested;
a particular situation; If you were in my place what would you do?;
a situation in which an increase in income results in a loss of benefits so that you are no better off;
an unfortunate situation; we're in the soup now;
a situation in golf where an opponent's ball blocks the line between your ball and the hole;
the general state of things; the combination of circumstances at a given time; the present international situation is dangerous; wondered how such a state of affairs had come about; eternal truths will be neither true nor eternal unless they have fresh meaning for every new social situation- Franklin D.Roosevelt;
a situation in which life seems irrational and meaningless; The absurd is the essential concept and the first truth--Albert Camus;
a state of connectedness between people (especially an emotional connection); he didn't want his wife to know of the relationship;
a state involving mutual dealings between people or parties or countries;
the state of living together in tribes;
a formal contractual relationship established to provide for regular banking or brokerage or business services; he asked to see the executive who handled his account;
a brokerage account of someone who sells short (sells securities he does not own);
the friendship characteristic of blood brothers;
the state of being with someone; he missed their company; he enjoyed the society of his friends;
