a private detective employed by a merchant to stop pilferage;
a member of the Nazi SA;
someone who tells lies;
a person who hides aboard a ship or plane in the hope of getting free passage;
a combat pilot who strafes the enemy;
someone who strays or falls behind;
a performer who acts as stooge to a comedian;
anyone who does not belong in the environment in which they are found;
an individual that one is not acquainted with;
a standing subway or bus passenger who grips a hanging strap for support;
a commuter who uses public transportation;
an expert in strategy (especially in warfare);
a member of a work gang who supervises the other workers;
a person who walks rapidly with long steps; he was such a strider that she couldn't keep up without running;
a worker who strings; a stringer of beads;
a member of a squad on a team; a first stringer; a second stringer;
someone who takes off all their clothes and runs naked through a public place;
a worker employed to clean streets (especially one employed by a municipal sanitation department);
someone who learned to fight in the streets rather than being formally trained in the sport of boxing;
a contestant who is very aggressive and willing to use underhand methods;
a child who spends most of his time in the streets especially in slum areas;
(sometimes offensive) a homeless boy who has been abandoned and roams the streets;
a prostitute who attracts customers by walking the streets;
one who helps carry a stretcher;
someone who leads a strike;
an employee on strike against an employer;
someone receiving intensive training for a naval technical rating;
a forward on a soccer team;
a serviceman who wears stripes on the uniform to indicate rank or years of service; he's a four-striper ;
a miner who does strip mining;
a performer who provides erotic entertainment by undressing to music;
a worker who strips the stems from moistened tobacco leaves and binds the leaves together into books;
the oarsman nearest the stern of the shell who sets the pace for the rest of the crew;
a powerful political figure who rules by the exercise of force or violence; he is determined to bring down the Iraqi strongman;
a man who performs feats of strength at a fair or circus;
a person who struggles with difficulties or with great effort;
a member of the royal family that ruled Scotland and England;
a man who is virile and sexually active;
a learner who is enrolled in an educational institution;
a college student who is teaching under the supervision of a certified teacher in order to qualify for a degree in education;
someone who memorizes quickly and easily (as the lines for a part in a play); he is a quick study;
a bore who is extremely formal, pompous, and old-fashioned;
a second-rate prize fighter;
a stand-in for movie stars to perform dangerous stunts; his first job in Hollywood was as a double for Clark Gable;
a walker or runner who trips and almost falls;
a person who is not very bright; The economy, stupid!;
an artist who is a master of a particular style;
an early Christian ascetic who lived on top of high pillars;
a British commissioned army officer below the rank of captain;
someone who enters into a subcontract with the primary contractor;
a clergyman an order below deacon; one of the Holy Orders in the unreformed western Christian church and the eastern Catholic Churches but now suppressed in the Roman Catholic Church;
someone who divides parts into smaller parts (especially a divider of land into building sites);
someone who overcomes and establishes ascendancy and control by force or persuasion;
a person who is subjected to experimental or other observational procedures; someone who is an object of investigation; the subjects for this investigation were selected randomly; the cases that we studied were drawn from two different communities;
a person who subscribes to subjectivism;
a conqueror who defeats and enslaves;
an officer ranking next below a lieutenant;
a member of the crew of a submarine;
someone who submits something (as an application for a job or a manuscript for publication etc.) for the judgment of others; he was a prolific submitter of proposals;
someone who yields to the will of another person or force;
a person of less than normal intelligence;
an assistant subject to the authority or control of another;
someone who contributes (or promises to contribute) a sum of money;
someone who contracts to receive and pay for a service or a certain number of issues of a publication;
someone who expresses strong approval;
someone who assists or supports by giving a subsidy;
an athlete who plays only when a starter on the team is replaced;
a person who subtracts numbers;
a resident of a suburb;
someone who articulates speech without uttering sounds;
a person who inherits some title or office;
a person who follows next in order; he was President Lincoln's successor;
someone who gives help in times of need or distress or difficulty;
a drinker who sucks (as at a nipple or through a straw);
someone who petitions a court for redress of a grievance or recovery of a right;
a Muslim who represents the mystical dimension of Islam; a Muslim who seeks direct experience of Allah; mainly in Iran;
an assistant or subordinate bishop of a diocese;
a woman advocate of women's right to vote (especially a militant advocate in the United Kingdom at the beginning of the 20th century);
an advocate of the extension of voting rights (especially to women);
a wealthy older man who gives a young person expensive gifts in return for friendship or intimacy;
someone who advances a suggestion or proposal; the suggester of this absurd strategy was a fool;
a person who kills himself intentionally;
a terrorist who blows himself up in order to kill or injure other people;
(slang) a businessman dressed in a business suit; all the suits care about is the bottom line;
a man who courts a woman; a suer for the hand of the princess;
the ruler of a Muslim country (especially of the former Ottoman Empire);
a member of a people who inhabited ancient Sumer;
(Maine colloquial) temporary summer residents of coastal Maine;
a wrestler who participates in sumo (a Japanese form of wrestling); sumo wrestlers are large heavy men;
a person considered as a source of warmth or energy or glory etc;
someone who basks in the sunshine in order to get a suntan;
a tramp who habitually arrives at sundown;
someone who worships the sun;
an officer on a merchant ship in charge of the cargo and its sale and purchase;
a police informer who implicates many people;
an amateur boxer who weighs more than 201 pounds;
a caretaker for an apartment house; represents the owner as janitor and rent collector;
the head of a religious community;
one of greater rank or station or quality;
an operator of a supermarket;
