a woman songster (especially of popular songs);
a composer of words or music for popular songs;
the husband of your daughter;
a poet who writes sonnets;
any of a group of Greek philosophers and teachers in the 5th century BC who speculated on a wide range of subjects;
a worldly-wise person;
a second-year undergraduate;
a female singer;
one who practices magic or sorcery;
in societies practicing shamanism: one acting as a medium between the visible and spirit worlds; practices sorcery for healing or divination;
a Native American shaman;
a woman sorcerer;
someone who is peevish or disgruntled;
a person of a particular character or nature; what sort of person is he?; he's a good sort;
a clerk who sorts things (as letters at the post office);
a pert or flirtatious young girl;
the immaterial part of a person; the actuating cause of an individual life;
someone for whom you have a deep affinity;
a person whose reactions to something serve as an indication of its acceptability; I would use newspapermen as a sounding board for such policies;
a technician in charge of amplifying sound or producing sound effects (as for a TV or radio broadcast);
a settler or prospector (especially in western United States or northwest Canada and Alaska);
someone with a habitually sullen or gloomy expression;
a member of the Southern Baptist Convention;
an American who lives in the South;
Johnnywas applied as a nickname for Confederate soldiers by the Federal soldiers in the American Civil War; greybackderived from their grey Confederate uniforms;
a nation's ruler or head of state usually by hereditary right;
someone who sows;
someone who seems unable to respond appropriately to reality (as if under the influence of some narcotic drug);
an astronaut who is active outside a spacecraft in outer space;
a writer paid by the area of the copy;
someone who sends unwanted email (often in bulk);
an American whose first language is Spanish;
someone who refrains from injuring or destroying;
a boxer who spars with another boxer who is training for an important fight;
a person suffering from spastic paralysis;
someone who expresses in language; someone who talks (especially someone who delivers a public speech or someone especially garrulous); the speaker at commencement; an utterer of useful maxims;
a speaker of a particular language who has spoken that language since earliest childhood; native speakers of French;
the presiding officer of a deliberative assembly; the leader of the majority party is the Speaker of the House of Representatives;
someone who leads or initiates an activity (attack or campaign etc.);
a writer who composes speeches for others to deliver;
someone whose authority is limited to the special undertaking they have been instructed to perform;
an expert who is devoted to one occupation or branch of learning;
practices one branch of medicine;
someone who draws up specifications giving details (as for obtaining a patent);
a close observer; someone who looks at something (such as an exhibition of some kind); the spectators applauded the performance; television viewers; sky watchers discovered a new star;
someone who risks losses for the possibility of considerable gains;
someone who makes conjectures without knowing the facts;
a therapist who treats speech defects and disorders;
a driver who exceeds the safe speed limit;
addict who habitually uses stimulant drugs (especially amphetamines);
an ice-skater who races competitively; usually around an oval course;
an orator who can hold his listeners spellbound;
someone who spells words;
someone who spends money to purchase goods or services;
someone who spends money prodigally;
one who spends lavishly and ostentatiously on entertainment; the last of the big spenders;
an inscrutable person who keeps his thoughts and intentions secret;
a thin person with long thin legs;
a public relations person who tries to forestall negative publicity by publicizing a favorable interpretation of the words or actions of a company or political party or famous person; his title is Director of Communications but he is just a spin doctor;
someone who spins (who twists fibers into threads);
an elderly unmarried woman;
the vital principle or animating force within living things;
a highly emotional and quick-tempered person (especially a girl or woman);
a person who spits (ejects saliva or phlegm from the mouth);
a person without employment who makes money by various dubious schemes; goes about smartly dressed and having a good time;
a worker who splices ropes together by interweaving strands;
a woodworker who joins pieces of wood with a splice;
(football) an offensive end who lines up at a distance from the other linemen;
a taxonomist who classifies organisms into many groups on the basis of relatively minor characteristics;
a worker who splits fish and removes the backbone;
a candidate with no chance of winning but who may draw enough votes to prevent one of the leading candidates from winning;
someone who spoils the pleasure of others;
a male spokesperson;
an advocate who represents someone else's policy or purpose; the meeting was attended by spokespersons for all the major organs of government;
a female spokesperson;
a workman employed to collect sponges;
someone who engages in sports;
a person known for the way she (or he) behaves when teased or defeated or subjected to trying circumstances; a good sport; a poor sport;
(Maine colloquial) a temporary summer resident of Maine;
someone who enjoys outdoor activities;
someone who leads a merry existence; especially a gambler on the outcome of sporting events;
an announcer who reads sports news or describes sporting events;
the newspaper editor responsible for sports news;
an enthusiastic devotee of sports;
a journalist who writes about sports;
a worker employed to apply spots (as markers or identifiers);
a worker employed at a dry-cleaning establishment to remove spots;
a welder who does spot welding;
a person's partner in marriage;
a person who sprawls; he is such a sprawler he needs a bed to himself;
a worker who applies spray to a surface;
a child;
a new military recruit;
someone who runs a short distance at top speed;
a person who rejects (someone or something) with contempt; she was known as a spurner of all suitors; he was no spurner of rules;
(military) a secret agent hired by a state to obtain information about its enemies or by a business to obtain industrial secrets from competitors;
a secret watcher; someone who secretly watches other people; my spies tell me that you had a good time last night;
someone who directs clandestine intelligence activities;
someone who quarrels about a small matter;
someone who does square dancing;
