relating to anemia or suffering from anemia;
relating to or producing insensibility;
relating to the ablative case;
specifically indicating a form of prosecution in which one is publicly accused of and tried for a crime and in which the judge is not also the prosecutor;
especially indicating a form of prosecution in which proceedings are secret and the accused is questioned by a prosecutor who acts also as the judge;
of or relating to the countries or cultures or people of West Africa;
belonging or relating to white people of South Africa whose ancestors were Dutch or to their language; an Afrikaans couple; Afrikaner support;
containing no liquid or actuated without the use of liquid; aneroid barometer;
of or relating to or characteristic of Angola or its people; the Angolan Civil War;
of or relating to or characteristic of Anguilla or its people; Anguillan sea food specialties;
relating to events before a marriage; prenuptial agreement;
relating to events after a marriage;
relating to or characterized by anti-Semitism; hating Jews;
of or relating to or characteristic of Antigua or its people; Antiguan islands;
of or relating to antiques or antiquities;
of or relating to persons who study or deal in antiques or antiquities;
of or relating to or taking account of appeals (usually legal appeals); appellate court;
having the character of an anecdote; anecdotal evidence;
of or relating to Arabian horses;
relating to or associated with Arabia or its people; Arabian Nights; Arabian Sea;
relating to or characteristic of Arabs; Arabic languages;
relating to or involving arithmetic; arithmetical computations;
of or relating to heraldry or heraldic arms; armorial bearing;
of or belonging to an aspect (as an aspect of the verb); the aspectual system of Greek;
in a state of asphyxia;
of or relating to a method of teaching language that focuses on listening and speaking;
relating to or characteristic of the times of the Roman Emperor Augustus; the Augustan Age;
of or relating to or characteristic of Australia or its inhabitants or its languages; Australian deserts; Australian aborigines;
of or relating to or characteristic of the Bahama Islands or their inhabitants; Bahamian population;
of or relating to or characteristic of Bahrain or its people or language; Bahraini beaches;
of or relating to or characteristic of Bangladesh or its people or language; Bangladeshi dialects;
relating to or designating languages that possess characteristics of Bantu; Bantoid languages;
of or relating to the African people who speak one of the Bantoid languages or to their culture; the Bantu population of Sierra Leone;
of or relating to people who speak Bantu; the Bantu-speaking people of Africa;
of or relating to baptism; baptismal font;
of or relating to or characteristic of Barbados or its inhabitants; a Barbadian vacation;
being a bard or relating to a bard's poetry; bardic poetry;
of or relating to the Benedictines;
of or relating to Saint Benedict or his works;
of or relating to or characteristic of Bengal or its people; Bengali hills;
of or relating to or characteristic of Benin or its people; Benin bronzes;
of or relating to or characteristic of Bermuda or its inhabitants; Bermudan beaches;
of or pertaining to or characteristic of Bhutan or its people or culture or language; Bhutanese Buddhists;
of or relating to or being a speech sound that is articulated using both lips; bilabial fricatives;
of or relating to or consisting of two terms; binomial expression;
of or relating to or being biography; biographical data;
resembling or containing bitumen; bituminous coal;
like bitumen;
having a valence of two or having two valences;
having two variables; bivariate binomial distribution;
resembling a bladder;
bearing or characterized by a blade or sword; often used in combination; he fought on, broken-bladed but unbowed;
having a blade or blades; often used in combination; a single-bladed leaf; narrow-bladed grass;
of or relating to blastemata;
of or relating to a segmentation cavity;
of or relating to a blastoderm;
of or relating to a blastomere;
of or relating to or characteristic of blastomycosis;
of or relating to a blastopore;
of or relating to a blastula;
of or relating to or derived from or containing boron; boric acid;
of or relating to or characteristic of Brunei or its people; Bruneian oil production;
of or evidencing buboes; bubonic plague;
of or relating to or characteristic of Bulgaria or its people; the Bulgarian capital is Sofia;
characterized by bungalows; the bungaloid suburbs;
of or relating to or resembling a bureaucrat or bureaucracy; his bureaucratic behavior annoyed his colleagues; a bureaucratic nightmare;
involving or resembling burglary; burglarious tools;
of or relating to or characteristic of Myanmar or its people; the Burmese capital; Burmese tonal languages;
of or relating to or characteristic of Burundi or its people; the Burundi capital;
of or relating to or characteristic of California or its inhabitants; Californian beaches;
of or relating to or characteristic of Cameroon or its people; the Cameroonian capital;
characteristic of cannibals or exhibiting cannibalism; cannibalistic behavior;
of or relating to a canton;
of or relating to the Carboniferous geologic era; carboniferous rock system;
of or relating to the Carmelite friars; Carmelite monasteries;
of or relating to the wrist; Carpal tunnel syndrome;
of or relating to the use of ethical principles to resolve moral problems;
of or relating to or practicing casuistry; overly subtle casuistic reasoning;
relating to or characteristic of the Catalan language; Catalan poetry;
relating to or denoting or characteristic of Catalonia or its inhabitants; Catalan independence movement;
of or having characteristics of or affected with catalepsy; cataleptic persons; cataleptic state;
relating to or causing or involving catalysis; catalytic reactions;
characterized by catatonia especially either rigidity or extreme laxness of limbs;
of or relating to or characteristic of the Republic of Chad or its people or language; the Chadian desert; Chad soldiers; Chadian folktales;
of or related to citric acid;
of or relating to or producing fruit of the plants of the genus Citrus; the citrus production of Florida;
of or relating to plants of the genus Citrus; a citrous disease;
of or relating to a climate; climatic changes;
relating to or resembling a cockney; Cockney street urchins;
characteristic of Cockneys or their dialect; cockney vowels;
intended as a commemoration; a commemorative plaque;
of or pertaining to concession;
of or relating to or characteristic of the Congo region or its people; Congolese rulers; the Congolese republic;
having to do with a consul or his office or duties;
of or relating to the Copts or their church or language or art; the distinctive Coptic art of 6th-century Christian Egypt;
of or relating to Costa Rica or its people; the Costa Rican rain forest; our Costa Rican neighbors;
of fabric that does not wrinkle easily;
of or relating to a creed;
of or relating to or characteristic of native-born persons of French descent in Louisiana; Creole cooking;
of or relating to a language that arises from contact between two other languages and has features of both; Creole grammars;
