situated in or suitable for the outdoors or outside of a building; an exterior scene; exterior grade plywood; exterior paints;
outside or external; the out surface of a ship's hull;
leading to or from the outside; an outside door;
situated within or suitable for inside a building; an interior scene; interior decoration; an interior bathroom without windows;
within doors; an indoor setting;
being or applying to the inside of a building; an inside wall;
having an eye or eyes or eyelike feature especially as specified; often used in combination; a peacock's eyed feathers; red-eyed;
having almond-shaped eyes;
having blue eyes;
suggesting an eye or eyes; eyelike markings on a butterfly's wings; the eyelike gleam of two distant windows in the dark;
having keen eyesight;
having only the left eye;
having or showing only one eye; one-eyed Jacks are wild; the three one-eyed Cyclopes of Greek myth;
having large round eyes like those of an ox; ox-eyed Juno;
having bulging eyes;
(of flowers) having a purple eyelike marking;
having only the right eye;
having large round wide-open eyes;
having eyes that look in different directions;
lacking eyes or eyelike features; eyeless fish that evolved in dark caves; an eyeless needle;
capable of or suitable for being played or played on; a playable lie in golf; the baseball fan reached out and caught a foul that was judged playable; the ball field was playable; harpsichord music is readily playable- P.H.Lang;
not capable of or suitable for being played or played on; the golf ball was in an unplayable lie; the field was unplayable; some music seems almost unplayable;
(of a baseball) hit between the foul lines; he hit a fair ball over the third base bag;
between the first and third base lines;
(of a baseball) not hit between the foul lines;
outside the foul lines;
free from favoritism or self-interest or bias or deception; conforming with established standards or rules; a fair referee; fair deal; on a fair footing; a fair fight; by fair means or foul;
of laws and regulations; designed to protect trade and commerce from unfair business practices;
exhibiting or calling for sportsmanship or fair play; a clean fight; a sporting solution of the disagreement; sportsmanlike conduct;
of a person; just and impartial; not prejudiced;
just and honest;
not fair; marked by injustice or partiality or deception; used unfair methods; it was an unfair trial; took an unfair advantage;
disregarding the rules (from the notion of an illegal low blow in boxing); her accusations were below the belt;
violating accepted standards or rules; a dirty fighter; used foul means to gain power; a nasty unsporting serve; fined for unsportsmanlike behavior;
brutally unfair or harsh; received raw treatment from his friends; a raw deal;
fair to all parties as dictated by reason and conscience; equitable treatment of all citizens; an equitable distribution of gifts among the children;
gained or earned without cheating or stealing; an honest wage; an fair penny;
without partiality; evenhanded justice;
not equitable or fair; the inequitable division of wealth; inequitable taxation;
steadfast in affection or allegiance; years of faithful service; faithful employees; we do not doubt that England has a faithful patriot in the Lord Chancellor;
unwavering in devotion to friend or vow or cause; a firm ally; loyal supporters; the true-hearted soldier...of Tippecanoe- Campaign song for William Henry Harrison; fast friends;
devoted (sometimes fanatically) to a cause or concept or truth; true believers bonded together against all who disagreed with them;
not true to duty or obligation or promises; an unfaithful lover;
not faithful to religion or party or cause;
tending to betray; especially having a treacherous character as attributed to the Carthaginians by the Romans; Punic faith; the perfidious Judas; the fiercest and most treacherous of foes; treacherous intrigues;
not true to an obligation or trust; is untrue to his highest opportunity and duty-Bruno Laske;
not having sexual relations with anyone except your husband or wife, or your boyfriend or girlfriend; he remained faithful to his wife;
sexually faithful; she was true to her significant other;
having sexual relations with someone other than your husband or wife, or your boyfriend or girlfriend; her husband was unfaithful;
not faithful to a spouse or lover; adulterous husbands and wives; a two-timing boyfriend;
steadfast in allegiance or duty; loyal subjects; loyal friends stood by him;
steadfast in devotion (especially to your lawful monarch or government); it is impossible to be allegiant to two opposing forces;
resembling a dog; especially in devotion; a doglike affection;
intensely loyal; his hard-core supporters;
faithful and true; leal to the core of her intrepid Scottish heart- Harry Lauder;
owing or owed feudal allegiance and service; one's liege lord; a liege subject;
marked by unswerving loyalty; a true-blue American; a reliable true-blue country club conservative;
deserting your allegiance or duty to leader or cause or principle; disloyal aides revealed his indiscretions to the papers;
having the character of, or characteristic of, a traitor; the faithless Benedict Arnold; a lying traitorous insurrectionist;
in opposition to a civil authority or government;
consisting of or characterized by or inciting to mutiny; mutinous acts; mutinous thoughts; a mutinous speech;
participating in organized resistance to a constituted government; the rebelling confederacy;
having deserted a cause or principle; some provinces had proved recreant; renegade supporters of the usurper;
likely to fail or make errors; everyone is fallible to some degree;
straying from the right course or from accepted standards; errant youngsters;
capable of making an error; all men are error-prone;
liable to be erroneous or misleading; an undependable generalization;
likely to fail under stress or pressure; the weak link in the chain;
incapable of failure or error; an infallible antidote; an infallible memory; the Catholic Church considers the Pope infallible; no doctor is infallible;
not liable to failure; a foolproof identification system; the unfailing sign of an amateur; an unfailing test;
not liable to error; the Church was...theoretically inerrant and omnicompetent-G.G.Coulton; lack an inerrant literary sense; an unerring marksman;
well known or easily recognized; a familiar figure; familiar songs; familiar guests;
having fair knowledge of; they were acquainted; fully acquainted with the facts;
much trodden and worn smooth or bare; did not stray from the beaten path;
frequently experienced; known closely or intimately; a long-familiar face; a well-known voice reached her ears;
(used for emphasis) very familiar; good old boy; same old story;
not known or well known; a name unfamiliar to most; be alert at night especially in unfamiliar surroundings;
not known before; used many strange words; saw many strange faces in the crowd; don't let anyone unknown into the house;
having little or no knowledge of; unacquainted with city ways;
being definitely out of the ordinary and unexpected; slightly odd or even a bit weird; a strange exaltation that was indefinable; a strange fantastical mind; what a strange sense of humor she has;
ludicrously odd; Hamlet's assumed antic disposition; fantastic Halloween costumes; a grotesque reflection in the mirror;
bizarre or fantastic; had a crazy dream; wore a crazy hat;
beyond or deviating from the usual or expected; a curious hybrid accent; her speech has a funny twang; they have some funny ideas about war; had an odd name; the peculiar aromatic odor of cloves; something definitely queer about this town; what a rum fellow; singular behavior;
inspiring a feeling of fear; strange and frightening; an uncomfortable and eerie stillness in the woods; an eerie midnight howl;
strikingly strange or unusual; an exotic hair style; protons, neutrons, electrons and all their exotic variants; the exotic landscape of a dead planet;
strange and somewhat frightening; the whole experience was really freaky;
characterized by gloom and mystery and the grotesque; gothic novels like Frankenstein;
somewhat strange;
very unusual; different in character or quality from the normal or expected; a strange, other dimension...where his powers seemed to fail- Lance Morrow;
strange in an interesting or pleasing way; quaint dialect words; quaint streets of New Orleans, that most foreign of American cities;
very strange or unusual; odd or even incongruous in character or appearance; the head terminating in the quaint duck bill which gives the animal its vernacular name- Bill Beatty; came forth a quaint and fearful sight- Sir Walter Scott; a quaint sense of humor;
strikingly odd or unusual; some trick of the moonlight; some weird effect of shadow- Bram Stoker;
within normal everyday experience; common and ordinary; not strange; familiar ordinary objects found in every home; a familiar everyday scene; a familiar excuse; a day like any other filled with familiar duties and experiences;
commonly encountered; a common (or familiar) complaint; the usual greeting;
the usual or familiar type; it is a common or garden sparrow;
commonplace and ordinary; the familiar everyday world;
being or in accordance with current social fashions; fashionable clothing; the fashionable side of town; a fashionable cafe;
in the current fashion or style;
fashionable and attractive at the time; often skilled or socially adept; he's a cool dude; that's cool; Mary's dress is really cool; it's not cool to arrive at a party too early;
marked by up-to-dateness in dress and manners; a dapper young man; a jaunty red hat;
