locked in by ice; icebound harbors;
obstructed by ice; ice-clogged rivers;
covered with or containing or consisting of ice; icy northern waters;
consisting of or of the nature of frozen or partially frozen rain;
still frozen; there wasn't time to cook the unthawed turkey, so they had to settle for hotdogs;
not frozen; unfrozen ground;
free of ice and open to travel; an ice-free channel in the river;
becoming liquid;
being or resembling melting snow; slushy snow; deep slushy mud;
no longer frozen; the thawed ground was muddy;
productive or conducive to producing in abundance; be fruitful and multiply;
producing or bearing berries;
bearing blue fruit;
producing in abundance; the bountiful earth; a plentiful year; fruitful soil;
producing offspring or set aside especially for producing offspring; the breeding population; retained a few bulls for breeding purposes;
bearing dark fruit;
marked by great fruitfulness; fertile farmland; a fat land; a productive vineyard; rich soil;
producing new life or offspring; the reproductive potential of a species is its relative capacity to reproduce itself under optimal conditions; the reproductive or generative organs;
yielding a large amount of agricultural or industrial production;
bearing oval fruit;
bearing in abundance especially offspring; flying foxes are extremely prolific; a prolific pear tree;
bearing red fruit;
bearing round fruit;
bearing small fruit;
not fruitful; not conducive to abundant production;
failing to accomplish an intended result; an abortive revolt; a stillborn plot to assassinate the President;
producing no fruit;
without offspring; in some societies a childless woman is rejected by her tribesmen;
containing as much or as many as is possible or normal; a full glass; a sky full of stars; a full life; the auditorium was full to overflowing;
covered with water; the main deck was afloat (or awash); the monsoon left the whole place awash; a flooded bathroom; inundated farmlands; an overflowing tub;
full of air;
filled to capacity; a brimful cup; I am brimful of chowder; a child brimming over with curiosity; eyes brimming with tears;
packed full to capacity; chowder chockablock with pieces of fish;
overfull as with blood;
full of eggs;
(usually followed by withor used as a combining form) generously supplied with; theirs was a house filled with laughter; a large hall filled with rows of desks; fog-filled air;
filled with or attended with; words fraught with meaning; an incident fraught with danger; a silence pregnant with suspense;
full of a gas;
exceeding demand; a glutted market;
full of; bearing great weight; trees heavy with fruit; vines weighed down with grapes;
(followed by with) deeply filled or permeated; imbued with the spirit of the Reformation; words instinct with love; it is replete with misery;
filled with a great quantity; a tray loaded with dishes; table laden with food; ladenedis not current usage;
loaded past capacity;
spread throughout; cities riddled with corruption;
filled with sperm;
filled with something; a stuffed turkey;
crammed with food; a full stomach; I feel stuffed;
still full; an untouched cocktail in her hand;
full of money; a well-lined purse;
holding or containing nothing; an empty glass; an empty room; full of empty seats; empty hours;
having everything extraneous removed including contents; the bare walls; the cupboard was bare;
(of a surface) not written or printed on; blank pages; fill in the blank spaces; a clean page; wide white margins;
carrying nothing in the hands;
(used of eyes) lacking liveliness; empty eyes; a glassy stare; his eyes were glazed over with boredom;
destitute or having been emptied of life or living beings; after the dance the littered and lifeless ballroom echoed hollowly;
wrongfully emptied or stripped of anything of value; the robbers left the looted train; people returned to the plundered village;
without an occupant or incumbent; the throne is never vacant;
void of thought or knowledge; a vacant mind;
devoid of matter; a vacuous space;
containing nothing; the earth was without form, and void;
emptied or exhausted of (as by drawing off e.g. water or other liquid); a drained marsh; a drained tank; a drained and apathetic old man...not caring any longer about anything;
emptied of emotion; after the violent argument he felt empty;
drained physically; the day's events left her completely exhausted--her strength drained;
not drained; preserve wetlands; keep them undrained;
for the entire time appropriate to an activity; a full-time job;
officially full-time; regular students;
involving less than the standard or customary time for an activity; part-time employees; a part-time job;
involving half the standard or customary time for an activity; he had two years of half-time training;
lacking continuity or regularity; an irregular worker; employed on a temporary basis;
not regular or skilled; found only odd-job employment;
employed only part-time when one needs full-time employment or not making full use of your skills; migrants are likely to be poor and underemployed; able people are kept underemployed;
designed for or capable of a particular function or use; a style of writing in which every word is functional; functional architecture;
affecting or involved in structure or construction; the structural details of a house such as beams and joists and rafters; not ornamental elements; structural damage;
having a useful function; utilitarian steel tables;
not having or performing a function;
not structural;
serving an esthetic rather than a useful purpose; cosmetic fenders on cars; the buildings were utilitarian rather than decorative;
performing or able to perform its regular function; a functioning flashlight;
(of e.g. a machine) performing or capable of performing; in running (or working) order; a functional set of brakes;
(used of computers) operating properly; how soon will the computers be up?;
not performing or able to perform its regular function; a malfunctioning valve;
not functioning properly; something is amiss; has gone completely haywire; something is wrong with the engine;
not working properly; a bad telephone connection; a defective appliance;
out of balance or out of adjustment; the front wheel of my bicycle is out of whack;
having the spring unwound; a run-down watch;
involving or affecting function rather than physiology; functional deafness;
involving or affecting physiology or bodily organs; an organic disease;
fitted or equipped with necessary rigging (sails and shrouds and stays etc);
rigged with a triangular (lateen) sail;
rigged with a structure projecting from or over the side of a boat for various purposes; to prevent capsizing or to support an oarlock or to help secure a mast etc;
rigged with square sails as the principal ones;
stripped of rigging;
provided or fitted out with what is necessary or useful or appropriate; a well equipped playground; a ship equipped with every mechanical aid to navigation;
provided with necessary articles of equipment for a specialized purpose (especially military); troops accoutered for battle; properly accoutered for the trip;
equipped with the complete arms and armor of a warrior;
equipped with or wearing a helmet;
equipped with appropriate wearing apparel and accessories; children properly outfitted for school; equipt in the...national dress of the Scottish people- Sir Walter Scott;
equipped or prepared with necessary intellectual resources; graduates well equipped to handle such problems; equipped to be a scholar;
(of an electronic device) equipped with transistors;
having or provided with a visor or a visor of a particular kind; their spic, red-visored caps;
