certain to be successful; a sure-fire way to get rich;
unofficial championship title for player who heads the league in batting average and home runs and runs batted in;
of a horse that has won the Kentucky Derby and the Belmont Stakes and the Preakness races;
having won; the victorious entry; the winning team;
not successful; having failed or having an unfavorable outcome;
tried unsuccessfully; attempted murder;
disappointingly unsuccessful; disappointed expectations and thwarted ambitions; their foiled attempt to capture Calais; many frustrated poets end as pipe-smoking teachers; his best efforts were thwarted;
doomed to extinction;
lacking resources (or any prospect of resources);
having acquired or gained nothing; the returned from the negotiations empty-handed;
(of a batter) without a hit; he went hitless for three innings;
certain to end in failure and disappointment; a no-win situation;
out of power; especially having been unsuccessful in an election; now the Democrats are out;
having no points scores; a scoreless inning;
acting to defeat its own purpose; it is self-defeating...to ignore the progress of events;
of persons; marked by failure to realize full potentialities; unfulfilled and uneasy men; unrealized dreams and ambitions;
not one of the first three in a race or competition;
having no wins; the team had a very disappointing winless season;
of a quantity that can fulfill a need or requirement but without being abundant; sufficient food;
sufficient for the purpose; an adequate income; the food was adequate; a decent wage; enough food; food enough;
sufficient to provide comfort; a comfortable salary;
of a quantity not able to fulfill a need or requirement; insufficient funds;
no longer sufficient; supplies are low; our funds are depleted;
not sufficient to meet a need; an inadequate income; a poor salary; money is short; on short rations; food is in short supply; short on experience;
containing little excess; a lean budget; a skimpy allowance;
less than the correct or legal or full amount often deliberately so; a light pound; a scant cup of sugar; regularly gives short weight;
short; eleven is one shy of a dozen;
containing sugar; he eats too much sugary food;
encrusted with sugar or syrup; candied grapefruit peel;
with honey added;
resembling honey;
with sweetening added;
not containing sugar;
with no sugar added;
not made sweet;
of or characteristic of high rank or importance; a superior ruler;
(used of behavior or attitude) characteristic of those who treat others with condescension;
standing above others in quality or position; people in high places; the high priest; eminent members of the community;
greatest in importance or degree or significance or achievement; our greatest statesmen; the country's leading poet; a preeminent archeologist;
at an elevated level in rank or importance; a high-level official; a high-level corporate briefing; upper-level management;
majestic in manner or bearing; superior to mundane matters; his majestic presence; olympian detachment; olympian beauty and serene composure;
of higher rank or status or value;
superior in rank or accomplishment; the upper half of the class;
of or characteristic of low rank or importance;
low or inferior in station or quality; a humble cottage; a lowly parish priest; a modest man of the people; small beginnings;
fairly poor to not very good; has an indifferent singing voice; has indifferent qualifications for the job;
at a low level in rank or importance; a low-level job; low-level discussions;
intermediate in rank or position; middle-level management;
decisively surpassed by something else so as to appear to be of a lower class;
of high or superior quality or performance; superior wisdom derived from experience; superior math students;
of the highest quality; an ace reporter; a crack shot; a first-rate golfer; a super party; played top-notch tennis; an athlete in tiptop condition; she is absolutely tops;
unusually good; outstanding; a banner year for the company;
selected or chosen for special qualifications; the blue-ribbon event of the season;
exceptionally good; a boss hand at carpentry; his brag cornfield;
of surpassing excellence; a brilliant performance; a superb actor;
first-rate; a capital fellow; a capital idea;
of superior grade; choice wines; prime beef; prize carnations; quality paper; select peaches;
very good;of the highest quality; made an excellent speech; the school has excellent teachers; a first-class mind;
of the highest quality or value; gilt-edged securities; gilt-edged credentials;
highest in quality;
modified to give superior performance; a high-performance car;
distinguished from others in excellence; did outstanding work in human relations; an outstanding war record;
having or reflecting superior quality or value; premium gasoline at a premium price;
absolutely first class and genuine; pukka sahib; pukka quarters with a swarm of servants;
marked by exceptional merit; had shining virtues and few faults; a shining example;
excellent or splendid; that's a perfectly spiffing idea;
highest in excellence or achievement; supreme among musicians; a supreme endxxeavor; supreme courage;
excellent; best possible;
exceeding or surpassing usual limits especially in excellence;
of a quality adequate for use in weapons (especially in weapons of mass destruction); weapons-grade plutonium; weapons-grade anthrax;
skillfully constructed;
of low or inferior quality;
below average in quality or performance; a bad chess player; a bad recital;
(used of metals) consisting of or alloyed with inferior metal; base coins of aluminum; a base metal;
of very poor quality; flimsy;
not of the highest quality or sophistication;
cheap and shoddy; cheapjack moviemaking...that feeds on the low taste of the mob- Judith Crist;
of low or inferior quality or value; of what coarse metal ye are molded- Shakespeare; produced...the common cloths used by the poorer population;
made coarse or crude by lack of skill;
of the kind or quality used in commerce; average or inferior; commercial grade of beef; commercial oxalic acid;
of very poor quality or condition; deplorable housing conditions in the inner city; woeful treatment of the accused; woeful errors of judgment;
(usually preceded by no) lower in quality; no less than perfect;
of inferior quality;
moderate to inferior in quality; they improved the quality from mediocre to above average;
(British informal) very poor in quality; ropey food; a ropey performance;
inferior in size or quality; scrawny cattle; scrubby cut-over pine; old stunted thorn trees;
of inferior status or quality; a second-class citizen; second-class accommodations;
of lesser quality than second-rate;
used of beef; usable but inferior;
having an orbit farther from the sun than the Earth's orbit; Mars and Jupiter are the closest in of the superior planets;
having an orbit between the sun and the Earth's orbit; Mercury and Venus are inferior planets;
lying immediately above or on something else;
lying or leaning on something else; an incumbent geological formation;
placed on or over something else; an overlying image;
lying or resting on and exerting pressure on something else; superincumbent layers of dead plants cut off the air and arrested decomposition;
lying nearby but lower; hills and subjacent valleys;
located beneath or below;
written or printed above and to one side of another character;
written or printed below and to one side of another character;
written or printed immediately following another character and aligned with it;
