a slow or gradual disappearance;
ceasing to exist; he regretted the disappearance of Greek from school curricula; what was responsible for the disappearance of the rainforest?; the disappearance of resistance at very low temperatures;
a stroke of ill fortune; a calamitous event; a period marked by adversities;
something that causes or entails suffering; I cannot think it a hardship that more indulgence is allowed to men than to women- James Boswell; the many hardships of frontier life;
a bad experience; the school of hard knocks;
an unexpected and inexplicable change in something (in a situation or a person's behavior, etc.); the vagaries of the weather; his wealth fluctuates with the vagaries of the stock market; he has dealt with human vagaries for many years;
an instance of change; the rate or magnitude of change;
a variation in circumstances or fortune at different times in your life or in the development of something; the project was subject to the usual vicissitudes of exploratory research;
(chemistry) variability in chemical composition without variation in crystalline form;
contact by fitting together; the engagement of the clutch; the meshing of gears;
a light sharp contact (usually with something flexible); he gave it a flick with his finger; he felt the flick of a whip;
the striking of one body against another;
an impact (as from a collision); the bump threw him off the bicycle;
a forceful impact that makes a loud noise;
a sudden jarring impact; the door closed with a jolt; all the jars and jolts were smoothed out by the shock absorbers;
the physical coming together of two or more things; contact with the pier scraped paint from the hull;
loss of military equipment;
loss of military equipment in battle;
loss of military equipment in field operations;
a decrease of military personnel or equipment;
a casualty to military personnel resulting from combat;
a wound that would cause an English soldier to be sent home from service abroad;
a wound that does not damage important internal organs or shatter any bones;
military personnel lost by death or capture;
personnel that are sacrificed (e.g., surrendered or lost in order to gain an objective);
a single complete execution of a periodically repeated phenomenon; a year constitutes a cycle of the seasons;
the complete cycle of events in the heart from the beginning of one heart beat to the beginning of the next; an electrical impulse conducted through the heart muscle that constricts the atria which is followed by constriction of the ventricles; the cardiac cycle can be shown on an electrocardiogram;
a cycle (of expansion and compression) of an idealized reversible heat engine that does work without loss of heat;
one complete cycle of operations (as by a computer); it was not possible to complete the computation in a single pass;
an event that repeats; the events today were a repeat of yesterday's;
several repetitions of a melodic phrase in different keys;
a periodically repeated sequence of events; a cycle of reprisal and retaliation;
a never-ending cycle of activities and events (especially when they seem to have little purpose); if we lose the election the whole legislative merry-go-round will have to start over;
(Hinduism and Buddhism) the endless cycle of birth and suffering and death and rebirth;
something (especially a game) that is played again;
happening again (especially at regular intervals); the return of spring;
a reappearance of an earlier characteristic;
an unexpected but vivid recurrence of a past experience (especially a recurrence of the effects of an hallucinogenic drug taken much earlier);
the daily event of the sun rising above the horizon;
the daily event of the sun sinking below the horizon;
a broad and deep undulation of the ocean;
waves breaking on the shore;
the wave that spreads behind a boat as it moves forward; the motorboat's wake capsized the canoe;
the movement or sound of water; the swash of waves on the beach;
a small wave on the surface of a liquid;
(physics) a wave that is hypothesized to propagate gravity and to travel at the speed of light;
a wave whose waveform resembles a sine curve;
(physics) a regular periodic variation in value about a mean;
(electronics) an oscillation of small amplitude imposed on top of a steady value;
(physics) a movement up and down or back and forth;
a small irregular movement;
a wave motion; the fluctuations of the sea;
a wave on the surface of a lake or landlocked bay; caused by atmospheric or seismic disturbances;
(physics) a quantum of energy or quasiparticle that can be propagated as a traveling wave in nonlinear systems and is neither preceded nor followed by another such disturbance; does not obey the superposition principle and does not dissipate; soliton waves can travel long distances with little loss of energy or structure;
a wave (as a sound wave in a chamber or an electromagnetic wave in a transmission line) in which the ratio of its instantaneous amplitude at one point to that at any other point does not vary with time;
a wave in which the medium moves in the direction of propagation of the wave;
(acoustics) a wave that transmits sound;
a sound wave that is transmitted via air;
(physics) a short-lived oscillation in a system caused by a sudden change of voltage or current or load;
the shape of a wave illustrated graphically by plotting the values of the period quantity against time;
a region of high pressure travelling through a gas at a high velocity; the explosion created a shock wave;
an explosive sound caused by the shock wave of an airplane traveling faster than the speed of sound; a sonic boom follows an aircraft as a wake follows a ship;
the undulating movement of the surface of the open sea;
a wave that lifts the surface of the water or ground;
a large sea wave;
a wave resulting from the periodic flow of the tides that is caused by the gravitational attraction of the moon and sun;
an unusual (and often destructive) rise of water along the seashore caused by a storm or a combination of wind and high tide;
an overwhelming manifestation of some emotion or phenomenon; a tidal wave of nausea; the flood of letters hit him with the force of a tidal wave; a tidal wave of crime;
a cataclysm resulting from a destructive sea wave caused by an earthquake or volcanic eruption; a colossal tsunami destroyed the Minoan civilization in minutes;
a long heavy sea wave as it advances towards the shore;
motion that recurs over and over and the period of time required for each recurrence remains the same;
a periodic motion in which the displacement is either symmetrical about a point or is the sum of such motions;
(geology) a horizontal dislocation;
a movement back from an impact;
rebounding from an impact (or series of impacts);
an occurrence of rebounding or springing back;
the backward jerk of a gun when it is fired;
the movement of a read/write head to a specific data track on a disk;
a twisting squeeze; gave the wet cloth a wring;
the maximum movement available to a pivoted or reciprocating piece by a cam;
the stroke of an engine piston moving away from the crankshaft;
the stroke of an engine piston moving toward the crankshaft;
a movement in a new direction; the turning of the wind;
a jerky pulling movement;
wavelike motion; a gentle rising and falling in the manner of waves;
one of a series of ridges that moves across the surface of a liquid (especially across a large body of water);
a long curling sea wave;
a wave that is blown by the wind so its crest is broken and appears white;
something that rises rapidly; a wave of emotion swept over him; there was a sudden wave of buying before the market closed; a wave of conservatism in the country led by the hard right;
an accident that destroys a ship at sea;
(nautical) the event of a boat accidentally turning over in the water;
designated event that concludes a contest (especially a race); excitement grew as the finish neared; my horse was several lengths behind at the finish; the winner is the team with the most points at the finish;
the finish of a contest in which the score is tied and the winner is undecided; the game ended in a draw; their record was 3 wins, 6 losses and a tie;
a tie in a race;
drawing position in chess: any of a player's possible moves would place his king in check;
in general, any very close finish; in particular, a finish of a race in which the contestants are so close together that the winner must be determined from a photograph taken at the instant of finishing;
a finish in second place (as in a race);
a finish in third place (as in a race);
a victory (as in a race or other competition); he was happy to get the win;
a finish in first place (as in a race);
