made troubled or apprehensive or distressed in appearance; his face was clouded with unhappiness;
afflicted with or marked by anxious uneasiness or trouble or grief; too upset to say anything; spent many disquieted moments; distressed about her son's leaving home; lapsed into disturbed sleep; worried parents; a worried frown; one last worried check of the sleeping children;
facing or experiencing financial trouble or difficulty; distressed companies need loans and technical advice; financially hard-pressed Mexican hotels are lowering their prices; we were hard put to meet the mortgage payment; found themselves in a bad way financially;
marked by distress; a fraught mother-daughter relationship;
tormented or harassed by nightmares or unreasonable fears; hagridden...by visions of an imminent heaven or hell upon earth- C.S.Lewis;
showing emotional affliction or disquiet; her expression became progressively more haunted;
infested with moths;
suffering severe physical strain or distress; he dropped out of the race, clearly distressed and having difficulty breathing;
engaged in a struggle to overcome especially poverty or obscurity; a financially struggling theater; struggling artists;
troubled by pain or loss; suffering refugees;
full of trouble; these are troublous times;
not beset by troubles or disturbance or distress; seemed untroubled by doubts of any kind; untroubled sleep; a kind untroubled face;
free of trouble and worry and care; the carefree joys of childhood; carefree millionaires, untroubled financially;
characterized by freedom from troubling thoughts (especially guilt); a clear conscience; regarded her questioner with clear untroubled eyes;
untroubled by dreams; a sound and dreamless sleep;
without problems or difficulties; NASA reported a trouble-free launch;
easy in mind; not worried; the prisoner seems entirely unconcerned as to the outcome of the examination;
untroubled by interference or disturbance; he could pursue his studies undisturbed;
not interfered with, disturbed, or harmed;
consistent with fact or reality; not false; the story is true; it is undesirable to believe a proposition when there is no ground whatever for supposing it true- B. Russell; the true meaning of the statement;
being or reflecting the essential or genuine character of something; her actual motive; a literal solitude like a desert- G.K.Chesterton; a genuine dilemma;
of a proposition; necessarily true or logically certain;
conforming to truth; I wouldn't have told you this if it weren't so; a truthful statement;
infallible or unfailing; a sure (or true) sign of one's commitment;
not in accordance with the fact or reality or actuality; gave false testimony under oath; false tales of bravery;
intentionally untrue; a mendacious statement;
plausible but false; a specious claim; spurious inferences;
concocted with intent to deceive; trumped-up charges;
not according with the facts; unfortunately the statement was simply untrue;
inclined to believe or confide readily; full of trust; great brown eye, true and trustful- Nordhoff & Hall;
willing to entrust personal matters; first she was suspicious, then she became confiding;
not suspicious; deceiving the unsuspecting public;
having or showing distrust; a man of distrustful nature; my experience...in other fields of law has made me distrustful of rules of thumb generally- B.N.Cardozo; vigilant and distrustful superintendence- Thomas Jefferson;
believing the worst of human nature and motives; having a sneering disbelief in e.g. selflessness of others;
marked by or given to doubt; a skeptical attitude; a skeptical listener;
suspicious or unduly suspicious or fearful of being displaced by a rival; a jealous lover;
openly distrustful and unwilling to confide;
(used of men) having deep-seated distrust of women;
unduly suspicious;
worthy of trust or belief; a trustworthy report; an experienced and trustworthy traveling companion;
conforming to fact and therefore worthy of belief; an authentic account by an eyewitness; reliable information;
having an acceptable credit rating; a responsible borrower;
worthy of being depended on; a dependable worker; an honest working stiff; a reliable sourcSFLe of information; he was true to his word; I would be true for there are those who trust me;
based on trust;
(of persons) worthy of trust or confidence; a sure (or trusted) friend;
not worthy of trust or belief; an untrustworthy person;
characterized by insincerity or deceit; evasive; a devious character; shifty eyes;
(of businesses and businessmen) unscrupulous; a shady operation;
not to be trusted; how extraordinarily slippery a liar the camera is- James Agee;
of a tire; having an inner tube;
of a tire; not needing an inner tube;
having tucked or being tucked; tightly tucked blankets; a fancy tucked shirt;
lacking tucks or not being tucked; the sheet came untucked; plain untucked shirt front;
moved around an axis or center;
being in such a position that top and bottom are reversed; a quotation mark is sometimes called an inverted comma; an upside-down cake;
having been turned so that the bottom is no longer the bottom; an overturned car; the upset pitcher of milk; sat on an upturned bucket;
turned inside out and resewn; the reversed collar looked as good as new;
turned in a circle around an axis;
with the inside surface on the outside;
not turned; left no stone unturned;
of fabric or clothing;
of objects having a top and bottom;
exhibiting the qualities or characteristics that identify a group or kind or category; a typical American girl; a typical suburban community; the typical car owner drives 10,000 miles a year; a painting typical of the Impressionist school; a typical romantic poem; a typical case of arteritis;
being or serving as an illustration of a type; the free discussion that is emblematic of democracy; an action exemplary of his conduct;
serving to represent or typify; representative moviegoers; a representative modern play;
often used as intensifiers; a regular morass of details; a regular nincompoop; he's a veritable swine;
conforming to definitive criteria; the horseshoe crab is not a true crab; Pythagoras was the first true mathematician;
not representative of a group, class, or type; a group that is atypical of the target audience; a class of atypical mosses; atypical behavior is not the accepted type of response that we expect from children;
not exemplifying a class; I soon tumbled to the fact that my weekends were atypical; behavior quite unrepresentative (or atypical) of the profession;
with hand brought forward and up from below shoulder level; an underhand pitch; an underhand stroke;
with hand brought forward and down from above shoulder level; an overhand pitch; an overhand stroke;
with the arm swung round at shoulder height; round-arm bowling;
on the surface; surface materials of the moon;
on or above the surface of the ground; aboveground nuclear testing; surface instruments for detecting oil deposits; surface transportation;
constructed at ground level; grade-constructed accesses to the freeway;
(of mines and mining) worked from the exposed surface; opencast mining; an opencut iron mine;
beneath the surface; subsurface materials of the moon;
under the level of the ground; belowground storage areas; underground caverns;
beneath the surface of the sea;
beneath the surface of the water; submerged rocks;
being or operating under the surface of the earth; subterranean passages; a subsurface flow of water;
located or originating from above; an overhead crossing;
capable of being immersed in water or functioning while submerged; a submersible pump; a submergible electric frying pan;
not submersible or submergible;
filled with or marked by tears; tearful eyes; tearful entreaties;
filled or brimming with tears; swimming eyes; sorrow made the eyes of many grow liquid;
having eyes blurred as with tears; sad and misty-eyed;
with eyes full of tears;
liable to sniffle;
liable to weep easily;
free from tears;
not shedding tears; dry sobs; with dry eyes;
of trade unions; the union movement; union negotiations; a union-shop clause in the contract;
requiring union membership; a closed shop;
being a member of or formed into a labor union; organized labor; unionized workers; a unionized shop;
not belonging to or not allowing affiliation with a trade union; nonunion carpenters; a nonunion contractor;
not requiring union membership; an open shop employs nonunion workers;
not affiliated in a trade union; the workers in the plant were unorganized;
producing only one offspring at a time;
producing more than one offspring at a time;
