speak in a blustering or scornful manner; A puffing kind of man;
show unwillingness towards; he declined to join the group on a hike;
give an affirmative reply to; respond favorably to; I cannot accept your invitation; I go for this resolution;
accept despite lack of complete satisfaction; We settled for a lower price;
consent in writing to pay money to a trade union for political use;
refuse to pay a levy to a union for political use;
reject outright and bluntly; She snubbed his proposal;
formally reject or disavow a formerly held belief, usually under pressure; He retracted his earlier statements about his religion; She abjured her beliefs;
take back what one has said; He swallowed his words;
state something incorrectly; You misstated my position;
make a retreat from an earlier commitment or activity; We'll have to crawfish out from meeting with him; He backed out of his earlier promise; The aggressive investment company pulled in its horns;
cancel officially; He revoked the ban on smoking; lift an embargo; vacate a death sentence;
fail to fulfill a promise or obligation; She backed out of her promise;
make invalid for use; cancel cheques or tickets;
place into brackets; Please bracket this remark;
remove from a list; Cross the name of the dead person off the list;
bar from attention or consideration; She dismissed his advances;
count again; We had to recount all the votes after an accusation of fraud was made;
disregard; She passed off the insult;
cease to consider; put out of judicial consideration; This case is dismissed!;
treat with contemptuous disregard; flout the rules;
refuse to acknowledge; He turns a blind eye to the injustices in his office;
deal with a problem by laughing or pretending to be amused by it; She laughs away all these problems;
consent to, give permission; She permitted her son to visit her estranged husband; I won't let the police search her basement; I cannot allow you to see your exam;
allow the presence of or allow (an activity) without opposing or prohibiting; We don't allow dogs here; Children are not permitted beyond this point; We cannot tolerate smoking in the hospital;
grant authorization or clearance for; Clear the manuscript for publication; The rock star never authorized this slanderous biography;
approve or sanction officially;
authorize by certificate;
to agree or express agreement; The Maestro assented to the request for an encore;
consent reluctantly;
withhold assent; Several Republicans dissented;
be of different opinions; I beg to differ!; She disagrees with her husband on many questions;
disagree violently; We clashed over the new farm policies;
be in accord; be in agreement; We agreed on the terms of the settlement; I can't agree with you!; I hold with those who say life is sacred; Both philosophers concord on this point;
be in agreement; We never saw eye to eye on this question;
be willing to concede; I grant you this much;
adopt as a belief; I subscribe to your view on abortion;
give sanction to; I approve of his educational policies;
give religious sanction to, such as through on oath; sanctify the marriage;
approve officially; The list of speakers must be visaed;
deem wrong or inappropriate; I disapprove of her child rearing methods;
express or raise an objection or protest or criticism or express dissent; She never objected to the amount of work her boss charged her with; When asked to drive the truck, she objected that she did not have a driver's license;
take exception to; he demurred at my suggestion to work on Saturday;
raise a formal objection in a court of law;
ask for identification; The illegal immigrant was challenged by the border guard;
challenge in turn; The authentication was counterchallenged;
raise trivial objections;
conduct an interview in television, newspaper, and radio reporting;
try to learn someone's opinions and intentions; I have to sound out the new professor;
discuss formally with (somebody) for the purpose of an evaluation; We interviewed the job candidates;
go for an interview in the hope of being hired; The job candidate interviewed everywhere;
avoid or try to avoid fulfilling, answering, or performing (duties, questions, or issues) ; He dodged the issue; she skirted the problem; They tend to evade their responsibilities; he evaded the questions skillfully;
dodge, avoid answering, or take for granted; beg the question; beg the point in the discussion;
evade the truth of a point or question by raising irrelevant objections;
fail to experience; Fortunately, I missed the hurricane;
escape potentially unpleasant consequences; get away with a forbidden action; She gets away with murder!; I couldn't get out from under these responsibilities;
use cunning or deceit to escape or avoid; The con man always evades;
avoid something unpleasant or laborious; You cannot bypass these rules!;
stay clear from; keep away from; keep out of the way of someone or something; Her former friends now avoid her;
refrain from entering or walking onto; keep off the grass; stay off the premises;
avoid dealing with; She shirks her duties;
avoid having to deal with some unpleasant task; I shy away from this task;
avoid and stay away from deliberately; stay clear of;
deal with (something unpleasant) head on; You must confront your problems; He faced the terrible consequences of his mistakes;
discuss the pros and cons of an issue;
subject to prolonged examination, discussion, or deliberation; vex the subject of the death penalty;
think about carefully; weigh; They considered the possibility of a strike; Turn the proposal over in your mind;
engage in deep thought, consideration, or debate; I wrestled with this decision for years;
discuss lightly; We bandied around these difficult questions;
preside over; John moderated the discussion;
speak with others about (something) ; talk (something) over in detail; have a discussion; We discussed our household budget;
speak of in an irreverent or impious manner; blaspheme God;
talk at length and formally about a topic; The speaker dissertated about the social politics in 18th century England;
overthrow by argument, evidence, or proof; The speaker refuted his opponent's arguments;
give a defence or refutation of (a charge) or in (an argument) ; The defendant answered to all the charges of the prosecution;
speak in response; He countered with some very persuasive arguments;
answer adequately or successfully; The lawyer fielded all questions from the press;
react verbally; She didn't want to answer; answer the question; We answered that we would accept the invitation;
answer back in an impudent or insolent manner; don't sass me!; The teacher punished the students who were sassing all morning;
answer back;
declare untrue; contradict; He denied the allegations; She denied that she had taken money;
reject as untrue, unfounded, or unjust; She repudiated the accusations;
refuse to accept or believe; He denied his fatal illness;
refuse to recognize or acknowledge; Peter denied Jesus;
declare to be true or admit the existence or reality or truth of; He admitted his errors; She acknowledged that she might have forgotten;
acknowledge freely and openly; He makes no bones about the fact that he is gay;
admit or acknowledge a wrongdoing or error; the writer of the anonymous letter owned up after they identified his handwriting;
declare to be obsolete;
declare a child to be illegitimate;
admit as valid; The court sustained the motion;
admit (to a wrongdoing) ; She confessed that she had taken the money;
confess to God in the presence of a priest, as in the Catholic faith;
be emphatic or resolute and refuse to budge; I must insist!;
refuse to abandon one's opinion or belief;
hold stubbornly to a position; The wife hunkered down and the husband's resistance began to break down;
confess to a punishable or reprehensible deed, usually under pressure;
practice as a profession, teach, or claim to be knowledgeable about; She professes organic chemistry;
admit openly and bluntly; make no bones about;
refuse to acknowledge; disclaim knowledge of; responsibility for, or association with; Her husband disavowed her after 30 years of marriage and six children;
authenticate, affirm to be true, genuine, or correct, as in an official capacity; I attest this signature;
