make amendments to; amend the document;
mark with one's signature; write one's name (on) ; She signed the letter and sent it off; Please sign here;
sign with a mark instead of a name;
sign at the bottom of (a document) ;
append one's signature to; They inked the contract;
mark with one's signature; The author autographed his book;
mark with one's initials;
add one's signature to after another's to attest authenticity; You must countersign on this line of the contract;
sign in the presence of witnesses; The President executed the treaty;
sign as evidence of legal transfer; endorse cheques;
sign and endorse (another person's signature) , as for a loan;
provide (a passport) with a visa;
make a dot or dots;
register electronically; They recorded her singing;
erase (a magnetic storage device) ;
record data on a computer; boot-up instructions are written on the hard disk;
write new data on top of existing data and thus erase the previously existing data; overwrite that file;
record with a tape recorder;
record before presentation, as of a broadcast;
make a record of additions to a collection, such as a library;
display, as of records in sports games;
wipe out digitally or magnetically recorded information; Who erased the files form my hard disk?;
to perform and record a sale on a cash register; Sally rang up Eve's purchase of tomatoes;
make a record of; set down in permanent form;
record in a ship's manifest; each passenger must be manifested;
write, engrave, or print as a lasting record;
record in chronological order; make a historical record;
state; set forth one's reasons;
set forth beforehand, often as an explanation; He premised these remarks so that his readers might understand;
place in a container for keeping records; File these bills, please;
record in a public office or in a court of law; file for divorce; file a complaint;
register the trademark of; The company trademarked their new gadget;
record in detail; The parents documented every step of their child's development;
enter into a log, as on ships and planes;
record a distance travelled; on planes and cars;
make a film or photograph of something; take a scene; shoot a movie;
record on videotape;
record on photographic film; I photographed the scene of the accident; She snapped a picture of the President;
photograph again; Please retake that scene;
shoot again; We had to reshoot that scene 24 times;
take an x-ray of something or somebody; The doctor x-rayed my chest;
make underscoring marks;
draw a line or lines underneath to call attention to;
put quote marks around; Here the author is quoting his colleague;
notch a surface to record something;
write by means of a keyboard with types; type the acceptance letter, please;
use a shift key on a keyboard; She could not shift so all her letters are written in lower case;
write by hand; You should handwrite the note to your guests;
hit the backspace key on a computer or typewriter keyboard; To erase, you must backspace;
type with a full space between lines;
type with two empty spaces between lines;
type without looking at the keyboard;
make explicit; specify in detail; You should spell out your demands;
write briefly or hurriedly; write a short note of;
write down quickly without much attention to detail;
describe roughly or briefly or give the main points or summary of; sketch the outline of the book; outline his ideas;
indicate roughly; We sketched out our plan;
exchange messages; My Russian pen pal and I have been corresponding for several years;
communicate (with) in writing; Write her soon, please!;
send cables, wires, or telegrams;
transmit messages via radio waves; he radioed for help;
send something via a facsimile machine; Can you fax me the report right away?;
give a summary (of) ; he summed up his results; I will now summarize;
give an abstract (of) ;
make a summary (of) ;
make a summary or abstract of a legal document and inscribe it in a list;
place on the docket for legal action; Only 5 of the 120 cases docketed were tried;
summarize briefly; Let's recapitulate the main ideas;
go back over; retrograde arguments;
express in words; He said that he wanted to marry her; tell me what is bothering you; state your opinion; state your name;
state as one's opinion or judgement; declare; I say let's forget this whole business;
express with difficulty; I managed to get out a few words;
state emphatically and authoritatively; He declared that he needed more money to carry out the task he was charged with;
state freely; The teacher professed that he was not generous when it came to giving good grades;
make a declaration (of dutiable goods) to a customs official; Do you have anything to declare?;
to declare or affirm solemnly and formally as true; Before God I swear I am innocent;
affirm or avow formally or solemnly; The suspect protested his innocence;
say yes to;
affirm once again; He reaffirmed his faith in the church;
strengthen or make more firm; The witnesses confirmed the victim's account;
attach or append a legal verification to (a pleading or petition) ;
give evidence for;
give circumstantial evidence for;
confirm again; You must reconfirm your flight reservations;
make a deposition; declare under oath;
present and urge reasons in opposition;
to stress, single out as important; Dr. Jones emphasizes exercise in addition to a change in diet;
emphasize by putting heavy stress on or by moving to the front of the sentence; Speakers topicalize more often than they realize; The object of the sentence is topicalized in what linguists call Yiddish Movement;
emphasize, especially by identification; This novel points up the racial problems in England;
make clear by special emphasis and try to convince somebody of something; drive home a point or an argument; I'm trying to drive home these basic ideas;
give extra weight to (a communication) ; Her gesture emphasized her words;
give testimony in a court of law;
give personal assurance; guarantee; Will he vouch for me?;
provide evidence for; The blood test showed that he was the father; Her behavior testified to her incompetence;
constitute reasonable evidence for; A restaurant bill presumes the consumption of food;
advance evidence for;
report or maintain; He alleged that he was the victim of a crime; He said it was too late to intervene in the war; The registrar says that I owe the school money;
make an allegation in an action or other legal proceeding, especially answer the previous pleading of the other party by denying facts therein stated or by alleging new facts;
enter a demurrer;
state categorically;
