suggest as a logically necessary consequence; in logic;
imply as a possibility; The evidence suggests a need for more clarification;
imply or suggest; Your remarks make me out to be stupid;
involve as a necessary condition of consequence; as in logic; solving the problem is predicated on understanding it well;
have as a meaning; multi-denotes many;
denote or connote; maisonmeans housein French; An example sentence would show what this word means;
be a sign or indication of; Her smile denoted that she agreed;
convey or express a meaning; These words mean nothing to me!; What does his strange behavior signify?;
indicate or signify; I'm afraid this spells trouble!;
practice sophistry; change the meaning of or be vague about in order to mislead or deceive; Don't twist my words;
refer to something with a euphemism;
speak unintelligibly in or as if in religious ecstasy; The parishioners spoke in tongues;
give voice to; He voiced his concern;
make less strong or intense; soften; Tone down that aggressive letter; The author finally tamed some of his potentially offensive statements;
make known to the public information that was previously known only to a few people or that was meant to be kept a secret; The auction house would not disclose the price at which the van Gogh had sold; The actress won't reveal how old she is; bring out the truth; he broke the news to her; unwrap the evidence in the murder case;
explore and expose misconduct and scandals concerning public figures; This reporter was well-known for his muckraking;
cause to be revealed and jeopardized; The story blew their cover; The double agent was blown by the other side;
be made known; be disclosed or revealed; The truth will out;
reveal (something) about somebody's identity or lifestyle; The gay actor was outed last week; Someone outed a CIA agent;
to state openly and publicly one's homosexuality; This actor outed last year;
reveal the true nature of; The journal article unmasked the corrupt politician;
produce or disclose suddenly or unexpectedly; He sprang these news on me just as I was leaving;
be released or become known; of news; News of her death broke in the morning;
be leaked; The news leaked out despite his secrecy;
reveal unintentionally; Her smile betrayed her true feelings;
reveal in private; tell confidentially;
relieve oneself of troubling information;
give information that compromises others;
inform or spy (for the police) ;
tell anonymously; The news were leaked to the paper;
divulge confidential information or secrets; Be careful--his secretary talks;
refrain from divulging sensitive information; keep quiet about confidential information; Don't tell him any secrets--he cannot keep his mouth shut!;
orally recite the letters of or give the spelling of; How do you spell this word?We had to spell out our names for the police officer;
spell incorrectly;
give an interpretation or explanation to;
interpret the moral meaning of; moralize a story;
interpret (a text or an artwork) by the method of deconstructing;
interpret from a different viewpoint;
serve as a commentator, as in sportscasting;
interpret falsely;
make plain and comprehensible; He explained the laws of physics to his students;
give reasons for; Can you account for all these absences?;
explain with reference to nature;
make clear and (more) comprehensible; clarify the mystery surrounding her death;
make obscure or unclear;
articulate; either verbally or with a cry, shout, or noise; She expressed her anger; He uttered a curse;
utter indistinctly; She swallowed the last words of her speech;
cause to be heard or known; express or utter; raise a shout; raise a protest; raise a sad cry;
utter or tell; not breathe a word;
utter with seeming casualness; drop a hint; drop names";
express without restraint; The woman poured out her frustrations as the judge listened;
make a cat-like sound;
deliver verbally; He got off the best line I've heard in a long time;
express in speech; She talks a lot of nonsense; This depressed patient does not verbalize;
be verbose; This lawyer verbalizes and is rather tedious;
utter with a puff of air; whiff out a prayer;
discuss or mention; They spoke of many things;
utter while crying;
give expression to; She showed her disappointment;
manifest or show; This student gives promise of real creativity; The office gave evidence of tampering;
make apparent by one's mood or behavior; She exudes great confidence;
give expression or utterance to; She vented her anger; The graduates gave vent to cheers;
talk in a monotonous voice;
conclude by reasoning; in logic;
conclude from evidence; I gather you have not done your homework;
repeat aloud from memory; she recited a poem; The pupil recited his lesson for the day;
recite or repeat a fixed text; Say grace; She said her Hail Mary;
recite volubly or extravagantly; He could recite the names of all the chemical elements;
give or make a list of; name individually; give the names of; List the states west of the Mississippi;
specify individually; She enumerated the many obstacles she had encountered; The doctor recited the list of possible side effects of the drug;
place on a list of items; itemize one's tax deductions;
enumerate; We must number the names of the great mathematicians;
decide upon or fix definitely; fix the variables; specify the parameters;
mention and identify by name; name your accomplices!;
set anew; They re-set the date on the clock;
count backwards; before detonating a bomb, for example;
name or recite the numbers in ascending order; The toddler could count to 100;
determine the number or amount of; Can you count the books on your shelf?; Count your change;
count wrongly;
conduct a census; They censused the deer in the forest;
give numbers to; You should number the pages of the thesis;
number the pages of a book or manuscript;
determine the sum of; Add all the people in this town to those of the neighboring town;
keep score, as in games;
refer (a matter or legal case) to another committee or authority or court for decision;
be dared to do something and attempt it;
be dared to do something and not attempt it;
show consideration for; take into account; You must consider her age; The judge considered the offender's youth and was lenient;
utter with tense vocal chords;
pronounce (vowels) by bringing the tongue closer to the roof of the mouth; raise your o;
articulate in a very careful and rhythmic way;
pronounce a consonant with the tongue against the palate;
pronounce with a lowered velum; She nasalizes all her vowels;
speak nasally or through the nose; In this part of the country, people tend to nasalize;
pronounce a word incorrectly; She mispronounces many Latinate words;
utter platitudes; The candidate platitudinized and bored the audience;
utter tsk,tut,or tut-tut,as in disapproval;
pronounce with aspiration; of stop sounds;
utter with vibrating vocal chords;
let something be known; Tell them that you will be late;
