take on duties or office; accede to the throne;
become king or queen; She ascended to the throne after the King's death;
take on titles, offices, duties, responsibilities; When will the new President assume office?;
assume anew; resume a title; resume an office; resume one's duties;
act in an official capacity in a ceremony or religious ritual, such as a wedding; Who officiated at your wedding?;
give up or retire from a position; The Secretary of the Navy will leave office next month; The chairman resigned over the financial scandal;
give up one's career just as one becomes very successful; The financial consultant topped out at age 40 because he was burned out;
leave school or an educational program prematurely; Many students drop out because they are not prepared for our challenging program;
withdraw from established society, especially because of disillusion with conventional values; She hasn't heard from her brother in years--he dropped out after moving to California;
remove oneself from an association with or participation in; She wants to leave; The teenager left home; She left her position with the Red Cross; He left the Senate after two terms; after 20 years with the same company, she pulled up stakes;
assume an office, duty, or title; When will the new President take office?;
put into an office or a position; the new president was installed immediately after the election;
place ceremoniously or formally in an office or position; there was a ceremony to induct the president of the Academy;
admit as a member; We were inducted into the honor society;
invite someone to one's house; Can I invite you for dinner on Sunday night?;
have as a guest; I invited them to a restaurant;
lose office or power; The government fell overnight; The Qing Dynasty fell with Sun Yat-sen;
deprive of status or authority; he was divested of his rights and his title; They disinvested themselves of their rights;
assign to a post; put into a post; The newspaper posted him in Timbuktu;
assign the roles of (a movie or a play) to actors; Who cast this beautiful movie?;
appoint to a clerical posts; he was ordained in the Church;
be ordained; enter the Christian ministry; She took orders last month;
provide with power and authority; They vested the council with special rights;
furnish with power or authority; of kings or emperors;
train for a social environment; The children must be properly socialized;
educate for a future role or function; He is grooming his son to become his successor; The prince was prepared to become King one day; They trained him to be a warrior;
give an education to; We must educate our youngsters better;
educate persons of both sexes together;
educate in or as if in a school; The children are schooled at great cost to their parents in private institutions;
educate (one's children) at home instead of sending (them) to a school; The parents are home-schooling their daughter;
teach or refine to be discriminative in taste or judgment; Cultivate your musical taste; Train your tastebuds; She is well schooled in poetry;
make less natural or innocent; Their manners had sophisticated the young girls;
take part in social activities; interact with others; He never socializes with his colleagues; The old man hates to socialize;
establish communication with someone; did you finally connect with your long-lost cousin?;
establish a rapport or relationship; The President of this university really connects with the faculty;
be a social swinger; socialize a lot;
be on friendly terms with someone, as if with a brother, especially with an enemy;
rub elbows with; He hobnobs with the best of society;
spend time in a certain location or with certain people; She hangs out at the corner cafe;
accept people into an exclusive society or group, usually with some rite; African men are initiated when they reach puberty;
admit again or anew; After paying a penalty, the player was readmitted;
invest with regal power; enthrone; The prince was crowned in Westminster Abbey;
put a monarch on the throne; The Queen was enthroned more than 50 years ago;
remove a monarch from the throne; If the King does not abdicate, he will have to be dethroned;
remove from political office; The Republicans are trying to unseat the liberal Democrat;
give an assignment to (a person) to a post, or assign a task to (a person) ;
pass on or delegate to another; The representative devolved his duties to his aides while he was in the hospital;
assign a task to; I tasked him with looking after the children;
place somebody in a particular situation or location; he was placed on probation;
assign to a regiment; regiment soldiers;
transfer somebody to a different position or location of work;
transfer an employee to a different, temporary assignment; The officer was seconded for duty overseas;
hand over one and receive another, approximately equivalent; exchange prisoners; exchange employees between branches of the company;
exchange people temporarily to fulfill certain jobs and functions;
exchange on a regular basis; We rotate the lead soprano every night;
appoint someone to (a position or a job) ;
assume, as of positions or roles; She took the job as director of development; he occupies the position of manager; the young prince will soon occupy the throne;
appoint as a substitute;
act as a substitute; She stood in for the soprano who suffered from a cold;
to take an action to protect against future problems; Count the cash in the drawer twice just to cover yourself;
help out by taking someone's place and temporarily assuming his responsibilities; She is covering for our secretary who is ill this week;
transfer power to someone;
assign under a mandate; mandate a colony;
commence officially;
open to public use, as of a highway, park, or building; The Beauty Queen spends her time dedicating parks and nursing homes;
create and charge with a task or function; nominate a committee;
set up a committee or legislative body with one's own supporters so as to influence the outcome; pack a jury;
charge with a function; charge to be; She was named Head of the Committee; She was made president of the club;
name again or anew; He was renamed Minister of the Interior;
enter on a list or slate for an election; He was slated for borough president;
appoint summarily or commandeer; The army tried to co-opt peasants into civil defence groups;
give life-time employment to; She was tenured after she published her book;
give a promotion to or assign to a higher position; John was kicked upstairs when a replacement was hired; Women tend not to advance in the major law firms; I got promoted after many years of hard work;
promote from a lower position or rank; This player was brought up to the major league;
promote on the spot; Supreme Bishop Digby had been spot-promoted to Archangel;
give a title to someone; make someone a member of the nobility;
confer baronetcy upon; He was baronetized for his loyalty to the country;
make a lord of someone;
assign great social importance to; The film director was celebrated all over Hollywood; The tenor was lionized in Vienna;
raise (someone) to knighthood; The Beatles were knighted;
assign to a lower position; reduce in rank; She was demoted because she always speaks up; He was broken down to Sergeant;
remove from the center of activity or attention; place into an inferior position; The outspoken cabinet member was sidelined by the President;
bring to humbler or weaker state or condition; He reduced the population to slavery;
promote over another; he favors his second daughter;
give preference to one creditor over another;
examine in order to test suitability; screen these samples; screen the job applicants;
elect in a voting process; They voted in Clinton;
select by a vote for an office or membership; We elected him chairman of the board;
choose or elect as a fellow member or colleague; The church members co-opted individuals from similar backgrounds to replenish the congregation;
elect again;
ask to represent; of legal counsel; I'm retaining a lawyer;
put forward; nominate for appointment to an office or for an honor or position; The President nominated her as head of the Civil Rights Commission;
remove from a position or office; The chairman was ousted after he misappropriated funds;
oust or exclude from a group or membership by decree;
act quickly and decisively; not let slip an opportunity;
cause the downfall of; of rulers; The Czar was overthrown; subvert the ruling class;
overthrow by a revolution, of governments;
terminate the employment of; discharge from an office or position; The boss fired his secretary today; The company terminated 25% of its workers;
force out; The new boss cleaned out the lazy workers;
dismiss, usually for economic reasons; She was laid off together with hundreds of other workers when the company downsized;
