finish or terminate (meetings, speeches, etc.) ; The meeting was closed with a charge by the chairman of the board;
start to operate or function or cause to start operating or functioning; open a business;
cease to operate or cause to cease operating; The owners decided to move and to close the factory; My business closes every night at 8 P.M.; close up the shop;
bring back into original existence, use, function, or position; restore law and order; reestablish peace in the region; restore the emperor to the throne;
set up or found; She set up a literacy program;
do away with; Slavery was abolished in the mid-19th century in America and in Russia;
discard or do away with; cashier the literal sense of this word;
invest with ministerial or priestly authority; The minister was ordained only last month;
order by virtue of superior authority; decree; The King ordained the persecution and expulsion of the Jews; the legislature enacted this law in 1985;
enact again; Congress reenacted the law;
do something despite obstacles such as lack of time; He finally got around to painting the windows;
break from a meeting or gathering; We adjourned for lunch; The men retired to the library;
adjourn by royal prerogative; without dissolving the legislative body;
collect in one place; We assembled in the church basement; Let's gather in the dining room;
come and gather for a public event; Hundreds of thousands turned out for the anti-war rally in New York;
meet to select a candidate or promote a policy;
call a meeting; invite or command to meet; The Wannsee Conference was called to discuss the Final Solution; The new dean calls meetings every week;
attach oneself to a group;
become an ally or associate, as by a treaty or marriage; He allied himself with the Communists;
make a bad alliance; ally inappropriately; The two countries are misallied;
part; cease or break association with; She disassociated herself from the organization when she found out the identity of the president;
establish or impress firmly in the mind; We imprint our ideas onto our children;
have force or influence; bring about an effect or change; Politeness militated against this opinion being expressed;
discontinue an association or relation; go different ways; The business partners broke over a tax question; The couple separated after 25 years of marriage; My friend and I split up;
end a relationship; China broke with Russia;
work in an administrative capacity; supervise or be in charge of; administer a program; she administers the funds;
administer a pontifical office;
cause to be structured or ordered or operating according to some principle or idea;
organize as a territory;
organize anew; We must reorganize the company if we don't want to go under;
organize anew, as after a setback;
revise or reorganize, especially for the purpose of updating and improving; We must retool the town's economy;
bring under collective control; of farms and industrial enterprises;
maintain one's position and be in control of a situation;
bring under Soviet control, of a country;
form or join a union; The auto workers decided to unionize;
form a confederation with; of nations;
unite formally; of interest groups or countries;
to take one's place in a military formation or line; Troops fall in!;
become part of; become a member of a group or organization; He joined the Communist Party as a young man;
join in an affiliation; The two colleges affiliated; They affiliated with a national group;
join again;
enter a group or organization in order to spy on the members; The student organization was infiltrated by a traitor;
recruit for a union or organize into a union; We don't allow people to come into our plant and try to unionize the workers;
remove the organization from;
be in charge of, act on, or dispose of; I can deal with this crew of workers; This blender can't handle nuts; She managed her parents' affairs after they got too old;
cause to operate or function; This pilot works the controls; Can you work an electric drill?;
deal with (a problem or a subject) ; I still have not come to grips with the death of my parents;
deal with or settle; He disposed of these cases quickly;
behave carelessly or indifferently; Play about with a young girl's affection;
be in charge of or deal with; She takes care of all the necessary arrangements;
bring into common action, movement, or condition; coordinate the painters, masons, and plumbers; coordinate his actions with that of his colleagues; coordinate our efforts;
be co-ordinated; These activities coordinate well;
deal with simultaneously; She had to juggle her job and her children;
deal with in a routine way; I'll handle that one; process a loan; process the applicants;
process fast and efficiently; I will try to expedite the matter;
manage badly or incompetently; The funds were mismanaged;
manage or run; tend a store;
stir up or tend; of a fire;
begin to deal with; approach a task; go about a difficult problem; approach a new project;
be in charge of;
be a guiding or motivating force or drive; The teacher steered the gifted students towards the more challenging courses;
act or preside as chair, as of an academic department in a university; She chaired the department for many years;
be in charge of; Who is heading this project?;
be the captain of a sports team;
be the leader of; She spearheaded the effort to find a cure for the disease;
assume control;
seize control of;
exercise authoritative control or power over; control the budget; Command the military forces;
put under international control; internationalize trade of certain drugs;
take and maintain control over, often by violent means; The dissatisfied students held the President's office for almost a week;
be master; reign or rule;
direct or strongly influence the behavior of; His belief in God governs his conduct;
subject to rigid discipline, order, and systematization; regiment one's children;
have and control fully and exclusively; He monopolizes the laser printer;
control and direct with or as if by reins; rein a horse;
gain control over; corner the gold market;
watch and direct; Who is overseeing this project?;
order, supervise, or finance the construction of; The government is building new schools in this state;
act as president; preside over companies and corporations;
direct or control; projects, businesses, etc.; She is running a relief operation in the Sudan;
operate in or through; Work the phones;
run on a block system; block trains;
run until the normal working temperature is reached; We warmed up the car for a few minutes;
authorize payments of; declare dividends;
authorize officially; I am licensed to practice law in this state;
cause to be no longer approved or accepted; Carter derecognized Taiwan in 1979 after the U.S. recognized the People's Republic of China;
grant rights to; grant a patent for;
direct the course of; manage or control; You cannot conduct business like this;
carry on illegal business activities involving crime;
work in a specific place, with a specific subject, or in a specific function; He is a herpetologist; She is our resident philosopher;
devote oneself to a special area of work; She specializes in honey bees; This baker specializes in French bread;
work as a veterinarian; She vetted for the farms in the area for many years;
work as a minister; She is ministering in an old parish;
work as an intern; The young doctor is interning at the Medical Center this year;
work as the skipper on a vessel;
act as the coxswain, in a boat race;
do useless, wasteful, or trivial work;
give the right to; The Freedom of Information Act entitles you to request your FBI file;
grant a franchise to;
