milk secreted by a woman who has recently given birth;
milky fluid secreted for the first day or two after parturition;
the fluid-filled cavity that surrounds the developing embryo;
the serous fluid in which the embryo is suspended inside the amnion; before a woman gives birth her waters break;
the fluid (red in vertebrates) that is pumped through the body by the heart and contains plasma, blood cells, and platelets; blood carries oxygen and nutrients to the tissues and carries away waste products; the ancients believed that blood was the seat of the emotions;
blood found in arteries; except for the pulmonary artery the arterial blood is rich in oxygen;
human blood cells (usually just the red blood cells) that have the same antigens;
the blood group whose red cells carry the A antigen;
the blood group whose red cells carry the B antigen;
the blood group whose red cells carry both the A and B antigens;
the blood group whose red cells carry neither the A nor B antigens; people with type O blood are universal donors;
the blood group (approximately 85% of people) whose red cells have the Rh factor (Rh antigen);
the blood group whose red cells lack the Rh factor (Rh antigen);
coagulated blood from a wound;
the blood considered as the seat of vitality;
the blood flowing through the circulatory system;
a lump of material formed from the content of a liquid;
a semisolid mass of coagulated red and white blood cells;
blood obtained from the umbilical cord at birth;
flow of blood from the uterus; occurs at roughly monthly intervals during a woman's reproductive years;
blood found in the veins; except in the pulmonary vein venous blood is rich in carbon dioxide and poor in oxygen;
blood that has not been modified except for the addition of an anticoagulant; whole blood is normally used in blood transfusions;
an amber, watery fluid, rich in proteins, that separates out when blood coagulates;
the colorless watery fluid of the blood and lymph that contains no cells, but in which the blood cells (erythrocytes, leukocytes, and thrombocytes) are suspended;
blood serum containing antibodies against specific antigens; provides immunity to a disease;
a milky fluid consisting of lymph and emulsified fats; formed in the small intestine during digestion of ingested fats;
a thin coagulable fluid (similar to plasma but) containing white blood cells (lymphocytes) and chyle; is conveyed to the blood stream by lymphatic vessels;
the thick white fluid containing spermatozoa that is ejaculated by the male genital tract;
dark protective fluid ejected into the water by cuttlefish and other cephalopods;
a functionally specialized substance (especially one that is not a waste) released from a gland or cell;
saline fluid secreted by lacrimal glands; lubricates the surface of the eyeball;
a drop of the clear salty saline solution secreted by the lacrimal glands; his story brought tears to her eyes;
the structures that secrete and drain tears from the eye;
salty fluid secreted by sweat glands; sweat poured off his brow;
secretions that aid digestion;
digestive secretions of the stomach glands consisting chiefly of hydrochloric acid and mucin and the enzymes pepsin and rennin and lipase;
a fluid secreted into the duodenum by the pancreas; important for breaking down starches and proteins and fats;
a digestive juice secreted by the liver and stored in the gallbladder; aids in the digestion of fats;
a humor that was once believed to be secreted by the kidneys or spleen and to cause sadness and melancholy;
a humor that was once believed to be secreted by the liver and to cause irritability and anger;
the secretion of an endocrine gland that is transmitted by the blood to the tissue on which it has a specific effect;
secretions by glands lining the walls of the intestines;
a catecholamine precursor of epinephrine that is secreted by the adrenal medulla and also released at synapses;
a hormone produced by the anterior pituitary gland that stimulates the adrenal cortex;
a catecholamine secreted by the adrenal medulla in response to stress (trade name Adrenalin); stimulates autonomic nerve action;
hormones that affect gastrointestinal functioning;
polypeptide hormone secreted by the mucous lining of the stomach; when peptides and amino acids are present in the small intestine the secretion of gastric acid is stimulated;
a gastrointestinal hormone that stimulates the secretion of pancreatic enzymes and the contraction and emptying of the gall bladder; its release is stimulated by the presence of fatty acids and amino acids in the small intestine;
a gastrointestinal hormone that stimulates the secretion of water and bicarbonate from the pancreas and bile ducts whenever the stomach empties too much acid into the small intestine;
a gastrointestinal hormone produced by epithelial cells lining the fundus of the stomach; appears to be a stimulant for appetite and feeding, but is also a strong stimulant of growth hormone secretion from the anterior pituitary;
a gastrointestinal hormone that apparently participates in controlling smooth muscle contractions in the stomach and small intestine;
a hormone secreted by the pancreas; stimulates increases in blood sugar levels in the blood (thus opposing the action of insulin);
hormone secreted by the anterior pituitary gland and placenta; stimulates the gonads and controls reproductive activity;
hormone secreted by the isles of Langerhans in the pancreas; regulates storage of glycogen in the liver and accelerates oxidation of sugar in cells;
trade names for forms of insulin that are used to treat diabetes mellitus;
a form of insulin (trade name Humulin) made from recombinant DNA that is identical to human insulin; used to treat diabetics who are allergic to preparations made from beef or pork insulin;
hormone secreted by the pineal gland;
a hormone that is released by nerve impulses (e.g., norepinephrine or vasopressin);
hormone secreted by the posterior pituitary gland (trade name Pitocin); stimulates contractions of the uterus and ejection of milk;
hormone synthesized and released into the blood stream by the parathyroid glands; regulates phosphorus and calcium in the body and functions in neuromuscular excitation and blood clotting;
hormone secreted by the corpus luteum during the last days of pregnancy; relaxes the pelvic ligaments and prepares the uterus for labor;
any of several hormones produced in the hypothalamus and carried by a vein to the anterior pituitary gland where they stimulate the release of anterior pituitary hormones; each of these hormones causes the anterior pituitary to secrete a specific hormone;
a hormone produced by the anterior pituitary gland; promotes growth in humans;
trade name of a synthetic human growth hormone given to children deficient in the hormone; use by athletes and weightlifters is banned;
hormone secreted by the thymus; stimulates immunological activity of lymphoid tissue;
any of several closely related compounds that are produced by the thyroid gland and are active metabolically;
thyroid hormone that tends to lower the level of calcium in the blood plasma and inhibit resorption of bone;
hormone produced by the thyroid glands to regulate metabolism by controlling the rate of oxidation in cells; thyroxine is 65% iodine;
thyroid hormone similar to thyroxine but with one less iodine atom per molecule and produced in smaller quantity; exerts the same biological effects as thyroxine but is more potent and briefer;
hormone secreted by the posterior pituitary gland (trade name Pitressin) and also by nerve endings in the hypothalamus; affects blood pressure by stimulating capillary muscles and reduces urine flow by affecting reabsorption of water by kidney tubules;
any physiologically active internal secretion especially one of uncertain classification;
amine formed from histidine that stimulates gastric secretions and dilates blood vessels; released by the human immune system during allergic reactions;
a potent substance that acts like a hormone and is found in many bodily tissues (and especially in semen); produced in response to trauma and may affect blood pressure and metabolism and smooth muscle activity;
viscid lubricating fluid secreted by the membrane lining joints and tendon sheaths etc.;
protective secretion of the mucus membranes; in the gut it lubricates the passage of food and protects the epithelial cells; in the nose and throat and lungs it can make it difficult for bacteria to penetrate the body through the epithelium;
expectorated matter; saliva mixed with discharges from the respiratory passages; in ancient and medieval physiology it was believed to cause sluggishness;
nasal mucus;
dried nasal mucus;
a clear liquid secreted into the mouth by the salivary glands and mucous glands of the mouth; moistens the mouth and starts the digestion of starches;
a duct through which saliva passes from the salivary gland into the mouth;
saliva spilling from the mouth;
saliva colored brown by tobacco (snuff or chewing tobacco);
the oily secretion of the sebaceous glands; with perspiration it moistens and protects the skin;
a white secretion of the sebaceous glands of the foreskin;
substance discharged from the vagina (cellular debris and mucus and blood) that gradually decreases in amount during the weeks following childbirth;
a fluid product of inflammation;
a thin morbid discharge as from a wound or especially chronic gonorrhea;
discharge of white mucous material from the vagina; often an indication of infection;
a vessel in which blood circulates;
a blood vessel in a fetus that bypasses pulmonary circulation by connecting the pulmonary artery directly to the ascending aorta; normally closes at birth;
a ductus arteriosus that failed to close at birth; may require surgical correction;
any small blood vessel ramifying on the outside of a major artery or vein;
a blood vessel that carries blood from the capillaries toward the heart; all veins except the pulmonary vein carry unaerated blood;
(zoology) the system of venous blood vessels in an animal;
a vein that is permanently dilated; most common in the legs;
vein of the head of the penis; tributary of the internal pudendal vein that drains the perineum;
vein of the cochlear canal;
a vein serving the penis;
superficial dorsal veins of the penis; paired tributaries of the external pudendal veins on each side;
deep dorsal vein of the penis; tributary of the prostatic plexus;
