accompanies the artery of the same name;
either of two veins that accompany arteries of the same name serving the hip and thigh;
veins that serve the clitoris;
vein serving the large intestine;
vein formed by union of facial vein and the retromandibular vein and emptying into the jugular vein;
veins draining the conjunctiva;
one of several veins connecting intercostal veins with the lateral thoracic vein or the thoracoepigastric vein;
one of a number of veins in the subcutaneous tissue that empty into deep veins;
vein that drains the gallbladder;
one of the veins serving the fingers or toes;
one of the veins serving the spongy part of the cranial bones;
vein that is a tributary of the subclavian vein or external jugular vein and accompanies the descending scapular artery;
one of the two roots of a spinal nerve that passes dorsally to the spinal cord and that consists of sensory fibers;
one of several connecting veins in the scalp and head that drain blood from sinuses in the dura mater to veins outside the skull;
veins serving the anterior walls of the abdomen;
empties into the external iliac vein;
empties into the great saphenous vein;
veins that accompany the superior epigastric artery;
small veins in the sclera near the corneal margin; empty into the anterior ciliary veins;
small veins from the esophagus emptying into the brachiocephalic vein or the azygos veins;
veins that drain the ethmoidal sinuses and empty into the superior ophthalmic vein;
one of the veins that drain the external nose and empty into the angular or facial vein;
any of several veins draining the face;
a vein that accompanies the femoral artery in the same sheath; a continuation of the popliteal vein; becomes the external iliac vein;
one of several veins draining the stomach walls;
one of two veins serving the great curvature of the stomach;
veins that drain blood from structures around the knee; empty into the popliteal vein;
a small rounded structure; especially that at the end of the penis or clitoris;
small mass of erectile tissue at the end of the body of the clitoris;
the conical mass of erectile tissue that forms the head of the penis;
veins draining the gluteal muscles on either side of the body;
a continuation of the left ascending lumbar vein; crosses the midline at the 8th vertebra and empties into the azygos vein;
any of several veins draining the walls of the anal canal and rectum;
a vein that drains the liver; empties into the vena cava;
a vein that unites with the external iliac vein to form the common iliac vein;
a vein that drains the end of the ileum and the appendix and the cecum and the lower part of the ascending colon;
a continuation of the femoral vein; unites with the internal iliac vein to form the common iliac vein;
formed by the internal and external iliac veins; unites with its fellow from the opposite side of the body to form the inferior vena cava;
one of three veins draining the pelvic area;
a branch of the internal iliac vein;
veins connecting the dorsal and palmar veins of the hand or the dorsal and plantar veins of the foot;
several veins draining the intercostal spaces of the rib cage;
one of several veins accompanying spinal nerves;
veins in the neck that return blood from the head;
arises below the chin from veins draining the lower face; joins the external jugular vein;
formed by the junction of the posterior auricular and the retromandibular veins; empties into the subclavian vein;
a continuation of the sigmoid sinus of the dura mater; joins the subclavian vein to form the brachiocephalic vein;
a vein draining the lips of the mouth;
a tributary of the facial vein that drains the lower lip;
a tributary of the facial vein that drains the upper lip;
veins draining the lips of the vulva;
veins that drain the inner ear;
drains the lacrimal gland; empties into the superior ophthalmic vein;
one of two veins draining the larynx;
arises from a union of veins from the gastric cardia; runs in the lesser omentum; empties into the portal vein;
a vein that receives blood from the tongue and the floor of the mouth and empties into the internal jugular or the facial vein;
veins that drain the posterior body wall and the lumbar vertebral venous plexuses;
posterior continuation of the pterygoid plexus; joins the superficial temporal vein to form the retromandibular vein;
veins at accompany the meningeal arteries;
a tributary of the portal vein passing from the intestine between the two layers of mesentery;
dorsal and palmar veins of the hand;
dorsal and plantar branches of veins serving the metatarsal region of the foot;
veins that drain the upper abdominal wall and the lower intercostal spaces and the abdomen;
a vein located in the anterior medial part of the orbit; connects the superior ophthalmic with the angular vein;
a tributary of the coronary sinus; on the posterior wall of the left atrium;
a vein formed by the union of tributaries that drain the hip joints and thigh muscles; empties into the internal iliac vein;
a vein that drains the occipital region;
either of two veins that serve the eye; empties into the cavernous sinus;
a vein that drains a venous network in the floor and medial wall of the eye socket;
a vein that begins at the inner angle of the eye socket and passes through the superior orbital fissure to empty into the cavernous sinus;
one of the veins that drain the ovaries; the right opens into the inferior vena cava; the left opens into the left renal vein;
a vein that drains the region of the palate and empties into the facial vein;
veins draining the pancreas and emptying into the superior mesenteric and splenic veins;
small veins arising in skin around the navel; terminate as accessory portal veins;
parotid branches of the facial vein; they drain part of the parotid gland and empty into the retromandibular vein;
veins that drain the pectoral muscles and empty into the subclavian vein;
veins that accompany the perforating arteries; drain leg muscles; empty into the deep femoral vein;
several small veins from the pericardium;
accompany the peroneal arteries; arising in the heel and running up the back of the leg to join the posterior tibial veins of the popliteal vein;
veins from the pharyngeal plexus that empty into the internal jugular vein;
either of two veins that drain the diaphragm;
a vein arising in the knee and ascending to become the femoral vein;
system of veins that carry blood from the abdominal organs to the liver;
a short vein that carries blood into the liver;
arises near the apex of the heart and empties into the coronary sinus;
a tributary of the right gastric vein;
vein of the pudendum;
any of four veins that carry arterial blood from the lungs to the left atrium of the heart;
either of two pulmonary veins (left and right) returning blood from the inferior lobes of the lungs;
either of two pulmonary veins (left and right) returning blood from the superior lobes of the lungs;
receives veins from the upper surfaces of the stomach and empties into the portal vein;
superficial veins ascending the radial side of the forearm; combines with the ulnar veins to form the brachial vein;
veins that accompany renal arteries; open into the vena cava at the level of the 2nd lumbar vertebra;
posterior branch of the facial vein; formed by temporal veins in front of the ear;
vein of the sacral region;
either of two chief superficial veins of the leg that drain blood from the foot;
the longest vein in the body; runs from foot to the groin where it joins the femoral vein;
a vein running from the foot up the back of the leg to the knee;
tributaries of the anterior ciliary veins that drain the sclera of the eye;
veins passing from the scrotum to the pudendal veins;
