tributaries of the inferior mesenteric vein; drains the sigmoid colon;
veins that drain the spinal cord;
a vein formed by several small veins on the surface of the spleen; joins the superior mesenteric to form the portal vein;
a star-shaped group of venules in the renal cortex;
drains the sternocleidomastoid muscle; empties into the internal jugular vein;
a vein that drains the tympanic cavity and empties into the retromandibular vein;
a continuation of the axillary vein; joins the internal jugular to form the brachiocephalic vein;
a tributary of the lingual vein;
drains the front of the scalp; unites with the supratrochlear vein to form the angular vein;
drains the front of the scalp; unites with the supraorbital vein to form the angular vein;
any of several veins draining the temporal region;
temporal veins that empty into the pterygoid plexus;
arises near the eye; joins the superficial temporal veins to form the retromandibular vein;
join the middle temporal vein to empty into the retromandibular vein;
a vein from the testicles;
a vein serving the thalamus and corpus striatum;
a vein arising from the region of the superficial epigastric vein and opening into the axillary vein or thoracic vein;
a long vein that helps to form the internal cerebral vein;
tributaries to the basal vein;
veins that drain the thoracic walls;
any of several small veins draining blood from the thyroid area;
any of several veins on each side that drain the thyroid gland and empty into the innominate vein;
a vein on each side that drains the lateral part of the thyroid and empties into the internal jugular vein;
a vein on each side that drains the upper part of the thyroid and empties into the internal jugular vein;
veins of the lower leg; empty into the popliteal vein;
several small veins from the trachea;
veins from the tympanic cavity that empty into the retromandibular vein;
any of several veins of the forearm;
a vein in the umbilical cord; returns nutrient blood from the placenta to the fetus;
one of two veins on each side that arise from the uterine plexus and empty into the internal iliac vein;
a muscular sac attached to the liver that stores bile (secreted by the liver) until it is needed for digestion;
the upper region of the abdomen just below the lowest ribs on either side of the epigastrium;
large and complicated reddish-brown glandular organ located in the upper right portion of the abdominal cavity; secretes bile and functions in metabolism of protein and carbohydrate and fat; synthesizes substances involved in the clotting of the blood; synthesizes vitamin A; detoxifies poisonous substances and breaks down worn-out erythrocytes;
any of the many tiny canals that contain blood vessels and connective tissue and that form a network in bone;
any of the five lobes forming the liver;
the duct that drains bile from the liver;
oblique passage through the lower abdominal wall; in males it is the passage through which the testes descend into the scrotum and it contains the spermatic cord; in females it transmits the round ligament of the uterus;
a duct formed by the hepatic and cystic ducts; opens into the duodenum;
excretory ducts of the liver; empty into the hepatic ducts;
a large elongated exocrine gland located behind the stomach; secretes pancreatic juice and insulin;
a duct connecting the pancreas with the intestine;
either of two saclike respiratory organs in the chest of vertebrates; serves to remove carbon dioxide and provide oxygen to the blood;
lung tissue densely packed with alveoli;
any of the three lobes of the right lung or the two lobes of the left lung;
the thin serous membrane around the lungs and inner walls of the chest;
pleura that lines the inner chest walls and covers the diaphragm;
pleura that covers the lungs;
the cavity in the thorax that contains the lungs and heart;
the small potential space between the parietal and visceral layers of the pleura;
the hollow muscular organ located behind the sternum and between the lungs; its rhythmic contractions move the blood through the body; he stood still, his heart thumping wildly;
enlarged heart commonly found among athletes trained for endurance;
a heart (as of mammals and birds and reptiles) having two auricles;
a specialized bit of heart tissue that controls the heartbeat;
a thin triangular flap of a heart valve;
a movable piece of tissue partly connected to the body;
the muscle tissue of the heart; adapted to continued rhythmic contraction;
any of several muscles associated with the atrioventricular valves; the papillary muscles contract during systole to prevent regurgitation of blood into the atria;
a bundle of modified heart muscle that transmits the cardiac impulse from the atrioventricular node to the ventricles causing them to contract;
a node of specialized heart muscle located in the septal wall of the right atrium; receives impulses from the sinoatrial node and transmits them to atrioventricular bundle;
the middle muscular layer of the heart wall;
a specialized cardiac muscle fiber that is part of the Purkinje network;
a network of Purkinje fibers that carry the cardiac impulse from the atrioventricular node to the ventricles of the heart and causes them to contract;
a triangular area of the front of the chest (determined by percussion); corresponds to the part of the heart not covered by the lungs;
a chamber of the heart that receives blood from an atrium and pumps it to the arteries;
the chamber on the left side of the heart that receives arterial blood from the left atrium and pumps it into the aorta;
the chamber on the right side of the heart that receives venous blood from the right atrium and pumps it into the pulmonary trunk;
a small conical pouch projecting from the upper anterior part of each atrium of the heart;
a pouch projecting from the top front of each atrium of the heart;
an enclosed volume in the body; the chambers of his heart were healthy;
the cavity enclosed by the cranium;
any chamber that is connected to other chambers or passageways (especially one of the two upper chambers of the heart);
the upper chamber of each half of the heart;
the right upper chamber of the heart that receives blood from the venae cavae and coronary sinus;
the left upper chamber of the heart that receives blood from the pulmonary veins;
valve with two cusps; situated between the left atrium and the left ventricle;
valve with three cusps; situated between the right atrium and the right ventricle; allows blood to pass from atrium to ventricle and closes to prevent backflow when the ventricle contracts;
either of two heart valves through which blood flows from the atria to the ventricles; prevents return of blood to the atrium;
a semilunar valve between the left ventricle and the aorta; prevents blood from flowing from the aorta back into the heart;
a semilunar valve between the right ventricle and the pulmonary artery; prevents blood from flowing from the artery back into the heart;
a heart valve with cusps shaped like half-moons; prevents blood from flowing back into the heart;
a valve to control one-way flow of blood;
a structure in a hollow organ (like the heart) with a flap to insure one-way flow of fluid through it;
a small valve;
an enlarged and muscular saclike organ of the alimentary canal; the principal organ of digestion;
the region lying on or over the stomach (just below the sternum);
the opening into the stomach and that part of the stomach connected to the esophagus;
the interconnected system of spaces and vessels between body tissues and organs by which lymph circulates throughout the body;
the major duct of the lymphatic system;
a vascular duct that carries lymph which is eventually added to the venous blood circulation;
any of the lymphatic vessels that convey chyle from the small intestine to the thoracic duct;
a structure composed of or provided with blood vessels;
a tube in which a body fluid circulates;
the liquid parts of the body;
liquid containing proteins and electrolytes including the liquid in blood plasma and interstitial fluid; the body normally has about 15 quarts of extracellular fluid;
liquid found between the cells of the body that provides much of the liquid environment of the body;
liquid contained inside the cell membranes (usually containing dissolved solutes);
any of several liquids of the body; digestive juices;
a milky substance found in certain cancerous growths;
a clear liquid in the cell nucleus in which the nucleolus and chromatin and other structures are dispersed;
produced by mammary glands of female mammals for feeding their young;
