small genus of perennial herbs or subshrubs; some often placed in other genera;
a rare mallow found only in Illinois resembling the common hollyhock and having pale rose-mauve flowers; sometimes placed in genus Sphaeralcea;
perennial of northwestern United States and western Canada resembling a hollyhock and having white or pink flowers;
small genus of herbs of southeastern United States and tropical America and Africa;
any of various plants of the genus Kosteletzya predominantly of coastal habitats; grown for their flowers that resemble hibiscus;
subshrub of southeastern United States to New York;
widespread genus of herbs or softwood arborescent shrubs cultivated for their showy flowers;
arborescent perennial shrub having palmately lobed furry leaves and showy red-purple flowers; southwestern United States;
genus of shrubs or small trees: chaparral mallow;
shrub of coastal ranges of California and Baja California having hairy branches and spikes of numerous mauve flowers; sometimes placed in genus Sphaeralcea;
small genus of chiefly European herbs;
western Mediterranean annual having deep purple-red flowers subtended by 3 large cordate bracts;
genus of mallows characterized by red and yellow flowers often placed in other genera;
an American plant of the genus Malvastrum;
small genus of shrubs of Central and South America: wax mallows;
any of various plants of the genus Malvaviscus having brilliant bell-shaped drooping flowers like incompletely opened hibiscus flowers;
one species: glade mallow;
tall coarse American herb having palmate leaves and numerous small white dioecious flowers; found wild in most alluvial soils of eastern and central United States;
genus of tropical hairy shrubs or herbs of tropics and subtropics especially South America;
any of various evergreen plants of the genus Pavonia having white or yellow or purple flowers;
small genus of shrubs and trees of Australia and New Zealand;
deciduous New Zealand tree whose inner bark yields a strong fiber that resembles flax and is called New Zealand cotton;
a fiber from the bast of New Zealand ribbon trees that resembles cotton fiber;
very small genus of shrubs of southern hemisphere: bush hibiscus;
southern and western Australian shrub with unlobed or shallowly lobed toothed leaves and purple flowers; sometimes placed in genus Hibiscus;
large genus of tropical subshrubs or herbs some of which yield fibers of mucilaginous substances;
tall handsome perennial herb of southeastern United States having maplelike leaves and white flowers;
herb widely distributed in tropics and subtropics used for forage and medicinally as a demulcent and having a fine soft bast stronger than jute; sometimes an aggressive weed;
tropical American weed having pale yellow or orange flowers naturalized in southern United States;
genus of showy plants of western North America having palmate leaves and variously colored racemose flowers;
perennial purple-flowered wild mallow of western North America that is also cultivated;
large genus of chiefly tropical herbs with showy flowers and mostly globose fruits: globe mallows;
genus of coarse herbs and subshrubs of arid North and South America having pink or scarlet flowers and globose fruits;
false mallow of western United States having racemose red flowers; sometimes placed in genus Malvastrum;
a small genus of tropical trees including the portia tree;
any of various trees yielding variously colored woods similar to true tulipwood;
the variegated or showily striped ornamental wood of various tulipwood trees;
pantropical tree of usually seacoasts sometimes cultivated as an ornamental for its rounded heart-shaped leaves and showy yellow and purple flowers; yields valuable pink to dark red close-grained wood and oil from its seeds;
tropical trees with large dry or fleshy fruit containing usually woolly seeds;
trees of chiefly South America;
East Indian silk cotton tree yielding fibers inferior to kapok;
baobab; cream-of-tartar tree;
Australian tree having an agreeably acid fruit that resembles a gourd;
African tree having an exceedingly thick trunk and fruit that resembles a gourd and has an edible pulp called monkey bread;
tropical American trees with palmately compound leaves and showy bell-shaped flowers;
massive tropical tree with deep ridges on its massive trunk and bearing large pods of seeds covered with silky floss; source of the silky kapok fiber;
a genus of tall Asian trees of the family Bombacaceae;
tree of southeastern Asia having edible oval fruit with a hard spiny rind;
one species: medium-sized evergreen tree of Puerto Rico or Mexico;
evergreen tree with large leathery leaves and large pink to orange flowers; considered a link plant between families Bombacaceae and Sterculiaceae;
one species: balsa;
forest tree of lowland Central America having a strong very light wood; used for making floats and rafts and in crafts;
strong lightweight wood of the balsa tree used especially for floats;
tropical American deciduous shrubs or small trees;
tree of Mexico to Guatemala having densely hairy flowers with long narrow petals clustered at ends of branches before leaves appear;
genus of trees and shrubs widely distributed in warm regions some yielding useful timber; in some classifications included in the family Santalaceae;
type genus of the family Elaeocarpaceae;
Australian tree having hard white timber and glossy green leaves with white flowers followed by one-seeded glossy blue fruit;
pale easily worked timber from the quandong tree;
the fruit of the Brisbane quandong tree;
small genus of shrubs or small trees of Australia and New Zealand and western South America;
graceful deciduous shrub or small tree having attractive foliage and small red berries that turn black at maturity and are used for making wine;
one species: Jamaican cherry; sometimes placed in family Flacourtiaceae;
a fast-growing tropical American evergreen having white flowers and white fleshy edible fruit; bark yields a silky fiber used in cordage and wood is valuable for staves;
genus of tropical hardwood timber trees;
West Indian timber tree having very hard wood;
a large family of plants of order Malvales;
type genus of the Sterculiaceae: deciduous or evergreen trees of Old and New World tropics and subtropics;
any tree of the genus Sterculia;
large deciduous tree native to Panama and from which the country takes its name; having densely leafy crown and naked trunk;
large tree of Old World tropics having foul-smelling orange-red blossoms followed by red pods enclosing oil-rich seeds sometimes used as food;
Australian trees (usually with swollen trunks);
an Australian tree of the genus Brachychiton;
south Australian tree having panicles of brilliant scarlet flowers;
north Australian tree having white flowers and broad leaves;
widely distributed tree of eastern Australia yielding a tough durable fiber and soft light attractively grained wood; foliage is an important emergency food for cattle;
large tree of Queensland having cream-colored flowers blotched with red inside; sometimes placed in genus Sterculia;
large genus of African trees bearing kola nuts;
tree bearing large brown nuts containing e.g. caffeine; source of cola extract;
bitter brown seed containing caffein; source of cola extract;
genus of African shrubs or small trees;
any of various shrubs or small trees of the genus Dombeya grown for their rounded clusters of exquisite often sweet-scented flowers usually hanging beneath the leaves;
small genus of Asian trees or shrubs;
deciduous tree widely grown in southern United States as an ornamental for its handsome maplelike foliage and long racemes of yellow-green flowers followed by curious leaflike pods;
flannelbush;
any of several handsome evergreen shrubs of California and northern Mexico having downy lobed leaves and showy yellow flowers;
genus of shrubs and small trees of tropical America and Asia having cylindrical fruits spirally twisted around one another;
a tree or shrub of the genus Helicteres;
East Indian shrub often cultivated for its hairy leaves and orange-red flowers;
small genus of timber trees of eastern Asia, Australasia and tropical Africa that form large buttresses;
large tree of Australasia;
large evergreen tree of India and Burma whose leaves are silvery beneath;
small tree of coastal regions of Old World tropics whose leaves are silvery beneath;
genus of African herbs and subshrubs having honey-scented bell-shaped flowers;
African shrub having decumbent stems and slender yellow honey-scented flowers either solitary or in pairs;
genus of tropical Asian trees and shrubs;
Indian tree having fragrant nocturnal white flowers and yielding a reddish wood used for planking; often grown as an ornamental or shade tree;
small genus of east Asian and Australian timber trees;
Australian timber tree;
cacao plants;
