any of several shrubs of the genus Andromeda having leathery leaves and clusters of small flowers;
wiry evergreen shrub having pendent clusters of white or pink flowers; of wet acidic areas in Arctic and Canada to northeastern United States;
erect to procumbent evergreen shrub having pendent clusters of white or pink flowers; of sphagnum peat bogs and other wet acidic areas in northern Europe;
large evergreen shrubs and trees of southern Europe and western North America: strawberry tree; madrona;
any of several evergreen shrubs of the genus Arbutus of temperate Europe and America;
evergreen tree of the Pacific coast of North America having glossy leathery leaves and orange-red edible berries; wood used for furniture and bark for tanning;
small evergreen European shrubby tree bearing many-seeded scarlet berries that are edible but bland; of Ireland, southern Europe, Asia Minor;
bearberry; manzanita;
chiefly evergreen subshrubs of northern to Arctic areas;
evergreen mat-forming shrub of North America and northern Eurasia having small white flowers and red berries; leaves turn red in autumn;
deciduous creeping shrub bright red in autumn having black or blue-black berries; alpine and circumpolar;
chiefly evergreen shrubs of warm dry areas of western North America;
erect California shrub having leaves with heart-shaped lobes at the base;
erect treelike shrub forming dense thickets and having drooping panicles of white or pink flowers and red berrylike drupes; California;
erect openly branched California shrub whose twigs are woolly when young;
a genus containing only one species: spike heath;
small evergreen mat-forming shrub of southern Europe and Asia Minor having stiff stems and terminal clusters of small bell-shaped flowers;
a genus allied to and once included in genus Phyllodoce;
procumbent Old World mat-forming evergreen shrub with racemes of pinkish-white flowers;
one species;
common Old World heath represented by many varieties; low evergreen grown widely in the northern hemisphere;
low tufted evergreen shrubs of colder parts of north temperate regions having moss-like foliage and nodding white or pink flowers;
heath of mountains of western United States having bell-shaped white flowers;
one species: leatherleaf;
north temperate bog shrub with evergreen leathery leaves and small white cylindrical flowers;
a dicotyledonous genus of the family Ericaceae;
low straggling evergreen shrub of western Europe represented by several varieties with flowers from white to rose-purple;
small creeping evergreen shrubs: trailing arbutus;
low-growing evergreen shrub of eastern North America with leathery leaves and clusters of fragrant pink or white flowers;
widely distributed genus of creeping or upright evergreen shrubs;
slow-growing procumbent evergreen shrublet of northern North America and Japan having white flowers and numerous white fleshy rough and hairy seeds;
creeping shrub of eastern North America having white bell-shaped flowers followed by spicy red berrylike fruit and shiny aromatic leaves that yield wintergreen oil;
small evergreen shrub of Pacific coast of North America having edible dark purple grape-sized berries;
deciduous or evergreen shrubs of North America: black huckleberries;
any of several shrubs of the genus Gaylussacia bearing small berries resembling blueberries;
low shrub of the eastern United States bearing shiny black edible fruit; best known of the huckleberries;
huckleberry of the eastern United States with pink flowers and sweet blue fruit;
creeping evergreen shrub of southeastern United States having small shiny boxlike leaves and flavorless berries;
erect evergreen shrubs: mountain laurel;
any plant of the genus Kalmia;
a North American evergreen shrub having glossy leaves and white or rose-colored flowers;
laurel of bogs of northwestern United States having small purple flowers and pale leaves that are glaucous beneath;
North American dwarf shrub resembling mountain laurel but having narrower leaves and small red flowers; poisonous to young stock;
evergreen shrubs of north temperate regions;
evergreen shrub of eastern North America having white or creamy bell-shaped flowers and dark green hairy leaves used for tea during American Revolution;
a Rocky Mountain shrub similar to Ledum groenlandicum;
bog shrub of northern and central Europe and eastern Siberia to Korea and Japan;
one species: sand myrtle;
low-growing evergreen shrub of New Jersey to Florida grown for its many white star-shaped flowers and glossy foliage;
American and Asiatic deciduous and evergreen shrubs;
any plant of the genus Leucothoe; grown for their beautiful white flowers; glossy foliage contains a poisonous substance similar to that found in genus Kalmia;
fast-growing evergreen shrub of southeastern United States having arching interlaced branches and racemes of white flowers;
bushy deciduous shrub of the eastern United States with long racemes of pinkish flowers;
one species: alpine azalea;
creeping mat-forming evergreen shrub of high mountain regions of northern hemisphere grown for its rose-pink flowers;
evergreen or deciduous shrubs or small trees of United States to Antilles and eastern Asia to the Himalaya;
deciduous shrub of coastal plain of the eastern United States having nodding pinkish-white flowers; poisonous to stock;
deciduous much-branched shrub with dense downy panicles of small bell-shaped white flowers;
showy evergreen shrub of southeastern United States with shiny leaves and angled branches and clusters of pink to reddish flowers that resemble an umbel;
deciduous shrubs of North America and eastern Asia;
straggling shrub of northwestern North America having foliage with a bluish tinge and umbels of small bell-shaped flowers;
low shrub of the eastern United States with downy twigs;
sourwood;
deciduous shrubby tree of eastern North America having deeply fissured bark and sprays of small fragrant white flowers and sour-tasting leaves;
small genus of evergreen Arctic and alpine shrubs;
small shrub with tiny evergreen leaves and pink or purple flowers; Alpine summits and high ground in Asia and Europe and United States;
semi-prostrate evergreen herb of western United States;
decorative evergreen shrubs of woody vines;
broad-leaved evergreen Asiatic shrub with glossy leaves and drooping clusters of white flowers;
ornamental evergreen shrub of southeastern United States having small white bell-shaped flowers;
large genus of evergreen shrubs native to cooler regions of the northern hemisphere having showy flowers;
any shrub of the genus Rhododendron: evergreen shrubs or small shrubby trees having leathery leaves and showy clusters of campanulate (bell-shaped) flowers;
medium-sized rhododendron of Pacific coast of North America having large rosy brown-spotted flowers;
late-spring-blooming rhododendron of eastern North America having rosy to pink-purple flowers;
shrub growing in swamps throughout the eastern United States and having small white to pinkish flowers resembling honeysuckle;
group of evergreen or deciduous shrubs formerly considered a separate genus; now included in the genus Rhododendron;
any of numerous ornamental shrubs grown for their showy flowers of various colors;
evergreen or deciduous berry-bearing shrubs of northern hemisphere: cranberries; blueberries;
any of numerous shrubs of genus Vaccinium bearing cranberries;
trailing red-fruited plant;
small red-fruited trailing cranberry of Arctic and cool regions of the northern hemisphere;
any of numerous shrubs of the genus Vaccinium bearing blueberries;
any of various dark-fruited as distinguished from blue-fruited blueberries;
shrub or small tree of eastern United States having black inedible berries;
low-growing deciduous shrub of northeastern North America having flowers in compact racemes and bearing sweet dark blue berries;
shrub of southeastern United States grown commercially especially for canning industry;
low-growing tufted deciduous shrub of northern and alpine North America having pink to coral-red flowers followed by sweet blue berries;
high-growing deciduous shrub of eastern North America bearing edible blueish to blackish berries with a distinct bloom; source of most cultivated blueberries;
shrub of the eastern United States having shining evergreen leaves and bluish-black fruit;
stiff bushy evergreen shrub of western North America having sour black berries and glossy green foliage used in floral arrangements;
erect blueberry of western United States having solitary flowers and somewhat sour berries;
erect European blueberry having solitary flowers and blue-black berries;
an evergreen shrub with leathery leaves;
low deciduous shrub of the eastern United States bearing dark blue sweet berries;
shrub of northwestern North America bearing red berries;
small branching blueberry common in marshy areas of the eastern United States having greenish or yellowish unpalatable berries reputedly eaten by deer;
low evergreen shrub of high north temperate regions of Europe and Asia and America bearing red edible berries;
coextensive with the genus Clethra;
type and sole genus of the Clethraceae; deciduous shrubs or small trees: white alder, summer-sweet ;
shrub of eastern and southern coastal United States having beautiful racemes of spice-scented white flowers;
