north temperate low evergreen plants; in some classifications placed in its own order Diapensiales;
used in some classifications: coextensive with family Diapensiaceae;
type genus of Diapensiaceae;
any boreal low-growing evergreen plant of the genus Diapensia;
evergreen herbs of southeastern United States;
tufted evergreen perennial herb having spikes of tiny white flowers and glossy green round to heart-shaped leaves that become coppery to maroon or purplish in fall;
one species: pyxie; the eastern United States;
creeping evergreen shrub having narrow overlapping leaves and early white star-shaped flowers; of the pine barrens of New Jersey and the Carolinas;
evergreen perennial herbs of North America and eastern Asia: oconee bells;
any plant of the genus Shortia; evergreen perennial herbs with smooth leathery basal leaves and showy white solitary flowers;
plant of southeastern United States having solitary white funnel-shaped flowers flushed with pink and large glossy green leaves that turn bronze-red in fall;
Australasian shrubs or small trees;
any heathlike plant of the family Epacridaceae; most are of the Australian region;
type genus of the Epacridaceae: Australian heath;
any heathlike evergreen shrub of the genus Epacris grown for their showy and crowded spikes of small bell-shaped or tubular flowers;
spindly upright shrub of southern Australia and Tasmania having white to rose or purple-red flowers;
small erect shrub of Australia and Tasmania with fragrant ivory flowers;
small shrub of southern and western Australia having pinkish to rosy purple tubular flowers;
evergreen shrubs of Australia and Tasmania;
small prostrate or ascending shrub having scarlet flowers and succulent fruit resembling cranberries; sometimes placed in genus Styphelia;
evergreen trees or shrubs of mountains of Australia and Tasmania;
stout Australian shrub with narrow leaves crowded at ends of branches and terminal clusters of white or pink flowers;
gaunt Tasmanian evergreen shrubby tree with slender tapering leaves 3 to 5 feet long;
Australian heathlike shrubs;
heathlike shrub of southwestern Australia grown for its sharply scented foliage and pink flowers followed by pentagonal fruit;
family of fleshy parasitic herbs lacking green foliage and having heads of small flowers; California and Mexico;
evergreen herbs of temperate regions: genera Pyrola, Chimaphila, Moneses, Orthilia;
short-stemmed perennial herbs of cool or temperate regions: wintergreen; shinleaf;
any of several evergreen perennials of the genus Pyrola;
evergreen of eastern North America with leathery leaves and numerous white flowers;
the common wintergreen having many-flowered racemes of pink-tinged white flowers; Europe and North America;
North American evergreen with small pinkish bell-shaped flowers and oblong leaves used formerly for shinplasters;
evergreen with rounded leaves and very fragrant creamy-white flowers; widely distributed in northern parts of Old and New Worlds;
a shrubby perennial rhizomatous evergreen herb; grows in damp coniferous woodlands in northern temperate regions;
small genus of evergreen herbs with long creeping rootstocks and shining leaves; North America; Europe; east Asia;
any of several plants of the genus Chimaphila;
Eurasian herb with white or pinkish flowers in a terminal corymb;
one species: one-flowered wintergreen; sometimes included in genus Pyrola;
delicate evergreen dwarf herb of north temperate regions having a solitary white terminal flower; sometimes placed in genus Pyrola;
used in some classification for saprophytic herbs sometimes included in the family Pyrolaceae: genera Monotropa and Sarcodes;
leafless fleshy saprophytic plants; in some classifications placed in the family Pyrolaceae;
small waxy white or pinkish-white saprophytic woodland plant having scalelike leaves and a nodding flower; turns black with age;
term used in some classifications for the pinesaps, which are usually included in the genus Monotropa;
fleshy tawny or reddish saprophytic herb resembling the Indian pipe and growing in woodland humus of eastern North America; in some classifications placed in a separate genus Hypopitys;
snow plant; in some classifications placed in family Pyrolaceae;
a fleshy bright red saprophytic plant of the mountains of western North America that appears in early spring while snow is on the ground;
an order of dicotyledonous trees of the subclass Hamamelidae;
chiefly monoecious trees and shrubs: beeches; chestnuts; oaks; genera Castanea, Castanopsis, Chrysolepis, Fagus, Lithocarpus, Nothofagus, Quercus;
beeches;
any of several large deciduous trees with rounded spreading crowns and smooth grey bark and small sweet edible triangular nuts enclosed in burs; north temperate regions;
wood of any of various beech trees; used for flooring and containers and plywood and tool handles;
large European beech with minutely-toothed leaves; widely planted as an ornamental in North America;
variety of European beech with shining purple or copper-colored leaves;
North American forest tree with light green leaves and edible nuts;
variety of European beech with pendulous limbs;
a beech native to Japan having soft light yellowish-brown wood;
chestnuts; chinkapins;
any of several attractive deciduous trees yellow-brown in autumn; yield a hard wood and edible nuts in a prickly bur;
wood of any of various chestnut trees of the genus Castanea;
large tree found from Maine to Alabama;
wild or cultivated throughout southern Europe, northwestern Africa and southwestern Asia;
a small tree with small sweet nuts; wild or naturalized in Korea and China;
a spreading tree of Japan that has a short trunk;
shrubby chestnut tree of southeastern United States having small edible nuts;
shrubby tree closely related to the Allegheny chinkapin but with larger leaves; southern midwestern United States;
evergreen trees and shrubs of warm regions valued for their foliage; southeastern United States and eastern Australia and northern New Zealand;
a tree of the genus Castanopsis;
two species: golden chinkapins;
small ornamental evergreen tree of Pacific Coast whose glossy yellow-green leaves are yellow beneath; bears edible nuts;
evergreen shrub similar to golden chinkapin; mountains of California;
tanbark oaks;
evergreen tree of the Pacific coast area having large leathery leaves; yields tanbark;
small evergreen tree of China and Japan;
bark rich in tannin; bruised and cut in pieces to use for tanning; spent tanbark used as a ground covering;
beeches of temperate southern hemisphere except Africa: southern beech;
any of various beeches of the southern hemisphere having small usually evergreen leaves;
large evergreen tree of Tasmania;
Chilean evergreen whose leafy boughs are used for thatching;
any of several tall New Zealand trees of the genus Nothofagus; some yield useful timber;
New Zealand beech with usually pale silvery bark;
tall deciduous South American tree;
large Chilean timber tree yielding coarse lumber;
New Zealand forest tree;
tall New Zealand tree yielding very hard wood;
fruit of the oak tree: a smooth thin-walled nut in a woody cup-shaped base;
cup-shaped plant organ;
cup-shaped structure of hardened bracts at the base of an acorn;
oaks;
a deciduous tree of the genus Quercus; has acorns and lobed leaves; great oaks grow from little acorns;
the hard durable wood of any oak; used especially for furniture and flooring;
oak given a weathered appearance by exposure to fumes of ammonia; used for cabinetwork;
any of several American evergreen oaks;
highly variable often shrubby evergreen oak of coastal zone of western North America having small thick usually spiny-toothed dark-green leaves;
any of numerous Old World and American oaks having 6 to 8 stamens in each floret, acorns that mature in one year and leaf veins that never extend beyond the margin of the leaf;
large slow-growing deciduous tree of the eastern United States having stout spreading branches and leaves with usually 7 rounded lobes; yields strong and durable hard wood;
semi-evergreen shrub or small tree of Arizona and New Mexico having acorns with hemispherical cups;
large deciduous oak of the eastern United States with a flaky bark and leaves that have fewer lobes than other white oaks; yields heavy strong wood used in construction; thrives in wet soil;
large deciduous tree of central and southern Europe and Asia Minor having lanceolate leaves with spiked lobes;
medium-sized evergreen of southwestern United States and northwestern Mexico with oblong leathery often spiny-edged leaves;
medium-large deciduous tree with a thick trunk found in the eastern United States and southern Canada and having close-grained wood and deeply seven-lobed leaves turning scarlet in autumn;
