the sound of a bell rung in Roman Catholic churches to announce the time when the Angelus should be recited;
the sound of someone playing a set of bells;
the occurrence of a change in direction back in the opposite direction;
a rolling or revolving motion;
a vaguely specified social event; the party was quite an affair; an occasion arranged to honor the president; a seemingly endless round of social functions;
an occasion on which people can assemble for social interaction and entertainment; he planned a party to celebrate Bastille Day;
an uproarious party;
a party held on the anniversary of someone's birth;
(Briticism) a grand formal party on an important occasion;
an informal social gathering at which there is Scottish or Irish folk music and singing and folk dancing and story telling;
an afternoon party at which cocktails are served;
a party for social dancing;
a lavish dance requiring formal attire;
a ball at which young ladies are presented to society;
a ball at which guests wear costumes and masks;
a formal ball held for a school class toward the end of the academic year;
a dance party featuring country dancing;
an informal dance where popular music is played;
a dance party that lasts all night and electronically synthesized music is played; raves are very popular in Berlin;
an elaborate party (often outdoors);
an elaborate Hawaiian feast or party (especially one accompanied by traditional foods and entertainment);
a party lasting over one or more nights at a large house;
a happy party;
a party at which tea is served;
a progressive whist party;
a joyful occasion for special festivities to mark some happy event;
a formal event performed on a special occasion; a ceremony commemorating Pearl Harbor;
formal ceremony about important occasions; pomp and circumstance;
a ceremony at which a dead person is buried or cremated; hundreds of people attended his funeral;
the ritual placing of a corpse in a grave;
a traditional Tibetan funeral ritual in which the corpse is exposed to the open air to be eaten by sacred vultures;
the social event at which the ceremony of marriage is performed;
a rich and spectacular ceremony;
a ceremony in which something (as a building) is dedicated to some goal or purpose;
a new dedication; the rededication of the Temple of Jerusalem;
a ceremony accompanying the start of some enterprise;
a ceremony to honor the memory of someone or something;
a formal ceremony performed by military personnel;
a formal entry into an organization or position or office; his initiation into the club; he was ordered to report for induction into the army; he gave a speech as part of his installation into the hall of fame;
the ceremony of installing a new monarch;
(Judaism) an initiation ceremony marking the 13th birthday of a Jewish boy and signifying the beginning of religious responsibility; a bar mitzvah is an important social event;
(Judaism) an initiation ceremony marking the 12th birthday of a Jewish girl and signifying the beginning of religious responsibility;
(usually plural) a ceremony that involves processions and speeches; academic exercises;
the ceremony of walking barefoot over hot stones or a bed of embers;
an academic exercise in which diplomas are conferred;
a requirement of etiquette or custom; a mere formality;
a public ceremony on Maundy Thursday when the monarch distributes Maundy money;
a ceremonial feast held by some Indians of the northwestern coast of North America (as in celebrating a marriage or a new accession) in which the host gives gifts to tribesmen and others to display his superior wealth (sometimes, formerly, to his own impoverishment);
a social function that is held for the purpose of raising money;
an occasion that lends itself to (or is deliberately arranged for) taking photographs that provide favorable publicity for those who are photographed;
an occasion of spending a night away from home or having a guest spend the night in your home (especially as a party for children);
an occasion on which a winner is selected from among two or more contestants;
a contest between athletes;
a contest or fight (especially between boxers or wrestlers);
an athletic contest consisting of ten different events;
the modern revival of the ancient games held once every 4 years in a selected country;
an athletic contest modeled after the Olympic Games but intended for mentally or physically handicapped persons;
an Olympics for winter sports;
a minor match preceding the main event;
an athletic contest consisting of five different events;
a competition at which a champion is chosen;
a foolhardy competition; a dangerous activity that is continued until one competitor becomes afraid and stops;
a contest whose outcome is uncertain up to the very end;
a fiercely disputed contest; their rancor dated from a political dogfight between them; a real dogfight for third place; a prolonged dogfight over their rival bids for the contract;
a contest of speed; the race is to the swift;
a race between (usually high-performance) automobiles;
one of several international races;
an automobile race run over public roads;
a race between people riding bicycles;
a French bicycle race for professional cyclists that lasts three weeks and covers about 3,000 miles;
a race between people rowing or driving boats;
a high-speed motorcycle race on a public road;
a race between ancient chariots;
a race between dogs; usually an occasion for betting on the outcome;
a race between crews of people in yachts;
a race run on foot; she broke the record for the half-mile run;
a footrace run for fun (often including runners who are sponsored for a charity);
a footrace of 26 miles 385 yards;
a race (as in swimming) in which each contestant has a free choice of the style to use;
a long race run over open country;
an important dogsled race run annually on the Iditarod Trail;
an equestrian competition; the first day is dressage; the second is cross-country jumping; the third is stadium jumping;
a preliminary race in which the winner advances to a more important race;
a contest of speed between horses; usually held for the purpose of betting;
a horse race in which each owner declares before the race at what price his horse will be offered for sale after the race;
a horse race in which the winning horse must be put up for auction;
a horse race between people riding in sulkies behind horses that are trotting or pacing;
an annual race for three-year-old horses; held at Churchill Downs in Louisville, Kentucky;
an annual race for three-year-old horses; held at Pimlico in Baltimore, Maryland;
an annual race for three-year-old horses; held on Long Island at Elmont, New York;
a horse race in which part of the prize is put up by the owners of the horses in the race;
a horse race over an obstructed course;
an annual steeplechase run in Liverpool, England;
a race in which competitors must negotiate obstacles;
a footrace of usually 3000 meters over a closed track with hurdles and a water jump;
a race between thoroughbred horses;
a novelty race in which competitors move potatoes from one place to another one at a time;
a novelty race in which competitors jump ahead with their feet confined in a sack;
a race in which all contestants start from scratch (on equal terms);
a race between people wearing skis;
