intense mournfulness;
a feeling of intense unhappiness; she was exhausted by her misery and grief;
sadness resulting from being forsaken or abandoned;
sadness expressed by weeping;
an emotion of great sadness associated with loss or bereavement; he tried to express his sorrow at her loss;
sorrow for sin arising from fear of damnation;
devastating sorrow and despair; he is recovering from a broken heart; a broken heart languishes here;
intense sorrow caused by loss of a loved one (especially by death);
a state of gloomy sorrow;
expressing sorrowfulness;
(poetry) painful grief;
sadness associated with some wrong done or some disappointment; he drank to drown his sorrows; he wrote a note expressing his regret; to his rue, the error cost him the game;
a feeling of deep regret (usually for some misdeed);
remorse caused by feeling responsible for some offense;
a deep feeling of guilt often experienced by those who have survived some catastrophe that took the lives of many others; derives in part from a feeling that they did not do enough to save the others who perished and in part from feelings of being unworthy relative to those who died; survivor guilt was first noted in those who survived the Holocaust;
remorse for your past conduct;
a feeling of dreary or pessimistic sadness;
a sudden numbing dread;
a feeling of dismal cheerlessness;
sad feelings of gloom and inadequacy;
a feeling of low spirits; he felt responsible for her lowness of spirits;
depression resulting from an undermining of your morale;
a feeling of being unable to manage;
a feeling of sorrow (often self-indulgent) over your own sufferings;
feeling downcast and disheartened and hopeless;
a feeling of being oppressed;
an oppressive feeling of heavy force; bowed down by the weight of responsibility;
a longing for something better than the present situation;
a feeling of sulky discontent;
abnormal depression and discontent;
the feeling of being displeased and discontent; he was never slow to express his dissatisfaction with the service he received;
the feeling of being bored by something tedious;
a general feeling of boredom and dissatisfaction;
(always used with a modifier) boredom resulting from overexposure to something; he was suffering from museum fatigue; after watching TV with her husband she had a bad case of football fatigue; the American public is experiencing scandal fatigue; political fatigue;
the feeling of being displeased or annoyed or dissatisfied with someone or something;
a feeling of dissatisfaction that results when your expectations are not realized; his hopes were so high he was doomed to disappointment;
the feeling that accompanies an experience of being thwarted in attaining your goals;
the general feeling that some desire will be fulfilled; in spite of his troubles he never gave up hope;
the feeling you have when you have hope;
the feeling of being encouraged;
the optimistic feeling that all is going to turn out well;
feeling sanguine; optimistically cheerful and confident;
the feeling that everything is wrong and nothing will turn out well; they moaned in despair and dismay; one harsh word would send her into the depths of despair;
the despair you feel when you have abandoned hope of comfort or success;
acceptance of despair;
acceptance of the inevitability of defeat;
the feeling of despair in the face of obstacles;
the feeling of discouragement in the face of someone's superior fame or wealth or status etc.;
the feeling that things will turn out badly;
a cynical feeling of distrust;
a strong positive emotion of regard and affection; his love for his work; children need a lot of love;
selfless love of one person for another without sexual implications (especially love that is spiritual in nature);
(Christian theology) the love of God or Christ for mankind;
the love of a child for a parent;
intense feeling of love;
a feeling of love or fondness;
temporary love of an adolescent;
feelings of ardent love; their devotion to each other was beautiful;
a positive feeling of liking; he had trouble expressing the affection he felt; the child won everyone's heart; the warmness of his welcome made us feel right at home;
a feeling of affection for a person or an institution;
a feeling of protective affection;
a feeling of friendship and esteem; she mistook his manly regard for love; he inspires respect;
a sentimental affection; she had a soft spot for her youngest son;
disposition to do good;
doing good; feeling beneficent;
your deepest feelings of love and compassion; many adoption cases tug at the heartstrings;
a loving feeling;
a warmhearted feeling;
feelings of allegiance;
the emotion of intense dislike; a feeling of dislike so strong that it demands action;
hatred of mankind;
hatred of marriage;
hatred of women;
hatred of reasoning;
hatred of change or innovation;
hatred of new ideas;
hatred of children;
a bloodthirsty hatred arousing murderous impulses;
a feeling of scornful hatred;
the feeling of a hostile person; he could no longer contain his hostility;
a feeling of ill will arousing active hostility;
feelings of envy and resentment of one social or economic class for toward another;
an actively expressed feeling of dislike and hostility;
a feeling of hostility that arouses thoughts of attack;
hostile or warlike attitude or nature;
hostile or belligerent mood; the chief is on the warpath today;
a feeling of deep and bitter anger and ill-will ;
intense resentment; his promotion caused much heartburning among his rivals;
a feeling of sulky resentment;
a resentment strong enough to justify retaliation; holding a grudge; settling a score;
a feeling of grudging admiration and desire to have something that is possessed by another;
an envious eagerness to possess something;
a feeling of jealous envy (especially of a rival);
(psychoanalysis) a female's presumed envy of the male's penis; said to explain femininity;
wishing evil to others;
doing or causing evil;
feeling a need to see others suffer;
a malevolent desire for revenge;
a characteristic (habitual or relatively temporary) state of feeling; whether he praised or cursed me depended on his temper at the time; he was in a bad humor;
an annoyed or irritated mood;
