a statement (either spoken or written) that is made to reply to a question or request or criticism or accusation; I waited several days for his answer; he wrote replies to several of his critics;
a reply by a Pope to an inquiry concerning a point of law or morality;
response to an inquiry or experiment;
a public statement containing information about an event that has happened or is going to happen; the announcement appeared in the local newspaper; the promulgation was written in English;
an announcement that usually advises or warns the public of some threat; a frost advisory;
(Christianity) the announcement to the Virgin Mary by the angel Gabriel of the incarnation of Christ;
a public announcement of a proposed marriage;
an announcement distributed to members of the press in order to supplement or replace an oral presentation;
an announcement containing information about an event; you didn't give me enough notice; an obituary notice; "a notice of sale;
(law) a formal notice filed with a court or officer to suspend a proceeding until filer is given a hearing; a caveat filed against the probate of a will;
a notice of someone's death; usually includes a short biography;
a collection of biographies of famous pairs of Greeks and Romans written by Plutarch; used by Shakespeare in writing some of his plays;
an announcement of the events that will occur as part of a theatrical or sporting event; you can't tell the players without a program;
a theatrical program; he couldn't find her name on the playbill;
a program for a race meeting; lists the races and the names of the horses;
a statement made about the future;
the prediction that human intelligence and technology will enable life to expand in an orderly way throughout the entire universe;
the practice of predicting people's futures (usually for payment);
a prediction of someone's future based on the relative positions of the planets;
predicting what the weather will be;
a prediction about how something (as the weather) will develop;
a prediction uttered under divine inspiration;
a prophecy (usually obscure or allegorical) revealed by a priest or priestess; believed to be infallible;
a forecast of the expected financial position and the results of operations and cash flows based on expected conditions;
a forecast of the weather;
(logic) a statement that affirms or denies something and is either true or false;
(logic) a proposition that asserts something about some (but not all) members of a class;
(logic) a proposition that asserts something of all members of a class;
(logic) a proposition that is true if and only if another proposition is false;
a proposition obtained by conversion;
a subsidiary proposition that is assumed to be true in order to prove another proposition;
one of the substantive phrases in a logical proposition; the major term of a syllogism must occur twice;
a proposition deducible from basic postulates;
a categorematic expression; a term capable of standing alone as the subject or predicate of a logical proposition; names are called categorems;
a syncategorematic expression; a word that cannot be used alone as a term in a logical proposition; logical quantifiers, adverbs, prepositions, and conjunctions are called syncategoremes;
the proposition arrived at by logical reasoning (such as the proposition that must follow from the major and minor premises of a syllogism);
(logic) a proposition that is accepted as true in order to provide a basis for logical reasoning;
(logic) a proposition that is not susceptible of proof or disproof; its truth is assumed to be self-evident;
a statement that is assumed to be true and from which a conclusion can be drawn; on the assumption that he has been injured we can infer that he will not to play;
the premise of a syllogism that contains the major term (which is the predicate of the conclusion);
the premise of a syllogism that contains the minor term (which is the subject of the conclusion);
the term in a syllogism that is the predicate of the conclusion;
the term in a syllogism that is the subject of the conclusion;
the term in a syllogism that is common to both premises and excluded from the conclusion;
an argument that appears good at first view but is really fallacious;
an argument that assumes that which is to be proved;
an unproved statement put forward as a premise in an argument;
an assumption on which rests the validity or effect of something else;
(mathematics) a condition specified for the solution to a set of differential equations;
a stipulated condition; he accepted subject to one provision;
a postulated sequence of possible events; planners developed several scenarios in case of an attack;
a statement of the current market price of a security or commodity;
a false statement;
a statement that evades the question by cleverness or trickery;
a statement that deviates from or perverts the truth;
a trivial lie; he told a fib about eating his spinach; how can I stop my child from telling stories?;
an interesting but highly implausible story; often told as an excuse;
(law) a false boast that can harm others; especially a false claim to be married to someone (formerly actionable at law);
a gross untruth; a blatant lie;
an unimportant lie (especially one told to be tactful or polite);
a deliberately false or improbable account;
a deliberately misleading fabrication;
a misleading falsehood;
a partially true statement intended to deceive or mislead;
a showy misrepresentation intended to conceal something unpleasant;
making to seem more important than it really is;
a statement that is restrained in ironic contrast to what might have been said;
a long and elaborate misrepresentation;
pretending with intention to deceive;
pretense that your position is stronger than it really is; his bluff succeeded in getting him accepted;
something serving to conceal plans; a fictitious reason that is concocted in order to conceal the real reason;
a pretext for delay or inaction;
an expression of agreement that is not supported by real conviction;
a hypocritical display of sorrow; false or insincere weeping; the secretaries wept crocodile tears over the manager's dilemma; politicians shed crocodile tears over the plight of the unemployed;
something intended to misrepresent the true nature of an activity; he wasn't sick--it was just a subterfuge; the holding company was just a blind;
verbal misrepresentation intended to take advantage of you in some way;
a fraudulent or duplicitous representation;
a statement that is not literally false but that cleverly avoids an unpleasant truth;
an indirect way of expressing something;
any language that pretends to communicate but actually does not;
an intentionally noncommittal or ambiguous statement; when you say maybeyou are just hedging;
an evasion of the point of an argument by raising irrelevant distinctions or objections;
the part of a contract that contains reservations and qualifications that are often printed in small type; don't sign a contract without reading the fine print;
an equivocal qualification; a word used to avoid making an outright assertion;
a statement that limits or restricts some claim; he recommended her without any reservations;
a statement made with careful qualifications;
a written explanation or criticism or illustration that is added to a book or other textual material; he wrote an extended comment on the proposal;
(Judaism) an ancient commentary on part of the Hebrew scriptures that is based on Jewish methods of interpretation and attached to the biblical text;
a comment or instruction (usually added); his notes were appended at the end of the article; he added a short notation to the address on the envelope;
a short note recognizing a source of information or of a quoted passage; the student's essay failed to list several important citations; the acknowledgments are usually printed at the front of a book; the article includes mention of similar clinical cases;
a printed note placed below the text on a printed page;
a Latin phrase (or its abbreviation) used to indicate that special attention should be paid to something; the margins of his book were generously supplied with pencilled NBs;
a note appended to a letter after the signature;
a note acknowledging the source of a published photograph;
a reference at one place in a work to information at another place in the same work;
a statement that expresses a personal opinion or belief or adds information; from time to time she contributed a personal comment on his account;
an opening remark intended to secure an advantage for the speaker;
(Islam) a legal opinion or ruling issued by an Islamic scholar; bin Laden issued three fatwahs calling upon Muslims to take up arms against the United States;
an opinion voiced by a judge on a point of law not directly bearing on the case in question and therefore not binding;
an incidental remark;
